<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="78" moduleid="104" modulename="lesson" contextid="115">
  <lesson id="78">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Project 3 Teacher Guide: Two-Variable Statistics</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>0</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password/>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>100</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>1</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>0</retake>
    <activitylink>0</activitylink>
    <mediafile/>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>0</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>0</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1658545907</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="702">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>703</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1658545076</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1659054784</timemodified>
        <title>Project 3 Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3 dir="ltr"&gt;Lesson Narrative&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" id="docs-internal-guid-b9a6f5ee-7fff-2605-96c3-c4afc1b03535"&gt;In this culminating project, students integrate ideas from the unit. Students collect, summarize, interpret, and draw conclusions from bivariate data using scatter plots, best fit lines, residuals, and correlation coefficients. This connects to previous work because students summarized, represented, interpreted, and drew conclusions from bivariate data using scatter plots, best fit lines, residuals, and correlation coefficients. This connects to upcoming work because students will continue to investigate data using conditional probability and statistical experiments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Technology isn&amp;rsquo;t required for this lesson, but there are opportunities for students to choose to use appropriate technology to solve problems. We recommend making technology available. When students collect and analyze data to answer a question, they are making sense of problems and persevering in solving them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Goals (Teacher Facing)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" id="docs-internal-guid-c53cf289-7fff-5142-0dbe-7fb4a40c7100"&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Collect data to create a linear model to predict information, answer questions, and draw conclusions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Interpret bivariate data using scatter plots, lines of best fit, residuals, and correlation coefficients.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Targets (Student Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-650ac98a-7fff-7be8-d01d-297b0d5e3da8"&gt;I can collect data, create a linear model to fit the data, determine if the linear model is a good fit, and use the information from my linear model to answer questions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h4 dir="ltr" id="docs-internal-guid-9c61a2cb-7fff-c1a6-6ed2-2ffc0090a01d"&gt;Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;4(A) calculate, using technology, the correlation coefficient between two quantitative variables and interpret this quantity as a measure of the strength of the linear association.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;4(B) compare and contrast association and causation in real-world problems.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;4(C) write, with and without technology, linear functions that provide a reasonable fit to data to estimate solutions and make predictions for real-world problems.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4 dir="ltr"&gt;Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rulers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tools for creating a visual display&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4 dir="ltr"&gt;Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Technology is not required for this lesson, but there are opportunities for students to research their own data about sports teams and penalties if they have access to devices that can access the internet. &lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-efd47359-7fff-99e6-c37b-a3a0cc752089"&gt;If students do not have access to technology, copies of a lesson guide from Illustrative Mathematics includes data that can be used.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;When students can research their own data, provide materials for them to create a visual display containing their information and any conclusions they make to share with the class.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 dir="ltr"&gt;Project Activities&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Activity P1: Estimating Lengths&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Activity P2: Analyze Data &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1566">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1658545076</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="703">
        <prevpageid>702</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>704</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1658545483</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1658545640</timemodified>
        <title>Activity P3.1: Estimating Lengths</title>
        <contents>&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Activity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;40 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mathematical purpose of this
 activity is for students to collect, summarize, interpret, and draw 
conclusions from bivariate data using scatter plots, best fit lines, 
residuals and correlation coefficients. Students measure the approximate
 lengths of the humerus bone and height of their classmates to collect 
data and create a linear model. The model is then used to approximate 
the height of an ancient human based on the length of a found humerus 
bone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making graphing technology 
available gives students an opportunity to choose appropriate tools 
strategically (MP5). By collecting their own data and using a best fit 
line to find additional information, students are modeling with 
mathematics (MP4).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Launch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2 
to 4. Present the task to students and ask students to brainstorm 
different ways that they could answer the question. After 2 minutes of 
quiet think time, ask students to share their ideas with the class. The 
remaining time should be used by students to collect, analyze, 
summarize, and interpret the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Speaking, Reading: MLR5 Co-Craft Questions.&lt;/em&gt;
 Use this routine to help students further interpret and increase 
awareness of the language used to talk about scatter plots, best fit 
lines, residuals and correlation coefficients. Display the first 
sentence of this problem ("An anthropologist finds a fossilized humerus 
bone of an ancient human ancestor."), and ask students to write down 
possible mathematical questions that could be asked about the situation.
 Invite students to compare their questions before revealing the 
remainder of the question. Listen for and amplify any questions 
involving comparing bivariate data.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Student Facing Statement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="Arm skeletal system" height="432" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/o4Yb8HMYDmxo4DHGad6wXjXa" width="276"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An anthropologist finds a fossilized humerus bone of an ancient human
 ancestor. The humerus is an arm bone running from the shoulder to the 
elbow. It is 24 centimeters in length. Use data from your classmates to 
estimate the height of this ancient human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Student Response&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample response: About 123 centimeters (around 4 feet). I measured 
the humerus and height of several classmates and created a scatter plot.
 I used a plot of the residuals and found that a linear model seemed to 
be appropriate. I then found the line of best fit to be about \( y = 5.1 x + 0.2 \), where \( y \) is the height in centimeters and \( x \) is the length of the humerus in centimeters. Using 24 centimeters for \( x \), I found that \( 5.1 \cdot 24 + 0.2 = 122.6 \), which I rounded since this is a rough estimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students may find it difficult to start to answer the question. Ask 
students what are the variables given in the situation. Ask students if 
there is a way we could collect information from people in the classroom
 to help answer the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this discussion is for students to communicate how they used mathematics to justify their findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;"How confident are you in your answer? What information helped 
you determine your confidence?" (Not very confident. Since the 
correlation coefficient is near 0.6, there is only a moderate 
relationship between height and humerus length. Additionally, this 
ancient human ancestor may have a different anatomy-for example, apes 
tend to have proportionally longer arms than humans do.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"How did you use mathematics to estimate the height of the ancient 
human?" (First, I collected data on the height and the approximate 
length of the humerus of my classmates. I then made a scatter plot to 
determine whether or not a linear model was appropriate, and then 
computed a line of best fit. I substituted 24 centimeters into my line 
of best fit and obtained my answer.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Do you think that the way you measured the humerus of your 
classmates impacted your choice of linear model? Explain your 
reasoning." (Yes, I think that I probably overestimated the bone length,
 because I was measuring from the outside and not the inside. I think 
that my model likely overestimates height.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1567">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1658545483</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1568">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1658545483</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="704">
        <prevpageid>703</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1658545604</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1658545650</timemodified>
        <title>Activity P3.2: Analyze Data </title>
        <contents>&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Activity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;40 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mathematical purpose of this
 activity is for students to collect, summarize, interpret, and draw 
conclusions from bivariate data using scatter plots, best fit lines, 
residuals and correlation coefficients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students could examine number of
 penalties (like number of flags thrown against a football team) or 
severity of penalties (like penalty yards assessed against a football 
team).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making graphing technology 
available gives students an opportunity to choose appropriate tools 
strategically (MP5). By selecting which variables to use for their model
 and finding additional data to support a claim, students are modeling 
with mathematics (MP4).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Launch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2 
to 4. Give students 2 minutes to work through the first question, then 
pause for a whole-group discussion. Tell students, "Data is often kept 
about fouls in basketball, flags in football, or penalty box minutes in 
hockey." If using the blackline master, then distribute it to students 
and tell them to begin questions 2 and 3. If you are not using the 
blackline master, then tell students to use the internet to find data 
about fouls, flags, penalties, or other similar data about rules 
violations and sports results. Ask them to record two questions for the 
data that they research that are similar to questions 2 and 3. Then ask 
them to answer their questions using mathematical work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A blackline master is included 
with data for hockey and football if students do not have access to 
technology to find their own data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Support for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Engagement: Develop Effort and Persistence.&lt;/em&gt;
 Encourage and support opportunities for peer interactions. Display 
sentence frames to support student conversation such as: "I predict 
_____ because . . .", "We will need to know . . .", "Why did you . . 
.?", "I agree/disagree because . . ."&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Supports accessibility for: Language; Social-emotional skills&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Student Facing Statement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Before
 researching data, do you think the number of penalties a team gets in a
 season is correlated to the number of wins the team gets in that 
season? Do you think it is a positive or negative relationship? Do you 
think the relationship is weak or strong? Explain your reasoning.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there a relationship 
between the number of penalties a team gets in a season and the number 
of wins in that season? Show any mathematical work that leads to your 
answer.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do penalties cause a change in wins or wins cause a change in penalties or neither? Explain your reasoning.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Student Response&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I
 think there will be a weak, negative relationship. Penalties usually 
come with ways that put the team at a disadvantage, but not a very 
severe one, so I think that more penalties will lead to fewer wins, but 
not a strong relationship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="Scatter plot, number of wins, penalty minutes per game. &amp;nbsp;" height="244" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/SkniynJNDJVmRvJomC8kFczD" width="227"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	Based on the scatter plot and correlation coefficient, there is a very weak (\( r = 0.19 \)), positive relationship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think neither of these variables causes the other to change. Most
 likely, a very good team may feel they have the ability to give up a 
few penalties and still win, so they don't worry as much about getting 
penalized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students may struggle with finding a method to determine the presence
 of a relationship. Ask students, "What data could you collect to begin 
answering the question? What representations could you create with that 
data to help illustrate a relationship?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this discussion is for students to communicate how they used mathematics to justify their findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If students are able to research their own data, tell the groups to 
create a visual display to present their findings. Some questions for 
discussion are listed here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;"If there is a negative correlation, do you think the penalties 
would cause fewer wins?" (Although it may be part of the cause, it is 
generally not the main reason a team loses several games.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Were there any interesting data points you would like to research 
more about?" (Some points were very far away from the rest of the data 
and might be interesting to look at more closely.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"How did you reach a conclusion? Explain your reasoning." (I 
created a scatter plot from data that I collected. I then plotted the 
residuals to verify that a linear model would be appropriate. I computed
 a line of best fit and a correlation coefficient and found that there 
was a weak relationship between penalties and wins because the 
correlation coefficient was between 0 and 0.5.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lesson Synthesis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some questions for discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;"What did you find important, challenging, or otherwise notable 
about today's lesson?" (It was really interesting to collect data to 
answer a question. I really felt like I was figuring something out.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"What mathematical work from this unit did you use in today's 
activity?" (I used scatter plots, lines of best fit, and the correlation
 coefficient. I also had to determine whether or not the two variables 
showed a causal relationship.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"How might the mathematical tools that you have learned in this 
unit help you outside of mathematics class?" (I could use these tools to
 think about graphs or claims that I see being made in the media. It 
would help me to determine what to believe and what not to believe.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1569">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1658545604</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1570">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1658545604</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>
