<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="1" moduleid="1" modulename="page" contextid="12">
  <page id="1">
    <name>RAISE Algebra 1</name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;RAISE (Rice Algebra Initiative for Success and Equity)&lt;/strong&gt; is an innovative project designed to improve Algebra I teaching and student learning for underserved students in Texas, specifically Black, Hispanic/Latinx, and students experiencing poverty (priority students). Our goal is to increase student learning and achievement in Algebra with an open education resource (OER) that is TEKS-aligned, easy to implement, culturally responsive, and supports the persistence and motivation of students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RAISE course covers all skills and content needed for students to be successful on the Texas STAAR end of course exam. This course is based on materials created by &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://illustrativemathematics.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Illustrative Mathematics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (IM) and &lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://openstax.org/" target="_blank"&gt;OpenStax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, as well as structure and elements created by our curriculum partner, &lt;a href="https://www.wisewire.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Wisewire&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What makes the RAISE project unique&lt;/strong&gt; is our approach to creating Algebra I content. Our continuous improvement model is focused on a user-centered approach that strives for student interactivity. We are designing and testing content directly with Algebra 1 teachers to ensure it works in real classrooms. Participating teachers drive our continuous improvement model and support the co-development of our curriculum. This model ensures that teacher and student feedback is at the heart of our work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The curriculum includes an instructional guide, prerequisite content to assess readiness skills for each unit, practice lessons and assessments, and promotes student engagement by incorporating interactive tools and videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our team&lt;/strong&gt; includes educators, learning science researchers, content developers, and software developers who are all focused on developing a curriculum that is interactive and easy to implement. We seek to identify and improve learning interventions that best support underrepresented students, ultimately leading to improved academic outcomes and the closing of achievement gaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About OpenStax&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Since 2012, OpenStax has been dedicated to the goal of equitable student success by providing students universal access to knowledge, support for teaching and learning, and learning science research to advance our understanding of effective digital learning.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>2</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:2:{s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";s:17:"printlastmodified";s:1:"1";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>17</revision>
    <timemodified>1658268628</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>