<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="95" moduleid="127" modulename="lesson" contextid="138">
  <lesson id="95">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Lesson 4.8 Teacher Guide: Interpreting and Creating Graphs</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>0</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password/>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>0</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>128</activitylink>
    <mediafile/>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>1</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1660608490</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="857">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>858</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659318071</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662657902</timemodified>
        <title>4.8.0: Lesson Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Narrative&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now, students have had multiple opportunities to interpret graphs of functions and to create them (primarily by plotting known input-output pairs of a function or by using descriptions of the situation). Students have also acquired essential vocabulary to communicate about graphs of functions and have used average rate of change as a way to measure how a function changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this lesson, students apply these insights and skills to interpret or create graphs of functions that are less well defined and that model real-life situations that are more complex. The lesson includes two main activities about flag-raising and two optional activities that use other contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information about the functions is presented in the form of verbal descriptions, video clips, and images. More ambiguity is involved here than in cases students have previously encountered, so they will need to persevere in sense making and problem solving. At times, the information given may be inadequate, so students will need to make assumptions and decisions to produce graphs that show the desired behaviors or meet certain requirements. Along the way, students engage in important aspects of mathematical modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Goals (Teacher Facing)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given a verbal or visual representation of a situation, sketch a graph and show key features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interpret the average rate of change in a situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice interpreting key features of graphs and explaining (orally and in writing) their meaning in terms of a situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Targets (Student Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain the average rate of change of a function in terms of a situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe important features of a graph and explain what they mean in a situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sketch a graph that shows important features of the situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TEKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation of Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A3(C) graph linear functions on the coordinate plane and identify key features, including \(x\)-intercept, \(y\)-intercept, zeros, and slope, in mathematical and real-world problems;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foundational: Lesson provides foundational content necessary for students to be able to perform this TEKS in later lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the instructional activities for the lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.8.1: Analyzing and Comparing the Properties of Graphs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.8.2: Interpreting Graphs Without Units&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.8.2: Self Check&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.8.2: Additional Resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.8.3: Sketching Graphs of Functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.8.3: Self Check&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.8.3: Additional Resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.8.4: Using Verbal Descriptions to Create Graphs of Functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.8.5: Representing Quantities in a Situation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will also complete a series of problems in the 4.8.6: Practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coordinate Grids or Graphing Technology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For activity 4.8.2, have a coordinate grid or graphing technology ready for students to complete the &amp;ldquo;Are You Ready for More?&amp;rdquo; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Vocabulary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this lesson, it is important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarize students with the vocabulary words they will see throughout the lesson. Encourage students to look for these words and notice their use and meanings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage students to use key vocabulary words in &amp;ldquo;math talk&amp;rdquo; and their written and oral explanations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilize a word wall. Sample cards are located here: &lt;a href="https://www.doe.virginia.gov/instruction/mathematics/resources/vocab_cards/" target="new"&gt;Mathematics Vocabulary Word Wall Cards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary words that are emphasized in this lesson include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maximum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minimum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;horizontal intercept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vertical intercept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;function&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;constant &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;N/A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Social Emotional Learning (SEL) Support&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, find ways to encourage and support students to work on cultivating their &lt;strong&gt;creativity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to try during this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/oh-the-places-youll-go/" target="new"&gt;Oh, The Places You&amp;rsquo;ll Go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/creative-spirit/" target="new"&gt;The Creative Spirit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other tips located here in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/playbooks/creativity" target="_blank"&gt;Playbook on Creativity&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;from Character Lab.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1920">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659318071</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="858">
        <prevpageid>857</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>859</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659318647</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662657949</timemodified>
        <title>4.8.1: Analyzing and Comparing the Properties of Graphs</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Warm Up (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This warm-up prompts students to carefully analyze and compare the properties of four graphs. Each graph represents a function relating time and temperature. No scales are shown on the coordinate axes, so students need to look for and make use of the structure of the graphs in determining how each one is like or unlike the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In making comparisons, students have a reason to use language precisely, especially recently learned terms that describe features of graphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2&amp;ndash;4. Display the graphs for all to see. Give students 1 minute of quiet think time and then time to share their thinking with their small group. In their small groups, ask each student to share their reasoning as to why a particular item does not belong, and together, find at least one reason each item doesn&amp;rsquo;t belong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which graph doesn&amp;rsquo;t belong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type="A"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="A graph, origin O. Horizontal axis is labeled time. Vertical axis is labeled temperature. A horizontal line is drawn on the graph." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/6FLYcnZUxvqhtTKFmXffTGZZ"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="A graph, origin O. Horizontal axis is labeled time. Vertical axis is labeled temperature. The curve is shaped like a U and opens downward." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/GR5pi8wLBK4Zu9SoPcyDASzc"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/zwXZsicodUZvc1ekFcohvLfM"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/f6ASxaz392WweQ56AYhhQGkq"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample responses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type="A"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t belong because:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the only graph that has no maximum or minimum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the only situation in which the temperature does not change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t belong because:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the only graph that has one maximum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the only graph that shows the temperature rising and then falling (but not rising again).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t belong because:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the only graph that has horizontal intercepts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the only graph that has one minimum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the only graph that shows negative output values or negative temperatures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the only graph that shows temperature falling and then rising (but not falling again).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t belong because:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the only graph that has several maxima and minima.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the only graph where the temperature rises and falls several times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This graph shows a repeating pattern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask each group to share one reason why a particular item does not belong. Record and display the responses for all to see. Encourage students to use relevant mathematical vocabulary in their explanations, and ask students to explain the meaning of any terminology that they do use, such as &amp;ldquo;intercepts,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;minimum,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;linear functions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After each response, ask the class if they agree or disagree. Since there is no single correct answer to the question asking which one does not belong, attend to students&amp;rsquo; explanations and ensure the reasons given are correct. Also, press students on unsubstantiated claims. For example, if they claim that the vertical intercept of graph C is different from all the others, ask them how they know (as none of the vertical axes have a scale).&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1921">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659318647</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1922">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659318647</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="859">
        <prevpageid>858</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>860</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659319951</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662658048</timemodified>
        <title>4.8.2: Interpreting Graphs Without Units</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (20 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to this point, students have had multiple opportunities to interpret graphs of functions in terms of a situation. In most cases, students were given some information about the units of measurement of at least one quantity, which helped them reason about the functions being represented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this activity, students encounter graphs without units on either of the axes. They interpret the graphs in the context of raising a flag and make a case for whether the graphs are realistic (which may depend on the units chosen for the axes). Students also see for the first time a graph that is a vertical line and think about why this graph does not represent a function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As students relate features of graphs to behaviors of quantities in a situation, they reason quantitatively and abstractly. In explaining and discussing why a graph is or is not realistic, students practice constructing logical arguments and critiquing the reasoning of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Show pictures of a flag ceremony and describe flag raising to students who might be unfamiliar with it. Consider sharing that, in some countries, students hold a flag-raising ceremony on a daily or weekly basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2. Ask students to read the task statement and look at the graphs. Then, give students a moment of quiet time to think about the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What might be reasonable units to use for the axes of the graphs?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How do we know that each graph represents a function?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give students a moment to share their thinking with their partner. Follow with a brief whole-class discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students are likely to suggest seconds as a reasonable unit to use for time and meters or yards as a reasonable unit for height. If these units are not mentioned, ask students about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, tell partners to take turns interpreting the graphs in the first question. Ask students to pause for a discussion before moving to the second question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If utilizing the extension, make sure students are given instructions on how to use graphing technology appropriately, even if it is a review. If students have not used this technology before, the teacher can still utilize the technology and show students the graphs to facilitate answering questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encourage and support opportunities for peer interactions. Invite students to talk about their ideas with a partner before writing them down. Display sentence frames to support students when they explain their strategy. For example, &amp;ldquo;I notice that . . .,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I wonder . . .,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;That could/couldn&amp;rsquo;t be true because . . . .&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A flag ceremony is held at a Fourth of July event. The height of the flag is a function of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some graphs that could each be a possible representation of the function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="a US flag being raised" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/kVjm62XgFPdRsMMPPg1hUwzt" width="350"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/DY41ib8vRKk34U2Y5r7yv6ek"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/asNGtKVkQDQCj7aJJnxkwPG4"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/kFM7ENoMUXRjD48qzbMHipnd"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/5XRH9UyTXhJkwZn83AfBTfhH"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/SznPGdZfnfk19Xzyhah3G2xL"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/R4BHFjd4nb4EFwCuWQvBPU88"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; For each graph assigned to you, explain what it tells us about the flag.
                Graph: _____
            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide as a group which graph(s) appear to be most realistic and which ones least realistic.
            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Video: Interpreting Graphs Without Units&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the following video to learn more about how to determine if a graph is realistic when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls="true" crossorigin="anonymous" width="550"&gt;
&lt;source src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/87ae00400d6a712d7c1fd3467031b8618a04c24d"&gt;
&lt;track default="true" kind="captions" label="On" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/c39fc8c6e2c159af119eeede1746eb8f643bd453" srclang="en_us"&gt;https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/87ae00400d6a712d7c1fd3467031b8618a04c24d
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here is another graph that relates time and height.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/eiwne8Mjv2j5YiZXmwuGWLCW"&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can this graph represent the time and height of the flag? Explain your reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this a graph of a function? Explain your reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sample response (assuming that time is measured in seconds and height in meters):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph A: The flag starts out on the ground but is immediately raised at a constant rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph B: The flag starts out at 3 meters above ground and then stays at that height the entire time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph C: The flag starts out on the ground but gets pulled up quickly. The movement slows down and there is a brief pause, and then it is raised up again at a quicker and quicker rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph D: The flag starts out on the ground, is raised up a couple of meters, and then is lowered back to the ground. This happens repeatedly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph E: The flag starts out at 0.5 meter above the ground and is raised up bit by bit, with a brief pause before it is raised farther.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph F: The flag starts out on the ground and is raised up at a constant speed for 3 seconds. It stops abruptly and comes back down at a constant speed. Then, 2 seconds later, it stops at 3 meters above the ground.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph E seems the most realistic. Graphs B and D are the least realistic. Graphs A, C, and F are possible, but it is unlikely that the flag starts out being on the ground.
            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sample response (assuming that time is measured in seconds and height in meters):
        &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; No. This graph shows the flag being at all heights between 0 and 6 meters at 3 seconds of time, which is impossible.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sample response (assuming that time is measured in seconds and height in meters):
                &lt;br&gt;
                No, it is not a graph of a function. A function has only one output for every input. This graph shows many possible outputs when the input is 3.
            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Extension&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Are you ready for more?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose an ant is moving at a rate of 1 millimeter per second and keeps going at that rate for a long time.
    If time, \(x\), is measured in seconds, then the distance the ant has traveled in millimeters, \(y\), is \(y=1x\). If time, \(x\), is measured in minutes, the distance in millimeters is \(y=60x\). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain why the equation \(y=(365\cdot24\cdot3600)x\) gives the distance the ant has traveled, in millimeters, as a function of time, \(x\), in years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use graphing technology to graph the equation.
        &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(x\)-axis: time (years), \(y\)-axis: distance traveled (millimeters)
            &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph the equation on a coordinate grid or using graphing technology.
            &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the graph look like that of a function? Why do you think it looks this way?
            &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjust the graphing window until the graph no longer looks this way. If you manage to do so, describe the graphing window that you use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you think the last graph in the flag activity could represent a function relating time and height of the flag? Explain your reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Extension Student Response &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sample response: The number of seconds in a year is \(365\cdot24\cdot60\cdot60\). If the ant travels 1 millimeter a second, in one year, it would travel \(365\cdot24\cdot3600\) millimeters. In \(x\) years, it would travel \((365\cdot24\cdot3600)x\) millimeters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(x\)-axis: time (years), \(y\)-axis: distance traveled (millimeters)
            &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="297" role="presentation" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/fad65d44987e892d7894738fcc7575e5d1c679db" width="300"&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sample response: The graph is a vertical line and doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like a graph of a function. The slope is really large, so the line is so steep that it looks vertical. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sample response: The graph is a slanted line when the \(x\)-axis is scaled from &amp;ndash;0.0001 to 0.0001 years and the \(y\)-axis is scaled to ten thousands in both directions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sample response: Flag F can represent a function because every input goes to exactly one output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select students to explain what each graph means in the context of flag raising and give an argument as to why it is or is not realistic. Consider asking partners to illustrate their response together&amp;mdash;one partner explaining what is happening with the flag and the other acting out the action of the flag raiser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss with students which graph is the most realistic and why. Also discuss whether using certain units of measurements would make an unrealistic graph more realistic, or vice versa. (For example, none of the graphs would be realistic if the time is measured in days or months and the height in kilometers or centimeters.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, solicit some explanations as to why the vertical line does not represent a function. If not mentioned in students&amp;rsquo; explanations, bring up a key point: A vertical line can be interpreted to mean that for one particular input (3 units of time, in this case), there is an infinite number of possible outputs. Therefore, it cannot represent a function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.8.2: Self Check&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="left"&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="302"&gt;
&lt;col width="322"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shannon is running on a flat, rocky trail that eventually rises up a steep mountain. Which graph below represents the total distance she covers with respect to time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engageny.org/resource/grade-8-mathematics-module-6"&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS TOTAL DISTANCE IN MILES AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN MINUTES. THE GRAPH IS A CURVE THAT INCREASES FROM LEFT TO RIGHT.
" class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="186" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/928c01ed1a362c3c485f7b739a70e3166eb183c1" width="200"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: She is able to start out faster since the trail is flat, but as the trail rises up the steep mountain, her rate tapers off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS TOTAL DISTANCE IN MILES AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN MINUTES. THE GRAPH IS A STRAIGHT LINE WITH A POSITIVE SLOPE." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="186" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/a31c21abe94d3ab1d919f49bb7e165179e9e8bbb" width="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This graph reflects a constant rate. The trail Shannon is running becomes steeper, which will slow down her pace. The answer is:&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.engageny.org/resource/grade-8-mathematics-module-6"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engageny.org/resource/grade-8-mathematics-module-6"&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS TOTAL DISTANCE IN MILES AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN MINUTES. THE GRAPH IS A CURVE THAT INCREASES FROM LEFT TO RIGHT.
" height="186" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/928c01ed1a362c3c485f7b739a70e3166eb183c1" width="200"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS TOTAL DISTANCE IN MILES AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN MINUTES. THE GRAPH IS A STRAIGHT LINE WITH A NEGATIVE SLOPE" class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="186" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/8ab9f74effb52c77c5c88a293465f72f64c2b3a8" width="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: You are looking for the graph of her distance traveled, so it should start at \((0,0)\). The answer is:&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.engageny.org/resource/grade-8-mathematics-module-6"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engageny.org/resource/grade-8-mathematics-module-6"&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS TOTAL DISTANCE IN MILES AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN MINUTES. THE GRAPH IS A CURVE THAT INCREASES FROM LEFT TO RIGHT.
" height="186" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/928c01ed1a362c3c485f7b739a70e3166eb183c1" width="200"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS TOTAL DISTANCE IN MILES AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN MINUTES. THE GRAPH IS A CURVE THAT DECREASES FROM LEFT TO RIGHT." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="186" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/564634d048608e6c3801e831b893ed4ac7ad9ef2" width="200"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: You are looking for the graph of her distance traveled, so it should start at \((0,0)\). The answer is:&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.engageny.org/resource/grade-8-mathematics-module-6"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.engageny.org/resource/grade-8-mathematics-module-6"&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS TOTAL DISTANCE IN MILES AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN MINUTES. THE GRAPH IS A CURVE THAT INCREASES FROM LEFT TO RIGHT.
" height="186" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/928c01ed1a362c3c485f7b739a70e3166eb183c1" width="200"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.8.2: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Interpreting Graphs of Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph below represents the total number of smartphones that are shipped to a retail store over the course of days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS NUMBER OF SMARTPHONES AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN DAYS. X-AXIS GOES FROM 0 TO 50 IN INCREMENTS OF 10. Y-AXIS GOES FROM 0 TO 4000 IN INCREMENTS OF 1000. THE GRAPH INCREASES LINEARLY FROM X = 0 TO X = 20,  (SECTION A), REMAINS CONSTANT FROM X = 20 TO X = 25 (SECTION B), AND INCREASES LINEARLY AGAIN BUT WITH A LESS STEEP SLOPE (SECTION C)." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="302" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/43f14296b68c6ce4197490dbbcf41a1014afd550" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Match each part of the graph (A, B, and C) to its verbal description. Explain the reasoning behind your choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type="i"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Half of the factory workers went on strike, and not enough smartphones were produced for normal shipments.&lt;br&gt;C; if half of the workers went on strike, then the number of smartphones produced would be less than normal. The rate of change for C is less than the rate of change for A.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="i"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The production schedule was normal, and smartphones were shipped to the retail store at a constant rate.&lt;br&gt;A; if the production schedule is normal, the rate of change of interval A is greater than the rate of change of interval C.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; A defective electronic chip was found, and the factory had to shut down, so no smartphones were shipped.&lt;br&gt;B; if no smartphones are shipped to the store, the total number remains constant during that time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Interpreting Graphs of Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relationship between Jameson&amp;rsquo;s account balance and time is modeled by the graph below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a story that models the situation represented by the graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS ACCOUNT BALANCE IN DOLLARS AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN DAYS. X-AXIS GOES FROM 0 TO 14 IN INCREMENTS OF 2. Y-AXIS GOES FROM 0 TO 100 IN INCREMENTS OF 20. THE GRAPH REMAINS CONSTANT FROM X = 0 TO X = 6, INCREASES FROM X = 6 TO X = 9, AND THEN DECREASES." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="302" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/3e608acfbdbc5e845f55bd17186a2842d9f2946d" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your notebook, write down your answer. Then select the&lt;strong&gt; Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to write a story based on the graph of this function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample Response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jameson was sick and did not work for almost a whole week. Then, he mowed several lawns over the next few days and deposited the money into his account after each job. It rained several days, so instead of working, Jameson withdrew money from his account each day to go to the movies and out to lunch with friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did you do? Know that you learn more from wrong answers than from right answers! Wrong answers help us find flaws in our thinking. Take a minute to think about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you got the question wrong. Then you won&amp;rsquo;t get this type of question wrong again!&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1923">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659319951</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1924">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659319951</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="860">
        <prevpageid>859</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>861</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659320899</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662753405</timemodified>
        <title>4.8.3: Sketching Graphs of Functions</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (10 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, students analyzed several graphs to see if they could represent the height of a flag being raised in a ceremony. In this activity, students watch a video of a flag being raised. They sketch a possible graph to represent the height of the flag as a function of time, and then they use their graphs to estimate the rate of change of the flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students&amp;rsquo; graphs do not need to be very precise, but they should capture key features of the situation. To do so, students need to make some estimates. For example, they need to gauge the starting height of the flag, the height of the pole, the heights at which pauses happened, whether the flag was moving at a constant rate between the pauses, and so on. Students also need to make some decisions about the graph, for instance: the scale to use on each axis, whether the graph should be discrete or continuous, and so on. Along the way, students engage in aspects of modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If desired and if possible, provide each student or each group with access to the video so students can replay the clip a few times, as needed. As students work, identify those who make different decisions for their graph and can explain their rationale. Ask them to share their work later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time is limited, focus work time and discussion on the graphing portion (the first question).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: For the additional resources, teachers may need to review inequality statements for students to graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell students that they will watch a video of a flag being raised, and their job is to sketch a graph that represents the height of the flag, in feet, as a function of time, in seconds. Explain to students that their graphs do not need to be precise and some estimations are required, but the graphs should reasonably capture the movement of the flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before playing the video, ask students to think about what information or quantities to look for while watching the video. If possible, record and display their ideas for all to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are videos that show the same clip of a flag being raised, played back at full speed and half speed. Show one or more of the videos for all to see. Students may wish to see the slower version a few times to help them sketch a graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full speed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video Raising a Flag (Full Speed) available at &lt;a href="https://player.vimeo.com/video/337951448" target="_blank" title="https://player.vimeo.com/video/337951448"&gt;https://player.vimeo.com/video/337951448&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Half speed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video Raising a Flag (Half Speed) available at &lt;a href="https://player.vimeo.com/video/337951456" target="_blank" title="https://player.vimeo.com/video/337951456"&gt;https://player.vimeo.com/video/337951456&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your teacher will show a video of a flag being raised. Function \(H\) gives the height of the flag over time. Height is measured in feet. Time is measured in seconds since the flag is fully secured to the string, which is when the video clip begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the coordinate plane, sketch a graph that could represent function \(H\). Be sure to include a label and a scale for each axis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student Response&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graph of function H. time in seconds and height in feet." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="178" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/g9uTzUubNEthDKBUoACZsZTd" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some students may have trouble starting their graphs because they don&amp;rsquo;t know what upper limits to use for the axes. Ask them to watch the video clip again and try to gather some information that may help them decide on the upper limits. Assure them that some estimation and decision making are necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select previously identified students to share their graph and explain their drawing decisions. If time permits, display the graphs for all to see and briefly discuss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how the graphs are alike and how they are different.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;key features such as intercepts, maximum, minimum, and intervals when the function increases, remains constant, or decreases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time permits, invite a couple of students to share how they used their graph to estimate the flag&amp;rsquo;s average rate of change. Emphasize that the average rate of change (which would vary for different graphs) represents how fast, on average, the flag was moving from the time it started being raised until the time it reached the top of the pole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use this routine to prepare students for the whole-class discussion. Invite students to quietly circulate and analyze at least 2 other graphs in the room. Give students quiet think time to consider which features of the graphs are alike and which are different. Display these prompts as students move around the room: &amp;ldquo;Where does the maximum height occur?&amp;rdquo;; &amp;ldquo;What scale is used on the axes?&amp;rdquo;; and &amp;ldquo;Where are the constant time intervals?&amp;rdquo; Next, ask students to find a partner to discuss what they noticed. This will help students compare and contrast key features on graphs of the same function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.8.3: Self Check&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marcus is going to the library with his friend Monica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monica lives between the library and Marcus&amp;rsquo;s house.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marcus lives 0.5 mile from Monica, and she lives 0.25 mile from the library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marcus walks to Monica&amp;rsquo;s house in 5 minutes, and he stays there for 15 minutes before they walk together to the library in 3 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you were sketching a graph of Marcus&amp;rsquo;s distance from home in miles with respect to time, in minutes, how would you represent the 15 minutes he was at Monica&amp;rsquo;s house graphically?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A vertical line connecting \((5, 0.5)\) and \((5, 20)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: A vertical line would indicate that Marcus was in 2 different places at the exact same time. The answer is a horizontal line connecting \((5, 0.5)\) and \((20, 0.5)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A line with a constant rate connecting \((0,0)\) and \((5, 0.5)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This is the line that represents the distance from when Marcus leaves his house until he gets to Monica&amp;rsquo;s house. The answer is a horizontal line connecting \((5, 0.5)\) and \((20, 0.5)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A line with a constant rate connecting \((0,0)\) and \((20, 0.5)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This would represent Marcus taking 20 minutes to walk to Monica&amp;rsquo;s house. The answer is a horizontal line connecting \((5, 0.5)\) and \((20, 0.5)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A horizontal line connecting \((5, 0.5)\) and \((20, 0.5)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: When Marcus arrives at Monica&amp;rsquo;s house, 5 minutes have passed and he is 0.5 mile from home. This is represented by \((5, 0.5)\). While he is at Monica&amp;rsquo;s, time passes, but the distance does not change. This can be represented by \((20, 0.5)\). Since the distance is the same, the line is horizontal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4.8.3: Additional Resources&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Graphing Situations as Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Draw a graph representing a function that describes Sam&amp;rsquo;s distance from home over an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Sam rides his bike to his friend&amp;rsquo;s house at a constant rate for 20 minutes.&lt;br&gt;
    B: Sam plays for 20 minutes at his friend&amp;rsquo;s house.&lt;br&gt;
    C: Sam and his friend bike together to an ice cream shop that is between their houses for 20 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a sample graph. Notice that the \(x\)-axis is labeled &amp;ldquo;time in minutes&amp;rdquo; and the \(y\)-axis is labeled &amp;ldquo;distance from home (miles).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distance from home is increasing as Sam rides to his friend&amp;rsquo;s house. While playing at his friend&amp;rsquo;s house, the distance remained constant and unchanged. When Sam left his friend&amp;rsquo;s house for the ice cream shop, the distance from home decreased because the shop is in between their houses, so Sam was getting closer to home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS DISTANCE FROM HOME IN MILES AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN MINUTES. X-AXIS GOES FROM 0 TO 60 IN INCREMENTS OF 10. Y-AXIS GOES FROM 0 TO 3.5 IN INCREMENTS OF 0.5. THE GRAPH INCREASES LINEARLY FROM X = 0 TO X = 20, REACHING A DISTANCE OF 3.25 MILES (SECTION A), REMAINS CONSTANT FROM X = 20 TO X = 40 (SECTION B), AND THEN DECREASES (SECTION C)." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="286" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/270cc818f622d4b3644527d27a8807e4e94fcbbf" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example 2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tyler filled up his bathtub, took a bath, and then drained the tub. The function gives the depth of the water \(B\), in inches, \(t\) minutes after Tyler began to fill the bathtub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Blank coordinate plane, no grid, origin O. Horizontal axis, time, minutes, from 0 to 40 by 10&amp;rsquo;s. Vertical axis, depth, inches, from 0 to 15 by 5&amp;rsquo;s." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="228" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/D6AYvzvXxxwZmd7Ntso6Brc3" width="307"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These statements describe how the water level in the tub was changing over time. Use the statements to sketch an approximate graph of the function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(B(0) = 0\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(B(1) &amp;lt; B(7)\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(B(9) = 11\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(B(10) = B(20)\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(B(20) &amp;gt; B(40)\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sample graph below meets all of the statements above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/b68a468b76a04fd72a662b975eeddc163e5e3622" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Graphing Situations as Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graph from p. 51&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rock climber begins her descent from a height of 50 feet. She slowly descends at a constant rate for 4 minutes. She takes a break for 1 minute; she then realizes she left some of her gear on top of the rock and climbs more quickly back to the top at a constant rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a graph representing this situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your notebook, write down your answer. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to graph the situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS HEIGHT ABOVE THE GROUND IN FEET AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN MINUTES. X-AXIS GOES FROM 0 TO 10 IN INCREMENTS OF 2. Y-AXIS GOES FROM 0 TO 50 IN INCREMENTS OF 10. THE GRAPH DECREASES LINEARLY FROM X = 0 TO X = 4, REMAINS CONSTANT FROM X = 4 TO X = 5, AND THEN INCREASES LINEARLY WITH A STEEPER SLOPE.
" class="atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="286" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/c7da6d46611768a9a4ca95bde74f8c161b357bce" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did you do? Know that you learn more from wrong answers than from right answers! Wrong answers help us find flaws in our thinking. Take a minute to think about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you got the question wrong. Then you won&amp;rsquo;t get this type of question wrong again!&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1925">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659320899</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1926">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659320899</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="861">
        <prevpageid>860</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>862</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659321487</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662658209</timemodified>
        <title>4.8.4: Using Verbal Descriptions to Create Graphs of Functions</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Cool Down (20 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2. Ask students to read the activity statement and be prepared to ask any clarifying questions about the task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After answering students&amp;rsquo; questions, give students a few minutes of quiet time to sketch the graphs for the first situation and then time to discuss the graphs with their partner. Tell partners to discuss their assumptions about the situation and the reasonableness of the graphs based on those assumptions. Ask them to revise their graphs based on each other&amp;rsquo;s feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider selecting a few students to share their graphs and graphing decisions before the class continues to the second and third situations. Discuss questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The water in both hoses flows at a constant rate. Did you assume the constant rate in one hose to be the same as the constant rate in the other hose?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Did you assume that the water for the two hoses was turned on at the same time?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What assumptions did you make about the shape and size of each pool? Did you assume that the pools have the same area for their base and just have different heights, or did you assume that they have different areas?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What assumptions did you make about how water was rising in each pool?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To prepare for a backyard party, a parent uses two identical hoses to fill a small pool that is 15 inches deep and a large pool that is 27 inches deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The height of the water in each pool is a function of time since the water is turned on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Two pools.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/nKjZ5E6qfzTjziVxymiyTLDo" width="350"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are descriptions of three situations. For each situation, sketch the graphs of the two functions on the same coordinate plane, so that \(S(t)\) is the height of the water in the small pool after \(t\) minutes, and \(L(t)\) is the height of the water in the large pool after \(t\) minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both functions, the height of the water is measured in inches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Situation 1: Each hose fills one pool at a constant rate. When the small pool is full, the water for that hose is shut off. The other hose keeps filling the larger pool until it is full.
        &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A blank graph, origin O. Horizontal axis, time in minutes, scale from 0 to 20 by 2s. Vertical axis, height in inches, from 0 to 30 by 3s." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/RwivDVLmjdSo7sbKn1rf9abe"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Situation 2: Each hose fills one pool at a constant rate. When the small pool is full, both hoses are shut off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A blank graph, origin O. Horizontal axis, time in minutes, scale from 0 to 20 by 2s. Vertical axis, height in inches, from 0 to 30 by 3s." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="234" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/RwivDVLmjdSo7sbKn1rf9abe" width="318"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Situation 3: Each hose fills one pool at a &lt;span class="os-raise-ib-tooltip" data-schema-version="1.0" data-store="storename"&gt;constant&lt;/span&gt; rate. When the small pool is full, both hoses are used to fill the large pool until it is full.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A blank graph, origin O. Horizontal axis, time in minutes, scale from 0 to 20 by 2s. Vertical axis, height in inches, from 0 to 30 by 3s." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="234" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/RwivDVLmjdSo7sbKn1rf9abe" width="318"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Situation 1:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Two functions. time in minutes and height in inches." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/f8nS2Awx53CKtTUoGPFyZrAi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Situation 2:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Two functions. time in minutes and height in inches." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/vaRJYEg3GbdvWE4rL7BcCtZi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Situation 3:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Two functions. time in minutes and height in inches." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/1BgWuNEc3aL7UBn6FxjrWx1Y"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt; Support for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use color coding and annotations to highlight connections between representations in a problem. For example, ask students to graph the large pool in one color and the small pool in another color for each graph and highlight relevant information in the description using the same colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some students might mistakenly think that when the pools are &amp;ldquo;full,&amp;rdquo; the water in each pool has reached the same height. Remind students that the two pools have different heights, so it takes different heights of water to make them full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite or select students to share their graphs and the assumptions and decisions they made as they were graphing. Display graphs that correctly represent the same situation but look different because of variation in assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How would the vertical values of the two graphs compare when the pools are full?&amp;rdquo; (The vertical value of the large pool would be up to 12 inches greater than that of the small pool because the large pool is 12 inches taller than the small pool.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;When each pool is being filled by one hose and at the same rate, should the two graphs have the same slope? Why or why not? If not, which graph has a greater slope?&amp;rdquo; (No. The water in the smaller pool rises more quickly because the area of the pool is smaller, so the slope for that graph should be greater.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How would the graph of the large pool change when one hose was moved from the small pool to the large pool? Would its slope increase, decrease, or stay the same?&amp;rdquo; (The slope of the graph for the large pool would double, because water is now rising at twice its previous rate. The graph for the small pool would stay constant, as the water is no longer increasing in height.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use this routine to support whole-class discussion. For each graph that is shared, ask students to use precise mathematical language to restate how the author&amp;rsquo;s assumptions and decisions affected key features of the graph. Ask the original speaker if their peer was able to accurately restate their thinking. Call students&amp;rsquo; attention to any words or phrases that helped clarify the original statement. This routine provides more students with an opportunity to produce language as they interpret the reasoning of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1927">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659321487</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1928">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659321487</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="862">
        <prevpageid>861</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>863</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659366740</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662658269</timemodified>
        <title>4.8.5: Representing Quantities in a Situation </title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Optional Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This optional activity gives students another opportunity to represent the quantities in a situation with a table and a graph, identify key features of the graph, and interpret those features in terms of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are some videos that show the same clip of a ball being dropped, but played back at different speeds. Show one or more of the videos for all to see. Before showing the videos, ask students to think about what information or quantities to look for while watching the videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the original speed:
        Video Tennis Ball Drop (Full Speed) available at &lt;a href="https://player.vimeo.com/video/304121518" target="_blank" title="https://player.vimeo.com/video/304121518"&gt;https://player.vimeo.com/video/304121518&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At half speed:
        Video Tennis Ball Drop (Half Speed) available at &lt;a href="https://player.vimeo.com/video/313399597" target="_blank" title="https://player.vimeo.com/video/313399597"&gt;https://player.vimeo.com/video/313399597&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At quarter speed:
        Video Tennis Ball Drop (Quarter Speed) available at &lt;a href="https://player.vimeo.com/video/313399606" target="_blank" title="https://player.vimeo.com/video/313399606"&gt;https://player.vimeo.com/video/313399606&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If possible, allow students to replay the videos several times to help them sketch as accurate a graph as possible. Alternatively, give students individual access to the interactive applet, if available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your teacher will show you one or more videos of a tennis ball being dropped. Here are some still images of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The height of the ball is a function of time. Suppose the height is \(h\) feet, \(t\) seconds after the ball is dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the blank coordinate plane to sketch a graph of the height of the tennis ball as a function of time.
        To help you get started, here are some pictures and a table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A man dropping a ball.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/WTtRTaNwjScSGve5Eb3qfx5E" width="100"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0.28 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A man dropping a ball.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/NXq9w1CEoU5swVNqLFdtnkwe" width="100"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0.54 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A man dropping a ball.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/K3wZjT9uXu7qyW6WPSs8DW2h" width="100"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0.74 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A man dropping a ball.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/LdVPP17jHkgK6MUxj74QCLeJ" width="100"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.03 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A man dropping a ball.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/KVLfS2LJfZDVUTu7CT5kPyM2" width="100"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.48 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A man dropping a ball.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/52cALTG1Xi1PpH6zxfVYNAf4" width="100"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.88 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A man dropping a ball.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/frBnLkC7yVvogQdf8Kwuk2ya" width="100"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.25 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A man dropping a ball.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/5w6msUM2TvXUeSPdZp8UWGgh" width="100"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete the table with your estimates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time (seconds)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Height (feet)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A _____&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0.28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B _____&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0.54&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C _____&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0.74&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D _____&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.03&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E _____&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.48&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F _____&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.88&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G_____&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H _____&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the table of values to sketch your graph.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A blank graph, origin O. Horizontal axis, time, seconds, scale from 0 to 4 by 0.25&amp;rsquo;s. Vertical axis, height, feet, from 0 to 7 by 0.5&amp;rsquo;s." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/LbergafF6uUM3u1uVPqovjq8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify the \(x\)- and \(y\)-intercepts of the graph. Explain what the coordinates tell us about the tennis ball.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the maximum and minimum values of the function. Explain what they tell us about the tennis ball.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time (seconds)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Height (feet)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0.28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0.54&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0.74&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.03&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 3.5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.48&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.88&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS HEIGHT IN FEET AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN SECONDS. THE HEIGHT OF THE BALL AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IS MODELED BY UPSIDE DOWN PARABOLAS. THE MAXIMUM HEIGHTS OF THE PARABOLAS DECREASE FROM LEFT TO RIGHT. THE FIRST PARABOLA HAS A MAXIMUM HEIGHT AT THE POINT (0, 6).  " class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="309" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/6182729b677a970efe9a347531750accfc7a4e99" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sample response:&lt;br&gt;
        \((0,6)\) is the \(y\)-intercept. It is the height from which the tennis ball is dropped. \((0.54,0)\), \((1.48,0)\), and \((2.25,0)\) are three of the horizontal intercepts. They represent the times at which the ball hits the ground.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sample response: &lt;br&gt;
        The maximum value of the function is 6, at \(t=0\). The height from which the ball is dropped, 6 feet, is its greatest height. The minimum value is 0, at multiple points when the tennis ball hits the ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use this routine to help students improve their verbal and written responses to the question, &amp;ldquo;Find the maximum and minimum values of the function. Explain what they tell us about the tennis ball.&amp;rdquo; Give students time to meet with 2&amp;ndash;3 partners to share and get feedback on their responses. The listener should press for detail and precision in language by asking, &amp;ldquo;Can you say that a different way?&amp;rdquo;; &amp;ldquo;How do you know?&amp;rdquo;; or &amp;ldquo;Can you show this on the table, graph, and video?&amp;rdquo; Invite students to go back and revise or refine their written explanation based on the feedback from their peers. This will help students uncover any gaps in their interpretation of a graph, fine-tune their understanding of what key graphical features represent, and express their interpretation more clearly and precisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Extension&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Are you ready for more?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you only see the still images of the ball and not the video of the ball bouncing, can you accurately graph the height of the ball as a function of time? Explain your reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Extension Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample response: No, each still image gives the position of the ball at a different time, or one point on the graph that represents height as a function of time. But without the video, we would not know what is happening at the time the image is taken: Is the ball going up? Is it coming down? Is it at one of its peaks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some students may mistake the horizontal axis on the graph to represent horizontal distance rather than time. Because the movement of the bouncing ball is primarily up and down (except toward the end, when it began rolling), these students might sketch a graph that is essentially a series of overlapping vertical segments. Ask them to revisit the input variable and what the horizontal axis represents. Then, ask them to plot some points for different values of \(t\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss how students translated the movement of the dropped ball into a graph and the connections between the graph and the situation. Ask questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Which parts of the ball&amp;rsquo;s movement did you find easier to plot more precisely? Which parts require estimating?&amp;rdquo; (The original position of the ball when it was released and the points when it hit the ground were easier to plot because they were more distinct and obvious. The points when the ball reached a peak and changed direction required a bit of estimation. The points between the peaks and the bounces were mainly estimated.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In this case, the horizontal intercepts are also the minimums of the graph. Why is that?&amp;rdquo; (The ball could not have a height that is less than 0. The lowest point it could be is 0 feet.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What happened to the output value, \(h\), as the input value, \(t\), increased?&amp;rdquo; (Overall, the output decreased as \(t\) increased, but there were intervals&amp;mdash;whenever the ball bounced up&amp;mdash;in which the height of the ball increased as time increased.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time permits, discuss students&amp;rsquo; responses to the last two questions.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1929">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659366740</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1930">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659366740</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="863">
        <prevpageid>862</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>864</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659367320</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662673062</timemodified>
        <title>4.8.6: Practice</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Students will complete the following questions to practice the skills they have learned in this lesson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. The graphs show the distance,d, traveled by two cars, A and B, over time,t. Distance is measured in miles and time is measured in hours.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lines A and B on coordinate plane." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/DrJGLMHZjQm62pJfZyYfcNbP"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which car traveled slower?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    Car A
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    Car B
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;Car A traveled slower because Car B was a further distance in the same amount of time as car A:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For #2-5 use the graphs below to match each description of a situation in which the volume of water in a tank is a function of time to its corresponding graph.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graph 1&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Graph on coordinate plane, no grid, Origin O. V shaped graph, line begins on Y axis, Vertex points down." role="image" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/Fqxu9r5i5fmYYt5SKJZWMHU8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graph 2&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Graph on coordinate plane, no grid, Origin O. Line begins at origin, moves upwards and to right. Steeper second segment." role="image" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/EmJAvPvTKEtb758Sn3sV6h4g"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graph 3&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Graph on coordinate plane, no grid, Origin O. V shaped graph, line begins on at origin, Vertex points up." role="image" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/EuFd4TFUo3NLWgA8uiFJKG9q"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graph 4&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Graph on coordinate plane, no grid, Origin O. Line begins at origin, moves upwards and to right, decreases briefly, then increases again." role="image" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/YGbHfqUkzqsNt7YciSQR42v2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    Graph 1
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    Graph 2
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    Graph 3
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    Graph 4
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An empty 20-gallon water tank is filled at a constant rate for 3 minutes until it is half full. Then, it is emptied at a constant rate for 3 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; Graph 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A full 10-gallon water tank is drained for 30 seconds, until it is half full. Afterwards, it gets refilled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; Graph 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 2,000-gallon water tank starts out empty. It is being filled for 5 hours, slowly at first, and faster later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; Graph 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="5"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An empty 100-gallon water tank is filled in 50 minutes. Then, a dog jumps in and splashes around for 10 minutes, letting 7 gallons of water out. The tank is refilled afterwards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;Graph 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For #6-7, use this situation and function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The daily cost to the manufacturing company is modeled by the function&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C(x)=7.25x+2500 where C(x) is the total daily cost and x is the number of items manufactured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="6"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is C(0)?&amp;nbsp; Enter an integer only. No commas or symbols.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 2500&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="7"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does C(0) mean in the context of the situation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;Cost before any items are manufactured&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1931">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659367320</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1932">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659367320</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="864">
        <prevpageid>863</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659367406</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662658367</timemodified>
        <title>4.8.7: Lesson Synthesis</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;Representing a function with a graph requires careful attention to the behavior of the quantities in the situation. To reinforce this idea, tell students that they will observe you walking from one end of the classroom to the other, and suppose they were to graph your distance from the starting point as a function of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students to notice any characteristics of the movement that would affect the output of this function and show up as distinct features on a graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk from one side of the classroom to the other, incorporating moves such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;walking at a constant rate all the way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slowing down and speeding up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;walking one way and then turning around and walking back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;taking a few steps, stopping and standing still, and then continuing walking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;walking backward a few steps, and then walking forward again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solicit as many observations as possible about the walk. For each observation that students make, ask them how it would affect a graph of the function. For instance, students may note that slowing down and speeding up translate to shallower and steeper lines, respectively. They may also say that stopping translates to a horizontal segment on the graph, and that the longer the pause, the longer the segment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time permits, repeat the walking demonstration and ask students to graph the function.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1933">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659367406</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1934">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659367406</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>
