<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="91" moduleid="123" modulename="lesson" contextid="134">
  <lesson id="91">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Lesson 4.6 Teacher Guide: Features of Graphs</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>0</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password/>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>0</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>124</activitylink>
    <mediafile/>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>1</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1660607516</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="813">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>814</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659140348</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662655881</timemodified>
        <title>4.6.0: Lesson Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Narrative&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to this point, students have described characteristics of graphs, made sense of points on the graphs, and interpreted them in terms of a situation. In this lesson, students develop this work more formally, while continuing to use the idea of function as the focusing lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students use mathematical terms such as &amp;ldquo;intercept,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;maximum,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;minimum&amp;rdquo; in their graphical analyses, and they relate features of graphs to features of the functions represented. For instance, they look at an interval in which a graph shows a positive slope and interpret that to mean an interval where the function&amp;rsquo;s values are increasing. Students also use statements in function notation, such as \(h(0)\) and \(h(t)=0\), to talk about key features of a graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now, students are familiar with the idea of intercepts. Note that in these materials, the terms &amp;ldquo;horizontal intercept&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;vertical intercept&amp;rdquo; are used to refer to intercepts more generally, especially when a function is defined using variables other than \(x\) and \(y\). If needed, clarify these terms for students who may be accustomed to using only \(x\)-intercept and \(y\)-intercept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As students look for connections across representations of functions and relate them to quantities in situations, they practice making sense of problems and reasoning quantitatively and abstractly. Using mathematical terms and notation to describe features of graphs and features of functions calls for attention to precision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Goals (Teacher Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze connections between statements that use function notation and features of graphs and describe (orally and in writing) these connections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interpret key features of a graph&amp;mdash;the intercepts, maximums, minimums, and the intervals when the function is increasing or decreasing&amp;mdash;in terms of a situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand and be able to use the terms &amp;ldquo;horizontal intercept,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;vertical intercept,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;maximum,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;minimum&amp;rdquo; when talking about graphs of functions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Learning Targets (Student Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify important features of graphs of functions and explain what they mean in the situations represented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain and apply the terms &amp;ldquo;horizontal intercept,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;vertical intercept,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;maximum,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;minimum&amp;rdquo; when talking about functions and their graphs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify important features of linear functions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TEKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation of Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A3(C) graph linear functions on the coordinate plane and identify key features, including \(x\) intercept, \(y\)-intercept, zeros, and slope, in mathematical and real-world problems;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full coverage: Lesson provides content that covers all parts of this TEKS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the instructional activities for the lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.6.1: Interpreting Statements in Function Notation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.6.2: Analyzing Graphs of Functions
        &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.6.2: Self Check&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.6.2: Additional Resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.6.3: Connecting Graphical and Verbal Representations of a Function&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.6.3: Self Check&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.6.3: Additional Resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.6.4: Key Features of Linear Functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.6.4: Self Check&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.6.4: Additional Resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.6.5: Interpreting Graphs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will also complete a series of problems in the 4.6.6: Practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Vocabulary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this lesson, it is important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarize students with the vocabulary words they will see throughout the lesson. Encourage students to look for these words and notice their use and meanings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage students to use key vocabulary words in &amp;ldquo;math talk&amp;rdquo; and their written and oral explanations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilize a word wall. Sample cards are located here: &lt;a href="https://www.doe.virginia.gov/instruction/mathematics/resources/vocab_cards/" target="_blank"&gt;Mathematics Vocabulary Word Wall Cards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary words that are emphasized in this lesson include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;function&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;variable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;relation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;constant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slope&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;zero&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maximum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minimum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(x\)-intercept or horizontal intercept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(y\)-intercept or vertical intercept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Social Emotional Learning (SEL) Support&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, find ways to encourage and support students to work on cultivating their &lt;strong&gt;creativity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to try during this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/finding-flow/" target="_blank"&gt;Finding Flow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/less-can-be-more/" target="_blank"&gt;Less Can Be More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other tips located here in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/playbooks/creativity" target="_blank"&gt;Playbook on Creativity&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;from Character Lab.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1818">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659140348</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="814">
        <prevpageid>813</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>815</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659140682</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662655918</timemodified>
        <title>4.6.1: Interpreting Statements in Function Notation</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt; Warm Up (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This warm-up is an opportunity to practice interpreting statements in function notation. It also draws attention to statements that correspond to the intercepts of a graph of a function (for instance, \(d(0)\) and \(d(m)=0\)), preparing students to reason about them in the lesson (particularly in the second activity).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diego is walking home from school at a constant rate. This graph represents function \(d\), which gives his distance from home, in kilometers, \(m\) minutes since leaving the school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the graph to find or estimate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graph of line. Horizontal axis, 0 to 24 by 4&amp;rsquo;s, minutes since leaving school. Vertical axis, 0 to 3 by point&amp;nbsp;5&amp;rsquo;s, kilometers from home. Line starts at about 0 comma 2 point 2 5, and ends at 20 comma 0." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/L4n73RvtJataLPDziWP4p76S"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is \(d(0)\), and what does it represent in the situation?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(d(12) =\)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does \(d(m)=1\) mean in this context, and what is the value of \(m\)?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does \(d(m)=0\) mean in this context, and what is the value of \(m\)?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(d(0)=2.25\); The moment Diego is leaving school, he is 2.25 kilometers from home (or Diego&amp;rsquo;s school is a little more than 2 kilometers from his house).&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(d(12)=0.9\)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(m\) is approximately 10.5. At approximately 10.5 minutes, Diego is 1 kilometer from home.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(m\) is 20. At 20 minutes, Diego is at home (or it takes Diego 20 minutes to walk the 2.25 kilometers home from school).&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students to interpret each statement in function notation before soliciting their response to each question. Make sure students understand, for instance, that \(d(0)\) represents Diego&amp;rsquo;s distance from school at the time of leaving (or at 0 minutes), and \(d(m)=0\) represents his distance from school being 0 km, \(m\) minutes after leaving his house.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time permits, discuss with students:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is the relationship between Diego&amp;rsquo;s distance from school and time a linear function? How can we tell?&amp;rdquo; (Yes. The graph is a line, which means the function&amp;rsquo;s value changes at a constant rate.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Can we tell from the graph how far away Diego&amp;rsquo;s house is from school? How?&amp;rdquo; (Yes. From the graph, we can see that at the time he leaves his house, he is 2.25 km from school.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Can we tell from the graph how long it took Diego to get home? How?&amp;rdquo; (Yes. From the graph, we can see the distance reaching 0 when the time is 20 minutes.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why does the graph slant downward (or have a negative slope)?&amp;rdquo; (As the input, \(m\),&amp;nbsp;increases, the output, \(9d(m)\), decreases.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1819">
            <jumpto>0</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659140682</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1820">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659140682</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="815">
        <prevpageid>814</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>816</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659141490</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662656009</timemodified>
        <title>4.6.2: Analyzing Graphs of Functions</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this activity, students examine graphs of functions, identify and describe their key features, and connect these features to the situations represented. These key features include the horizontal and vertical intercepts, maximums and minimums, and intervals where a function is increasing or decreasing (or where a graph has a positive or a negative slope).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither the features nor the terms are likely new to students. The idea of intercepts was introduced in middle school and further developed in earlier units. Graphical features such as maximums and minimums have been considered intuitively in various cases. They are simply more precisely defined here. In a later activity, students will distinguish between a maximum of a graph and the maximum of a function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give students about 5 minutes of quiet work time. Follow with a whole-class discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use this routine to help students interpret a situation to identify the key features of a graph. Display the student task statement and graphs, without the questions. Ask students to write down possible mathematical questions that could be asked about the situation. Invite students to compare their questions before revealing the activity&amp;rsquo;s questions. Listen for and amplify any questions involving the behavior of the toy rocket and drone, or questions about features or places on the graph that show important information about each object&amp;rsquo;s movement. This will help students produce the language of key features of graphs of functions, such as maximum, minimum, and intervals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help students get started, display sentence frames such as: &amp;ldquo;It looks like . . .,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I notice that . . .,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;_____ represents _____,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;What does this part of _____ mean?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A toy rocket and a drone were launched at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the graphs that represent the heights of two objects as a function of time since they were launched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Height is measured in meters above the ground, and time is measured in seconds since launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="2 graphs. Horizontal axis, 0 to 7, time in seconds. Vertical axis, 0 to 50 by 10&amp;rsquo;s, height in meters. Graph R is a parabolic and opens down. Graph D is piecewise linear." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/M7kSmncpv7Zi5VBoiswbhXcU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze the graph of the toy rocket and describe as precisely as you can what was happening. Your description should be complete and precise enough that someone who is not looking at the graph could visualize how the object was behaving. Include where the toy rocket starts and when it stops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze the graph of the drone and describe as precisely as you can what was happening. Your description should be complete and precise enough that someone who is not looking at the graph could visualize how the object was behaving. Include where the drone starts and when it stops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At what point were the drone and the toy rocket at the same height?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which parts or features of the graphs show important information about each object&amp;rsquo;s movement? List the features or mark them on the graphs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample Responses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The toy rocket was launched from a height of 25 meters above ground. It went up quickly, but it slowed down and then stopped getting higher when it reached 45 meters, which was 2 seconds after launch. At that point, it started to come back down. It hit the ground 5 seconds after it was launched.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The drone took off from the ground. It went up at a constant speed for 2 seconds, up to a height of 20 meters. Then, it hovered at that height for 3 seconds. Afterward, it started descending at a constant speed for 2 seconds. It landed back on the ground 7 seconds after launch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A little after 4 seconds, the drone and the toy rocket were at the same height (20 meters).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sample Responses:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the points where the graphs begin (when \(t\) is 0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the points where the graphs cross the horizontal axis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the point where the graphs change direction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the shape of each graph (curved or straight)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the intervals when the graphs behave certain ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the parts highlighted in the graph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Two nonlinear functions. time in seconds and height in meters." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/ifnt1dCUFVMHqqwCRzWJWA1R"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When analyzing the graphs and describing what is happening with each object, some students may mistakenly think that the horizontal axis represents horizontal distance, neglecting to notice that it represents time. They may then describe how the objects were moving vertically as they traveled horizontally, rather than with respect to the number of seconds since they took off. Encourage these students to check the label of each axis and revisit their descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select a few students to share their description of the graphs, and have each student describe the motion of one flying object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Display a blank coordinate plane for all to see. As each student shares their response, sketch a graph to match what is being described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Blank graph. time in seconds and height in meters." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/R68qdMqskCRyE5M2X8VN2h9p"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any gaps in their description, make assumptions and sketch accordingly. (For example, if a student states that the toy rocket reaches a height of 45 meters after 2 seconds but does not state its starting height, start the curve at \((0,0)\), \((0,40)\), or any other point besides \((0,25)\).) If requested, allow students to refine their descriptions and adjust the sketch accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, invite other students to share their response to the last question. On the graphs, highlight the features students noted. (See Student Response for an example.) Use the terms &amp;ldquo;vertical intercepts,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;horizontal intercepts,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;maximum,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;minimum&amp;rdquo; to refer to those features and label them on the graphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain to students that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A point on the graph that is as high as or higher than all other points is called a maximum of the graph (or a relative maximum because its height is viewed in relation to other points shown on the graph).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A point on the graph that is as low as or lower than all other points is called a minimum of the graph (or a relative minimum).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A graph could have more than one relative maximum or minimum. For instance, the points \((2,(D(2))\) and \((5,D(5))\) are both relative maximums, and \((0,D(0))\) and \((7,D(7))\) are both relative minimums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If no students mentioned the intervals in which each function was increasing, staying constant, or decreasing, draw their attention to these features on the graphs and label them as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4.6.2: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="302"&gt;
&lt;col width="322"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph below represents the temperature, \(t(m)\), in degrees Fahrenheit of water used for a cup of hot tea over time in minutes, \(m\). What does \(t(0)\) represent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS TEMPERATURE IN DEGREES FAHRENHEIT AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN MINUTES WITH A Y-INTERCEPT OF 70. THE GRAPH INCREASES, THEN DECREASES, AND THEN REMAINS CONSTANT." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="299" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/53af2afc0c96fc02a8264cbdf88c9777b1db4a7e" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(t(0)=70\); After 70 minutes, the temperature is 0 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: Remember the value inside the parentheses is the minutes passed, so \(t(0)\) means 0 minutes have passed. The answer is \(t(0)=70\); At 0 minutes, the temperature is 70 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(t(0)=180\); After 0 minutes, the temperature is 180 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: On the graph provided, the graph intersects the vertical axis at 70, not 180. The answer is \(t(0)=70\); at 0 minutes, the temperature is 70 degrees.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(t(0)=70\); After 0 minutes, the temperature is 70 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: \(t(0)= 70\) means that the \(x\) value is 0, or it is the point on the vertical axis. The point where the graph intersects the vertical axis is 70 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(t(0)= 180\); After 180 minutes, the temperature is 0 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: Remember the value inside the parentheses is the minutes passed, so \(t(0)\) means 0 minutes have passed. The answer is \(t(0)=70\); At 0 minutes, the temperature is 70 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Real-Life Graphs of Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A ball is bouncing across the school yard. The vertical or \(y\)-axis represents the height of the ball in feet, \(h(t)\), while the horizontal or \(x\)-axis represents the time, \(t\), that has passed in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS THE HEIGHT OF A BALL IN FEET AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN SECONDS WITH A Y-INTERCEPT OF 0 AND X-INTERCEPTS OF 0 AND 1. FROM X = 0 TO X = 1, THE HEIGHT OF THE BALL IS MODELED BY AN UPSIDE DOWN PARABOLA WITH A MAXIMUM AT THE POINT (0.5, 4)." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="293" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/9c26e6224714d52a4570a234fc52d7c5e8f1ed28" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the graph, \(t=0\) represents the first time the ball touches the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is \(h(1)\), and what does it represent in the context of the problem?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(1) = 0\), and it represents the height of the ball after 1 second, or the ball has a height of zero after 1 second. The value inside of the parentheses is the value from the \(x\)-axis or horizontal axis. The solution is the value of the graph at that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Real-Life Graphs of Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A ball is thrown across the field from point \(A\) to point \(B\). It hits the ground at point \(B\). The path of the ball is shown in the diagram below. The \(x\)-axis shows the horizontal distance the ball travels in feet, and the&amp;nbsp;\(y\)-axis shows the height of the ball in feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A GRAPH THAT SHOWS THE HEIGHT OF A BALL IN FEET AS A FUNCTION OF THE HORIZONTAL DISTANCE THE BALL TRAVELS IN FEET WITH A Y-INTERCEPT OF A AND X-INTERCEPT OF B." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="286" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/c4b05b9a3e4017c647d7a55d809600b48753f3f0" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain what \(f(C)\) means in this graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your notebook, write down your answer. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to explain \(f(C)\) in the graph:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(f(C)\) tells you to look at the height of the graph when \(x=C\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This point on the graph is the highest point, or maximum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did you do? Know that you learn more from wrong answers than from right answers! Wrong answers help us find flaws in our thinking. Take a minute to think about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you got the question wrong. Then you won&amp;rsquo;t get this type of question wrong again!&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1821">
            <jumpto>814</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659141490</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1822">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659141490</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="816">
        <prevpageid>815</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>817</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659142155</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662671524</timemodified>
        <title>4.6.3: Connecting Graphical and Verbal Representations of a Function</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the lesson, students identified key features of a graph of a function and related them to the features of a situation. In this activity, students continue to connect graphical and verbal representations of a function, applying the mathematical terms they learned. They also connect each feature (described in words and on the graph) to an expression or equation that could represent it mathematically, written in function notation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the activity synthesis, students learn to distinguish between a maximum or minimum of a graph (relative maximum or minimum) and the maximum or minimum of a function (absolute maximum or minimum). Students see that a maximum of a graph refers to a point on a graph that is as high as or higher than all other points, while the maximum of a function is a function value that is equal to or greater than all other values of that function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2. Give students a few minutes of quiet think time, and then time to discuss their response with their partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As students share their matches and explain their reasoning to their partner, display the following sentence frames for all to see: "_____ matches _____ because . . .", "I noticed _____ , so I matched . . .", and "The strategy that I used was . . . ." Encourage students to challenge each other when they disagree. While monitoring discussions, amplify student ideas to demonstrate use of mathematical language such as "first peak", "maximum", "minimum", or "vertical intercept." This routine will help students connect graphical and verbal representations of a function through partner discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bungee jump, the height of the jumper is a function of time since the jump begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;img alt="Woman bungee jumping." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/cUTfhB1hZqq8aHGi2hRpgWBY" width="300"&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Function h defines the height, in meters, of a jumper above a river, t seconds since leaving the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a graph of function h, followed by five expressions or equations and five graphical features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Pick up images from Moodle&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graph of curve. Horizontal axis, 0 to 35 by 5&amp;rsquo;s, t, seconds. Vertical axis, 0 to 90 by 10&amp;rsquo;s, h, meters. Curve starts a 0 comma 80, decreases then increases, 4 times." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/8C4mSxgix4eDvkKxWkU3T7cu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expressions and Equations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(0)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(t)=0\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(4)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(t)=80\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(t)=45\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first dip in the graph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vertical intercept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first peak in the graph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;horizontal intercept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maximum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Match each description about the jump to a corresponding expression or equation and to a feature on the graph.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One expression or equation does not have a matching verbal description. Its corresponding graphical feature is also not shown on the graph. Interpret that expression or equation in terms of the jump and in terms of the graph of the function. Record your interpretation in the last row of the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col width="204"&gt;
&lt;col width="180"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description of Jump&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expression or Equation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feature of Graph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the greatest height that the jumper is from the river&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the height from which the jumper was jumping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the time at which the jumper reached the highest point after the first bounce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the lowest point that the jumper reached in the entire jump&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the graph to:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li aria-level="2"&gt;
            estimate h(0) and h(4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li aria-level="2"&gt;
        estimate the solutions to h(t)=45 and &amp;planckh;(𝑡)=0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col width="204"&gt;
&lt;col width="180"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description of Jump&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expression or Equation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feature of Graph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the greatest height that the jumper is from the river&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(t)=80\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;maximum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the height from which the jumper was jumping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(0)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt; vertical intercept&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the time at which the jumper reached the highest point after the first bounce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(t)=45\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt; first peak in the graph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the lowest point that the jumper reached in the entire jump&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(4)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;first dip in the graph also the minimum of the graph shown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the time at which the jumper hits the surface of the river&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt; \h(t)=0\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;horizontal intercept&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(0)\) is 80 and \(h(4)\) is about 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no solution to h(t)=0 when t is between 0 and 35, which is what is shown on the graph. We don't know if it will have a solution when t is greater than 35.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Video: The Meaning of Function Notation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the following video to learn more about connecting graphical and verbal representations of a function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls="true" crossorigin="anonymous" width="550"&gt;
&lt;source src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/08336f60e67c7d416294bbeff0c6da750df4db0f"&gt;
&lt;track default="true" kind="captions" label="On" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/7a54bafd8b198ef12274c9fdae36bad6e6a563d5" srclang="en_us"&gt;https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/08336f60e67c7d416294bbeff0c6da750df4db0f
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The horizontal intercept is also called the x-intercept or zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vertical intercept is also called the y-intercept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Extension&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Are you ready for more?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the information available, how long do you think the bungee cord is? Make an estimate and explain your reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Extension Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample response: About 50 meters. The low points on the graph increase with each bounce and the high points decrease. They look like they are approaching about 30 meters in height above the river. Since the jump started from 80 meters above the river, this means that the bungee cord is about 50 meters long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have students pair up to share how they made their matches and how they interpreted the expression or equation without a matching verbal description. The teacher should circulate checking answers and listening for outliers.&amp;nbsp; Have students share the different responses if time or just share outliers with whole class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure students can interpret \(h(t)=0\) to mean that the jumper is no longer in the air and is in fact on the surface of the water. Because the graph has no horizontal intercept, and because no verbal descriptions to this effect were given, we know \(h(t)=0\) had no match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, ask students to share their response to the last set of questions. Discuss with students why \(h(t)=0\) has no solutions based on the information we have. It is possible that, if the graph is extended to include more time, we might see a representation of the jumper somehow reaching the water. But given the graph as is, it doesn't have a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a good time to introduce the distinction between a maximum (or minimum) of a graph and the maximum (or minimum) of a function. Ask students,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"What is the greatest value of function h?" (80)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"How do we know that 80 is the greatest, or that h(t) could not have greater values?" (The jumper could not be higher than the jumping platform.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"What is the least value of function h?" (about 10, based on the graph)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"How do we know that 10 is the least value, or that h(t) could not have lesser values?" (We don't. The jumper could go lower, say, if lowered into a receiving boat, or if released into the river.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain that, in this case, the graph has one maximum, or one point that is higher than all the other points, and it coincides with the maximum of the function, which is the greatest value of the function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph also has a minimum, \((4,h(4))\), which is lower than all other points shown on the graph, but this point does not represent the minimum of the function, or the lowest value the function could have. The function h could have 0 as its minimum (or a negative value if the jumper goes diving), but as far as the given graph is concerned, \((4,10)\) is a minimum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emphasize that a maximum (or minimum) of a graph is a point, and it gets labeled as such relative to other points visible on the graph. The maximum (or minimum) of a function, however, is a value that is the greatest (or least) for any input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.6.3: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="302"&gt;
&lt;col width="322"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph models the height, in feet, of a kickball over time. When is the ball at its maximum height?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS THE HEIGHT OF A KICKBALL IN FEET AS A FUNCTION OF TIME. THE FUNCTION IS MODELED BY AN UPSIDE DOWN PARABOLA WITH A Y-INTERCEPT OF 0, X-INTERCEPTS OF 0 AND 5, AND MAXIMUM AT THE POINT (2.5, 31).  " src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/52bf6fed91de1b38a4b18768528cfd1e3a733a03" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(2.5) = 31\), The maximum height is about 31 feet.&amp;nbsp; It occurred about 2.5 seconds after the ball was kicked&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: Maximums are the highest points on the graph. The maximum of this graph \(h(2.5)=31\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(5)=0\), The maximum height occurs about 6 seconds after the ball was kicked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: \(h(5)=0\) represents the point when the ball returns to the ground, or the horizontal axis intercept. The answer is The maximum of this graph \(h(2.5)=31\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(1)=20\), The maximum height occurred 1 second after the ball was kicked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The maximum is the highest point on the graph. \(h(1)=20\) is not the highest point. The answer is \(h(2.5)=31\). The maximum of this graph is 31.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(2.5) = 31\), The maximum height is about 2.5 feet.&amp;nbsp; It occurred about 31 seconds after the ball was kicked&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The maximum is the highest value on the vertical axis. \(h(2.5)=31\) is the correct answer, but the 2.5 represents the time and 31 represents the height. The answer is the maximum is about 31 feet and it occurred after 2.5 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.6.3: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;More Real Life Graphs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph below represents the total number of smartphones that are shipped to a retail store over the course of 50 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS THE NUMBER OF SMARTPHONES SHIPPED TO A RETAIL STORE AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN DAYS. THE X-AXIS GOES FROM 0 TO 50 IN INTERVALS OF 10. THE Y-AXIS GOES FROM 0 TO 4000 IN INCREMENTS OF 1000. THE GRAPH IS INCREASING LINEARLY FROM X = 0 TO X = 20, REMAINS CONSTANT FROM X = 20 TO X = 22, AND INCREASES FROM X = 22 TO X = 50." src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/12cba5171ae37e99a45b15309883f04b1241127f" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does \(f(20) =f(22)\)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since section B is not changing it represents the period of time where the store did not receive new shipments, so \(f(20)=f(22)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It:More Real Life Graphs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relationship between Jameson&amp;rsquo;s account balance B, in dollars, and time t, in days, is modeled by the graph below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS ACCOUNT BALANCE IN DOLLARS AS A FUNCTION OF TIME IN DAYS. THE X-AXIS GOES FROM 0 TO 14 IN INTERVALS OF 2. THE Y-AXIS GOES FROM 0 TO 100 IN INTERVALS OF 20. THE GRAPH IS CONSTANT FROM X = 0 TO X = 6, INCREASES FROM X = 6 TO X = 9, REACHING A MAXIMUM AT THE POINT (9, 100), AND THEN DECREASES." src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/3e608acfbdbc5e845f55bd17186a2842d9f2946d" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does the point \(B(9)=100\) represent in the context of the problem?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer. Then select the Solution button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to describe what \(B(9)=100\) represents in the context of the problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(B(9)=100\) represents the maximum amount of money Jameson had in his account over the time period shown. It also represents that after 9 days Jameson had $100 in his account.&amp;nbsp; It is the maximum because it is the highest point on the graph provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did you do? Know that you learn more from wrong answers than from right answers! Wrong answers help us find flaws in our thinking. Take a minute to think about why you got the question wrong. Then you won&amp;rsquo;t get this type of question wrong again!&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1823">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659142155</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1824">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659142155</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="817">
        <prevpageid>816</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>818</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659142793</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662656191</timemodified>
        <title>4.6.4: Key Features of Linear Functions</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the lesson, students explored key features of the graphs of functions and what they mean in the context of a real life situation. Now, students will focus specifically on the graphs of linear functions. Students will identify \(x\)-intercepts as zeros, \(y\)-intercepts, and slopes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2. Give students a few minutes of quiet think time, and then time to discuss their response with their partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The graph of \(f(x)=2x+6\) is graphed below. Answer the questions about the linear function and its key features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH OF A LINE WITH AN X-INTERCEPT OF &amp;minus;3 AND Y-INTERCEPT OF 6." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="297" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/883d5444bd5bb58e4fd98f9e360dd63cace83db2" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the value of \(f(-3)\)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What key feature of the linear function is the point \((-3,0)\)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the slope of the linear function?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What part of the linear function is the point \((0, 6)\)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The amount of money Adam saves in dollars is shown in the graph below:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH THAT SHOWS THE TOTAL AMOUNT OF MONEY IN DOLLARS AS A FUNCTION OF NUMBER OF DAYS. THE FUNCTION IS A LINE WITH A POSITIVE SLOPE THAT PASSES THROUGH THE POINTS (0, 3) AND (1, 6)." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="301" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/a963f822c76db76cac7225e978193e50fed19143" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the \(y\)-intercept of the graph, and what does it mean in the context of the problem?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the slope, and what does it mean in the context of the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The \(x\)-intercept, or zero&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The \(y\)-intercept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The point is \((0,3)\). When Adam started saving, he already had 3 dollars on&amp;nbsp;day 0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The slope is 3. Every 1 day, Adam saves 3 dollars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.6.3: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the zero of the linear function graphed below?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="287" role="presentation" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/a4e78c9d977949a2a60660a6e22115c74c8f3cbb" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\((6,0)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: The zero is where the function crosses the \(x\)-axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\((0, -4)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This is the \(y\)-intercept. The zero is located where the function value is zero, at the \(x\)-intercept. The answer is \((6,0)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\((0,6)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The \(x\)-coordinate is the first value in the ordered pair, and the \(y\)-coordinate is the second value. The answer is \((6,0)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\((0, 0)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This is the origin, but it is not a point on the graph of this linear function. The answer is \((6,0)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.6.4: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Features of Linear Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="287" role="presentation" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/d2528fdbf66913acdf643a44889ebba7613b3d35" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph of a linear function forms a line that goes on forever in both directions. Since the ends go to infinity and negative infinity, linear functions do not have maximums or minimums, unless their domain is restricted to a specific part of the graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can still pick out key features of linear functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The \(x\)-intercept, or zero, is where the line crosses the \(x\)-axis. This is where the \(y\)-coordinate is 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this linear function, the \(x\)-intercept, or zero, is \(x= 2\) and written as the point \((2,0)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The \(y\)-intercept is where the line crosses the \(y\)-axis and the \(x\)-coordinate is 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this linear function, the \(y\)-intercept is \(y=4\) and written as the point \((0,4)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slope of the line can be found as in previous units as the change in&amp;nbsp;\(y\)&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;over the change in&amp;nbsp;\(x\).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(\mathrm m=\;\frac{\mathrm{rise}}{\mathrm{run}}=\;\frac{\mathrm{change}\;\mathrm{in}\;\mathrm y}{\mathrm{change}\;\mathrm{in}\;\mathrm x}\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slope of this linear function is \(m=4-2=-2\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Features of Linear Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the \(x\)-intercept and \(y\)-intercept of the linear function graphed below. Write each answer as a point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="287" role="presentation" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/3a846a909d6e4ffde27212c03128bea3a91b03c8" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your notebook, write down your answer. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Solution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to find the intercepts of a linear function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the line crosses the \(x\)-axis at about \((-2.75, 0)\), that is the \(x\)-intercept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the line crosses the \(y\)-axis at \((0,2)\), that is the \(y\)-intercept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did you do? Know that you learn more from wrong answers than from right answers! Wrong answers help us find flaws in our thinking. Take a minute to think about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you got the question wrong. Then you won&amp;rsquo;t get this type of question wrong again!&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1825">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659142793</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1826">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659142793</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="818">
        <prevpageid>817</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>819</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659143035</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662656243</timemodified>
        <title>4.6.5: Interpreting Graphs</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Cool Down (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A squirrel runs up and down a tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph shows the height of the squirrel, \(h\) (feet), as a function of time, \(t\) (seconds).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Piecewise graph. Horizontal axis, 0 to 8, time, seconds. Vertical axis, 0 to 16, height, feet. Graph starts at 0 comma 9, increases, deceases to 4 comma 0, increases, then flattens out at 6 comma 10." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/p88qiKEEgqdKL9Zt2xe2yL3K"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the highest point the squirrel reaches?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solve \(h(t)=0\). What does this solution tell you about the squirrel?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the vertical intercept of the graph. What does it tell you about the squirrel?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;14 feet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(t=4\) means that after 4 seconds, the squirrel is at the bottom of the tree on the ground.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\((0,9)\) means that at the beginning, the squirrel is 9 feet high in the tree.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Response to Student Thinking&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt; More Chances&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will have more opportunities to understand the mathematical ideas in this cool-down, so there is no need to slow down or add additional work to the next lessons. Instead, use the results of this cool-down to provide guidance for what to look for and emphasize over the next several lessons to support students in advancing their current understanding.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1827">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659143035</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1828">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659143035</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="819">
        <prevpageid>818</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>820</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659143609</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662671936</timemodified>
        <title>4.6.6: Practice</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Students will complete the following questions to practice the skills they have learned in this lesson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This graph represents Andre&amp;rsquo;s distance from his bicycle as he walks in a park.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graph of Andre&amp;rsquo;s distance from his bicycle, coordinate plane, origin \(O\).&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/qKcjqvS26LYHe1ih3Y6kSJSw"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decide whether the following statements are true or false.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The graph has multiple horizontal intercepts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; True&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A horizontal intercept of the graph represents the time when Andre was with his bike.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; True&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A maximum of the graph is the point \((17,1)\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; False&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The graph represents the temperature, in degrees Fahrenheit, as a function of time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Function on coordinate plane." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/dnzPax941KGL3QxT2H4fhd7J"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At what hour in the afternoon does the maximum of the graph occur? Insert integers only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;3 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Match each feature of the situation with a corresponding statement in function notation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Function on coordinate plane." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/fd4jL9YGpAybVPhgLf8Lpr4p"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(h(0)= 7\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Starting height&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(h(1.5)\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; Minimum height&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(h(4)\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Maximum height &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="4" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(h(t)=6\) for \(7\leq\;\mathrm t\;\leq8\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Height staying the same&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The graph of \(f(x) =x^2\) is provided.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH OF THE PARENT FUNCTION Y EQUALS X SQUARED, WITH THE POINTS (1, 1), (2, 4), AND (3, 9) LABELED." height="291" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/8e96865debed8ceca9104cc834a822c518a3d995" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is \(f(2)\)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; The value of \(f(x)\) when \(x\) is 2, or \(f(2) = 4\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the value of \(f(1)\)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;\(f(1) = 1\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="5"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shannon is running on a flat, rocky trail that eventually rises up a steep mountain. The graph below represents the total distance she covers with respect to time.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/6ac1da9769751f767c0c0f55336f1a0ddce8b602" width="300"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How far does Shannon run in 60 minutes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 miles&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1829">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659143609</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1830">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659143609</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="820">
        <prevpageid>819</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659143776</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662656389</timemodified>
        <title>4.6.7: Lesson Synthesis</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;Keep students in groups of 2. Display the graph and the descriptions of two functions for all students to see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nonlinear graph. time in seconds and distance in feet." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/vSx8HVm7KXW43ji693XujQm5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Function \(b\) gives the vertical distance (or the height) of a bee from the ground as a function of time, \(t\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Function \(d\) gives the distance of a child from where his mom is sitting as a function of time, \(t\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell students that the outputs of both functions are measured in feet and the inputs are both measured in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask partners to choose a function. For that function, they should take turns identifying the following features on the graph and interpreting them in terms of the situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vertical intercept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;horizontal intercept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maximum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minimum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;intervals where the function is increasing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;intervals where the function is decreasing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;intervals where the function is staying constant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solution or solutions to \(b(t)=3.5\) or \(d(t)=3.5\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, discuss questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How can you tell that a point on the graph is a maximum, a minimum, or neither?&amp;rdquo; (Look around it, left and right, to see whether the given point is higher than all the other points, lower than all the others, or neither.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How many intercepts can the graph of a function have?&amp;rdquo; (An unlimited number on the horizontal axis, but only one on the vertical axis.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1831">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659143776</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1832">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659143776</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>
