<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="144" moduleid="189" modulename="lesson" contextid="200">
  <lesson id="144">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Lesson 5.14 Teacher Guide: Which One Changes Faster?</name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>1</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password></password>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>0</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>192</activitylink>
    <mediafile></mediafile>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>1</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1662773178</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="1332">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1333</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1662239248</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1663678802</timemodified>
        <title>5.14.0: Lesson Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt; Lesson Narrative&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson returns to a theme from the beginning of the unit, revisiting the fact that exponential functions grow more quickly, eventually, than linear functions. The first activity compares simple interest (linear growth) with compound interest (exponential growth). Students examine tables and graphs and see that the exponential function quickly overtakes the linear function. In the second activity, the exponential function is deliberately chosen to grow slowly over a large domain, making it less clear whether the exponential function will overtake the linear function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other activities provide an opportunity for students to strategically use technology, whether they make a graph (for which they will need to think carefully about the domain and range) or continue to tabulate explicit values of the two functions (likely with the aid of a calculator for the exponential function). This lesson provides multiple opportunities for students to justify their reasoning and critique the reasoning of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Goals (Teacher Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Use graphs and calculations to show that a quantity that increases exponentially will eventually surpass one that increases linearly. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Use tables, calculations, and graphs to compare growth rates of linear and exponential functions. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Write and use equations of exponential functions written in function notation to compare scenarios. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Targets (Student Facing)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Use tables, calculations, and graphs to compare growth rates of linear and exponential functions and predict how the quantities eventually change. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TEKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation of Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;A3(B) calculate the rate of change of a linear function represented tabularly, graphically, or algebraically in context of mathematical and real-world problems.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;A9(D) graph exponential functions that model growth and decay and identify key features, including \(y\)-intercept and asymptote, in mathematical and real-world problems&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Full coverage: Lesson provides content that covers all parts of this TEKS.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the instructional activities for the lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 5.14.1: Distinguish Linear and Exponential Growth &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 5.14.2: Using Tables to Compare Linear and Exponential Growth Functions
        &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; 5.14.2: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;5.14.2: Additional Resources&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 5.14.3: Compare Linear Functions with Exponential Functions&amp;nbsp;
        &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; 5.14.3: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;5.14.3: Additional Resources&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 5.14.4: Using Function Notation to Compare Linear and Exponential Functions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will also complete a series of problems in 5.14.5: Practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graphing technology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acquire devices that can run Desmos (recommended) or other graphing technology. It is ideal if each student has their own device. (Desmos is available under Math Tools.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be prepared to display a graph for all to see using the embedded Desmos applet or other graphing technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Vocabulary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this lesson, it is important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Familiarize students with the vocabulary words they will see throughout the lesson. Encourage students to look for these words and notice their use and meanings. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Encourage students to use key vocabulary words in “math talk” and their written and oral explanations. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Utilize a word wall. Sample cards are located here: &lt;a href="https://www.doe.virginia.gov/instruction/mathematics/resources/vocab_cards/" target="_blank"&gt;Mathematics Vocabulary Word Wall Cards&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary words that are emphasized in this lesson include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt; constant ratio &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; slope &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;None &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Support for Building Character&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, find ways to encourage and support students to work on cultivating their&lt;strong&gt; grit&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to try during this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/sample-then-specialize/" target="_blank"&gt;Sample, Then Specialize&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/choosing-challenge/" target="_blank"&gt;Choosing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other tips located here in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/playbooks/grit/" target="_blank"&gt;Playbook on Grit&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;from Character Lab.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2993">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662239248</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1333">
        <prevpageid>1332</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1334</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1662239595</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1663680175</timemodified>
        <title>5.14.1: Distinguish Linear and Exponential Growth</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Warm Up (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of this unit, students compared linear and exponential growth. They return to this comparison in this lesson. This warm-up aims to show that, visually, it could be very difficult to distinguish linear and exponential growth for some domain of the function. While any exponential function eventually grows very quickly, it also can look remarkably linear over a portion of the domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/P115Eo7QmdQn2FCCWgFSeE63" alt="Graph of line, origin O. Horizontal axis 0 to 7, by 1’s, labeled x. Vertical from 0 to 150, by 50’s, labeled y. Starts at 0 comma 120, appears to pass through 1 point 5 comma 125 and 7 comma 150.  &amp;nbsp;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Which equation do you think the graph represents? Use the graph to support your reasoning. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; \(y=120+(3.7) \cdot x\) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; \(y=120 \cdot (1.03)^x\) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;All answers are acceptable if backed up by a reasonable explanation. Sample responses:
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;The graph is for \(y=120+3.7x\) because it appears linear. On the graph, when \(x=7\), the value of \(y\) appears to be a little less than 150. When \(x=7\), \(120+(3.7) \cdot 7=145.9\), so the slope of the line could be 3.7.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;The graph is for \(y=120 \cdot (1.03)^x\). Multiplying 100 by 1.03 seven times, or \(100 \cdot (1.03)^7\), gives approximately 147.6, which more or less concurs with what is on the graph.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;It is hard to tell. I tried finding the \(y\)-coordinate values for different values of \(x\) using both equations, and they more or less agree with what is on the graph.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What information might help you decide more easily whether the graph represents a linear or an exponential function? &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt; Sample responses:
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Exact coordinates of points on the graph with whole-number \(x\)-values &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;A larger graphing window showing larger domain values so that the behavior of the function can be more visible &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite students to share the rationales for their decision and their ideas for improving the clarity of the graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help students understand that the graph of a linear function always looks like a line, regardless of the domain where it is plotted. An exponential function, however, can look linear depending on the domain and range. Graphs are very helpful for seeing the general behavior of a function but not always for determining what kind of function is being graphed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider showing students this image of the graph showing a larger domain and range as well as the original window (the red rectangle in the lower left).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/4CZ8KT3bnTSSis83y9iLKGY6" alt="A graph."&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or show a dynamic graph of \(y=120 \cdot (1.03)^x\), starting with a small window where the graph looks linear and then zooming out until the curve is visible&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2994">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662239595</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2995">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662239595</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1334">
        <prevpageid>1333</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1335</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1662246445</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1663681841</timemodified>
        <title>5.14.2: Using Tables to Compare Linear and Exponential Growth Functions</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this activity, students compare linear and exponential growth in a context involving simple and compound interest. The initial balances are chosen so that the two options stay pretty close for small values of time. The intersection of their graphs is far enough from 0 that it is not easily noticed with only a few calculations. The graph for simple interest is linear. The graph for compound interest is exponential, but it is relatively flat for small values of time. As the domain values increase, students may notice that the values of the two options get closer and closer, or they may notice from the graph that the gap between the two graphs gets smaller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for students who make different choices for the investment option because the better option would depend on the length of investment, which is unspecified. As in the case of the genies’ offers in the opening lesson, simple interest is better if the investment term is short, but compound interest becomes increasingly more favorable as time passes. Some students may not recognize this until they graph the two functions in the last question. Identify students who decide to change their earlier choice and can defend the change. Ask them to share later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2. Encourage students to think quietly about the questions before conferring with their partner. Provide access to graphing technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div style="border:1px solid black; padding:5px; background-color:#f2f2f2;"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt; Use this routine to support reading comprehension of this word problem. Use the first read to orient students to the situation. Ask students to describe what the situation is about without using numbers (a family is choosing between investing money with simple or compound interest). Use the second read to identify quantities and relationships. Ask students what can be counted or measured without focusing on the values. Listen for, and amplify, the important quantities that vary in relation to each other in this situation: years of investment and amount of money. After the third read, ask students to brainstorm possible strategies to answer the questions. This helps students connect the language in the word problem and the reasoning needed to solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div style="border:1px solid black; padding:5px; background-color:#f2f2f2;"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Begin the activity with concrete or familiar contexts. Activate background knowledge by asking students to recall what they know about simple interest, compound interest, and savings accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A family has $1,000 to invest and is considering two options: investing in government bonds that offer 2% simple interest, or investing in a savings account at a bank, which charges a $20 fee to open an account and pays 2% compound interest. Both options pay interest annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are two tables showing what they would earn in the first couple of years if they do not invest additional amounts or withdraw any money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="163"&gt;
        &lt;col width="148"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;years of investment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;amount in dollars&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;$1,000&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;$1,020&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;$1,040&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Savings Account&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="163"&gt;
        &lt;col width="148"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;years of investment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;amount in dollars&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;$980&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;$999.60&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;$1,019.59&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Bonds: How does the investment grow with simple interest? &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The investment grows linearly. It increases by $20 every year. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Savings account: How are the amounts $999.60 and $1,019.59 calculated? &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; $999.60 is 1.02 times $980, and $1,019.59 is 1.02 times $999.60. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; For each option, write an equation to represent the relationship between the amount of money and the number of years of investment. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(
        b=1,000+20x\) and \(s=980 \cdot (1.02)^x\) (\(x\) is the years since the investments were made, \(b\) is the value of the bonds, and \(s\) is the value of the savings account, in dollars) .&lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Which investment option should the family choose? Use your equations or calculations to support your answer. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Answers vary. Students may choose bonds or savings account, depending on the assumptions they make about the time frame of the investment. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Use graphing technology to graph the two investment options and show how the money grows in each. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/6evM49c6z5j4boP2sYfUrCrh" alt=" GRAPH OF TWO FUNCTIONS, REPRESENTING TWO INVESTMENT OPTIONS. FUNCTION B IS LINEAR AND REPRESENTS THE BOND INVESTMENT. FUNCTION S IS EXPONENTIAL AND REPRESENTS THE SAVINGS INVESTMENT. THE X-AXIS IS LABELED YEARS OF INVESTMENT AND GOES FROM 0 TO 18. THE Y-AXIS IS LABELED AMOUNT IN DOLLARS AND GOES FROM 0 TO THIRTEEN HUNDRED. STARTING AT X EQUALS 12, THE EXPONENTIAL FUNCTION, S, SURPASSES THE LINEAR FUNCTION, B. 
" width="300" height="431" class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students may have trouble choosing an option without additional information. Ask them to think about what might make sense for their own family or to give circumstances that would justify a choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider surveying the class to see the choices students made. Select students who made different choices to explain their responses, starting with those who opted for the bonds. Display their reasoning and graphs for all to see. If no students consider a time frame beyond 8 or 9 years, ask students which option would be better if the money could be left alone for 20 years. Discuss questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;“How does the fee for the savings account affect the function?” (It reduces the account balance, at the beginning, by $20. In the equation, there is a subtraction of 20.) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;“Where can we see the fees on the graph?” (The vertical intercept of the graph for the savings account is at 980, which is 20 less than 1,000.) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;“When might the bonds be the better investment, if ever?” (When the investment is shorter than a decade because that is when the savings account surpasses it.) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;“When might the savings account be the better investment, if ever?” (When it is left for more than 10 years, after the compounding effects of interest make up for the initial fees.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point out that the exponential function here (the balance of the savings account) has a relatively slow rate of growth. It takes it a relatively long time before it overtakes the linear function, but it eventually does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Video: Using Tables to Compare Linear and Exponential Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the following video to learn more about comparing linear and exponential functions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls="true" crossorigin="anonymous" width="550"&gt;
    &lt;source src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/b2c38efd9bdabdfa5993319c5eb1d37b24042ed2"&gt;
    &lt;track src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/cde8cdd3b62ea446c6bfc2f233327ae95b83d98f" kind="captions" srclang="en_us" label="On" default="true"&gt;https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/b2c38efd9bdabdfa5993319c5eb1d37b24042ed2
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;5.14.2: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="302"&gt;
        &lt;col width="322"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Using a calculator, Joanna made the following table and then made the following conjecture: \(3x\) is always greater than \((1.02)^x\). Is Joanna correct? Explain.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="5"&gt;
                    &lt;tbody&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(x\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\((1.02)^x\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(3x\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;1.02&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;1.0404&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;1.0612&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;9&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;1.0824&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;12&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;1.1041&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="157" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;15&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;/tbody&gt;
                &lt;/table&gt;
                &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Joanna is correct. None of the values in the table for \((1.02)^x\) are greater than the values for \(3x\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: While this is a true statement, the table can be continued forever for both expressions. The answer is Joanna is incorrect. Since \((1.02)^x\) is exponential growth and \(3x\) is linear growth, eventually \((1.02)^x\) will be greater than \(3x\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Joanna is correct. If you graph the points in the table for \((1.02)^x\) and \(3x\), the points for \(3x\) are all above the points for \((1.02)^x\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: While this is a true statement, the graph can be continued forever for both expressions. The answer is Joanna is incorrect. Since \((1.02)^x\) is exponential growth and \(3x\) is linear growth, eventually \((1.02)^x\) will be greater than \(3x\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Joanna is incorrect. Since \((1.02)^x\) is exponential growth and \(3x\) is linear growth, eventually \((1.02)^x\) will be greater than \(3x\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;That’s correct! Check yourself: If you graph both expressions and zoom out, you can see that after \(x=351\), \((1.02)^x\) is greater than \(3x\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Joanna is incorrect. If you continue the table to \(x=300\), \((1.02)^x\) is greater than \(3x\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: While you do need to continue the table to see where \((1.02)^x\) is greater, it’s not at \(x=300\). The answer is Joanna is incorrect. Since \((1.02)^x\) is exponential growth and \(3x\) is linear growth, eventually \((1.02)^x\) will be greater than \(3x\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5.14.2: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Comparing Linear and Exponential Growth Using Tables&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classify each of the following tables as linear, exponential growth, or exponential decay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table A&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="59"&gt;
        &lt;col width="56"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(x\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(f(x)\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(\frac12\)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(\frac14\)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(\frac18\)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(\frac{1}{16}\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(\frac{1}{32}\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table B&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="59"&gt;
        &lt;col width="56"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(x\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(f(x)\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1.4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2.5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3.6&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4.7&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5.8&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table C&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="59"&gt;
        &lt;col width="56"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(x\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(f(x)\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;30&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;60&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;120&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;240&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;480&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In each situation, the inputs or \(x\)-values are increasing by 1 each time. These can also be called consecutive terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have consecutive terms, then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; If the difference between their corresponding outputs or \(y\)-values is always the same constant, then the input-output pairs in the table can be modeled by a linear function. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; If the quotient between their corresponding outputs or \(y\)-values is always the same constant, then the input-output pairs in the table can be modeled by an exponential function. A growth rate greater than one means that it is exponential growth, and a growth rate between zero and one means that it is exponential decay. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible for a table to be a set of values that is not any of these relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this information you can see that in Table A, \(\frac{\frac{1}{4}}{ \frac{1}{2}}=\frac12\). This holds true for the quotient of every other set of consecutive terms, too. Since the quotient is always the same, Table A represents an exponential function. Since the growth rate is \(\frac12\), or between zero and one, Table A represents exponential decay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Table B, the quotient of consecutive terms is not the same, but there is a common difference. The difference between the first two terms is \(2.5 -1.4=1.1\). This holds true for each of the other pairs of consecutive terms, so Table B represents a linear relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Table C, the quotient of consecutive terms is \(\frac{60}{30}=2\). This relationship holds true for all of the pairs of consecutive terms, which means this table represents an exponential relationship. Since the growth factor is greater than one, Table C represents exponential growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Try It: Comparing Linear and Exponential Growth Using Tables&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which of the following tables represents exponential growth? Explain your reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table A&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="68"&gt;
        &lt;col width="55"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(x\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(f(x)\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;14&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;20&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table B&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="68"&gt;
        &lt;col width="55"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(x\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(f(x)\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;432&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;144&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;48&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;16&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table C&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="68"&gt;
        &lt;col width="55"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(x\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(f(x)\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;16&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;64&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;256&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="68"&gt;
        &lt;col width="55"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(x\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(f(x)\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;9&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;Solution &lt;/strong&gt;button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Here is how to determine which table is exponential growth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking for exponential growth, remember that each \(y\)-value should be greater than the previous one. By first checking for growth, you can eliminate Table B and Table D. In Table B, each term is less than the first one, so it is not exponential growth. In Table D, the values increase and decrease, so it is not exponential growth, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, check for connections between consecutive terms. In Table A, \(2+6= 8\) and \(2 \cdot 4=8\). Since there seems to be the possibility of either a linear relationship or exponential growth, you need to check the next set of terms. Since \(8 \cdot 4 \neq 14\) and \(8+6 =14\), the relationship in Table A is linear, not exponential.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means the answer should be Table C, but we should always check to confirm. If we check consecutive terms in Table C for a growth factor, we get the following: \(\frac {16}{4}=4\), \(\frac{64}{16}=4\), and \(\frac{256}{64}=4\). This proves that the growth factor is 4 and Table C represents exponential growth.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2996">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662246445</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2997">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662246445</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1335">
        <prevpageid>1334</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1336</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1662246804</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1663706847</timemodified>
        <title>5.14.3: Compare Linear Functions with Exponential Functions</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This activity prompts students to again compare a linear function with an exponential one, but this time without a context, and the exponential function grows much more slowly over a long period of time. Even if students predict that the exponential function will grow more quickly because it is exponential, they still need to decide which one reaches 2,000 first. To do that, students may try:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; continuing the table of values with increasingly larger values.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; using graphing technology.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; finding when \(f(x)=2,000\) and substituting this value \((x=1,000)\) into \(g(x)\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making graphing and spreadsheet technology available gives students an opportunity to choose appropriate tools strategically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Present the two equations that define two functions \(f\)&amp;nbsp;and \(g\): \(f(x)=2x\) and \(g(x)=(1.01)^x\). Give students a moment to share what they notice and wonder about the functions. Ask questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;“What is happening in the first function? What about in the second function?”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;“Which function do you think will reach a value of 2,000 first?”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt; Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div style="border:1px solid black; padding:5px; background-color:#f2f2f2;"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ask students to prepare a visual display that shows their mathematical thinking in response to the question, “Which function do you think will reach a value of 2,000 first?” Invite previously identified students to share their representations. In groups of 2, ask students to compare their strategies and discuss how the strategies are the same or different. Consider using the prompt: “Which strategy do you believe is the most efficient in determining a solution?” Listen for and amplify observations of advantages and disadvantages to different approaches, such as using a particular approach for a certain time interval. This will help students connect different approaches and determine the effectiveness of each one through partner and whole-class discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h5&gt; Support for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div style="border:1px solid black; padding:5px; background-color:#f2f2f2;"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Provide access to tools and assistive technologies, such as a graphing calculator or graphing software. Some students may benefit from a checklist or list of steps to be able to use the calculator or software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Consider the functions \(f(x)=2x\) and \(g(x)=(1.01)^x\).&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Complete the table of values for the functions \(f\) and \(g\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="66" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(x\) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="64" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(f(x)\) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="64" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(g(x)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="66" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="64" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="64" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="66" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;10 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="64" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="64" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="66" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;50 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="64" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="64" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="66" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;100&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="64" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="64" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="66" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;500&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="64" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="64" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="97" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(x\) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="98" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(f(x)\) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="98" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(g(x)\) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="97" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="98" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="98" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1.01 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="97" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;10&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="98" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;20&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="98" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;~1.10 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="97" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;50&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="98" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;100&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="98" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;~1.645 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="97" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;100&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="98" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;200&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="98" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;~2.7 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="97" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;500&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="98" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1,000&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="98" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;~144.8 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Based on the table of values, which function do you think grows faster? Explain your reasoning. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Sample response:&amp;nbsp;\(f\)&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;is growing faster for the values of&amp;nbsp;\(x\)&amp;nbsp;in the table, but as&amp;nbsp;\(x\)&amp;nbsp;increases, \(g\) starts to grow faster. So as&amp;nbsp;\(x\)&amp;nbsp;increases, \(g\) may eventually grow faster than \(f\).
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Which function do you think will reach a value of 2,000 first? Show your reasoning. If you get stuck, consider increasing \(x\) by 100 a few times and record the function values in the table. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; When \(x\) is 600, \(f(600)=1,200\) and \(g(600) \approx 392\), so&amp;nbsp;\(f\) takes a larger value. When&amp;nbsp;\(x\)&amp;nbsp;is 700, \(f(700)=1,400\) and \(g(700) \approx 1,059\), so \(f\) still takes a larger value. But when&amp;nbsp;\(x\)&amp;nbsp;is 800, \(f(800)=1,600\) and \(g(800) \approx 2,865\), so \(g\) takes a larger value.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Extension&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Are you ready for more?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the functions \(g(x)=x^5\) and \(f(x)=5^x\). While it is true that \(f(7)&amp;gt;g(7)\), for example, it is hard to check this using mental math. Find a value of \(x\) for which properties of exponents allow you to conclude that \(f(x)&amp;gt;g(x)\) without a calculator.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Answers vary. One example is \(x=25\). We have \(f(25)=5^{25}\), whereas \(g(25)=25^5=(5^2)^5=5^{10}\), which is certainly smaller than \(5^{25}\).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select students who used contrasting approaches to share. The exponential function \(g\)&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;grows sufficiently slowly that it looks like it will not catch up with or ever overtake the linear function \(f\). This is true when using a table of values as well as when using a graph. Invite students who used contrasting methods to share, in the order shown in the Activity Narrative.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emphasize that the table needs to be continued for a long time to identify when the values of \(g\) become greater than those of \(f\). Similarly, the window of the graph needs to be chosen carefully. A very efficient method is to identify that \(f(1,000)=2,000\) and then evaluate \(g(1,000)\). Since \(g(1,000)\) is much greater than 2,000, \(g\) reaches 2,000 first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If not already illustrated by students who used graphing, show this dynamic sketch and zoom out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though for quite a while it doesn’t seem like the values of \(g\)&amp;nbsp;would ever catch up with those of&amp;nbsp;\(f\)&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; if the growth is allowed to take place long enough, exponential eventually surpasses linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt; 5.14.3: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="302"&gt;
        &lt;col width="322"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Terence looked down the second column of the table below and noticed that \(\frac{3}{1}=\frac{9}{3}=\frac{27}{9}=\frac{81}{27}\). Because of his observation, he claimed that the input-output pairs in this table could be modeled with an exponential function. Explain why Terence is correct or incorrect.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="5"&gt;
                    &lt;tbody&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="126" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;\(x\)&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="126" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;\(T(x)\)&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="126" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="126" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="126" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="126" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="126" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="126" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;9&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="126" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;13&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="126" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;27&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="126" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;40&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="126" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;81&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;/tbody&gt;
                &lt;/table&gt;
                &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Terence is correct. Terms in a table that are connected by a factor are exponential.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: Terms in an exponential table are connected by a factor, but the terms are not consecutive. If you look at this table, the&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;\(x\)-values are not increasing by 1. The answer is Terence is incorrect. This table represents a linear relationship since the ratio of change of each row is consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Terence is correct. This table can be modeled by \(y=1(3)^x\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This table would be represented by this equation if the terms were consecutive. The \(x\)&lt;i&gt;-&lt;/i&gt;values are not increasing by 1 each time. The answer is Terence is incorrect. This table represents a linear relationship since the ratio of change of each row is consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Terence is incorrect. This table represents points that do not have an exponential or linear relationship because the \(x\) and \(y\)&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; change by different amounts.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: The table represents a linear relationship, not an exponential relationship. The answer is Terence is incorrect. This table represents a linear relationship since the ratio of change of each row is consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Terence is incorrect. This table represents a linear relationship since the ratio of change of each row is consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;That’s correct! Check yourself: Since the \(x\)-values are not increasing by 1 each time, you need to check the ratio of the rate of change. Since \(\frac{2}{1}=\frac{6}{3}=\frac{18}{9}=\frac{54}{27}\), this is a linear relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5.14.3: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Determining and Comparing Linear and Exponential Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Smith has an apple orchard. He hires his daughter, Lucy, to pick apples and offers her two payment options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Option A: $1.50 per bushel of apples picked&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Option B: 1 cent for coming to work, 3 cents picking one bushel, 9 cents for picking two bushels, 27 cents for picking three bushels, and so on, with the amount of money tripling for each additional bushel picked&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Which option is linear, and which option is exponential? How do you know? &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Create a table to model each scenario. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; If she picks 6 bushels, which option is better? &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; If she picks 12 bushels, which option is better? &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; How many bushels does she need to pick for Option B to be better than Option A? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s first think about linear and exponential functions in general. Let’s also consider Option A and B when \(x\) represents the bushels of apples picked and \(f(x)\) represents the total amount she earns based on \(x\) bushels of apples.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Since Option A is $1.50 per bushel picked, it is linear. For Option B, the amount of money is tripling for each bushel picked, so it is exponential. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="108" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="228" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linear Model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="222" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exponential Model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="108" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Form&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="228" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(f(x)=ax+b\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="222" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(f(x)=a(b)^x\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="108" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meaning of Parameters&amp;nbsp;\(a\)&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;\(b\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="228" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(a\)&amp;nbsp;is the slope of the line or the constant rate of change; \(b\) is the \(y\)-intercept or the \(f(x)\) value at \(x=0\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="222" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(a\) is the \(y\)-intercept or the \(f(x)\) value when \(x=0\); \(b\) is the base or the constant quotient of change. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="108" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="228" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(f(x)=1.50x\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="222" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(f(x)=.01(3)^x\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="108" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rule for Finding \(f(x+1)\) from \(f(x)\)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="228" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Starting at \((0,0)\), to find \(f(x+1)\), add 1.5 to \(f(x)\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="222" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Starting at \((0,0.1)\), to find \(f(x+1)\), multiply \(f(x)\) by 3. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="108" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="228" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="5"&gt;
                    &lt;tbody&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;\(x\)&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;\(f(x)\)&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;1.50&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;3.00&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;4.50&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;/tbody&gt;
                &lt;/table&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="222" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="5"&gt;
                    &lt;tbody&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;\(x\)&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;\(f(x)\)&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;0.01&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;0.03&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;0.09&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="146" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;0.27&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;/tbody&gt;
                &lt;/table&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; To create the table for Option A, added $1.50 to each consecutive term.&amp;nbsp; To create the table for Option B, multiply each term by 3 to get the next term. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Option A table &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="71"&gt;
        &lt;col width="91"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of bushels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amount of money earned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1.50&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3.00&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4.50&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;6.00&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;7.50&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;9.00&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Option B table&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="71"&gt;
        &lt;col width="91"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of bushels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amount of money earned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0.03&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0.09&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0.27&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0.81&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2.43&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;7.29&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; To determine which scenario is better when she picks 6 bushels, you can look at the values in your table, or you can write the equation modeling each scenario and substitute in 6 for \(x\). For 6 bushels, Option A is better at $9.00. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; To determine which scenario is better when she picks 12 bushels, you can extend the table or use the graph or equation. Option A is $18.00 for 12 bushels, and Option B is $5,314.41 for 12 bushels, so Option B is better. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="5"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; To determine where Option B becomes the better option, you can extend the table, or you can graph the functions and find the \(x\)-value where Option B surpasses Option A. You can also use problems 3 and 4 to help you. The number of bushels is more than 6 but less than 12. Option B is better if you are going to pick 7 or more bushels of apples. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Determining and Comparing Linear and Exponential Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jayden has a dog-walking business. He has two plans. Plan 1 includes walking a dog once a day for a rate of $5 per day. Plan 2 also includes one walk a day but charges 1 cent for 1 day, 2 cents for 2 days, 4 cents for 3 days, and 8 cents for 4 days, and it continues to double for each additional day. Mrs. Maroney needs Jayden to walk her dog every day for two weeks. Which plan should she choose? Show the work to justify your answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt; Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to determine which of Jayden’s plans Mrs. Maroney should choose:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plan 1 is a linear plan since it’s $5 per day. Plan 2 is doubling each day, so it is an exponential plan. Every other example has shown us that the exponential plan is going to be greater eventually. Since Mrs. Maroney needs Jayden for 2 weeks, or 14 days, we need to determine when Plan 2 becomes greater than Plan 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plan 1 for 14 days would be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(5+5+5+5+5+5+5+5+5+5+5+5+5+5 = 5 \cdot 14 = $70\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plan 2 for 14 days would be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(.01 \cdot 2 \cdot 2 \cdot 2 \cdot 2 \cdot 2 \cdot 2 \cdot 2 \cdot 2 \cdot 2 \cdot 2 \cdot 2 \cdot 2 \cdot 2 = .01(2)^{14} =$163.84\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plan 1 would be better for Mrs. Maroney.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2998">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662246804</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2999">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662246804</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1336">
        <prevpageid>1335</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1337</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1662249306</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1663682095</timemodified>
        <title>5.14.4: Using Function Notation to Compare Linear and Exponential Functions</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Cool Down (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function \(f\) is given by \(f(x)=10x+3\), and the function \(g\) is given by \(g(x)=2^x\). For each question, show your reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Which function reaches 50 first? &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(f(5)=53\) and \(g(5)=32\), so \(f\) reaches 50 first. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Which function reaches 100 first? &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;

        \(f(7)=73\) and \(g(7)=128\), so \(g\) reaches 100 first.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Response to Student Thinking&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Points to emphasize&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a few minutes in the next lesson to discuss a few approaches to estimate values to compare the two functions.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3000">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662249306</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3001">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662249306</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1337">
        <prevpageid>1336</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1338</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1662249639</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1663707057</timemodified>
        <title>5.14.5: Practice</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Students will complete the following questions to practice the skills they have learned in this lesson.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Functions \(a, b, c, d, e\), and \(f\) are given below. Which functions are linear?
        &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                \(a(x)=3x\)
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                \(b(x)=3^x\)
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                \(c(x)=x^3\)
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                \(d(x)=9+3x\)
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                \(e(x)=9 \cdot 3^x\)
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;\(
                f(x)=9 \cdot 3x\)


            &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;a. \(a(x)=3x\), d. \(d(x)=9+3x\), f. \(f(x)=9⋅3x\)
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Functions \(a, b, c, d, e\), and \(f\) are given below. Which functions are exponential?
        &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;\(a(x)=3x\)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; \(b(x)=3^x\) &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; \(c(x)=x^3\) &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; \(d(x)=9+3x\) &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; \(e(x)=9 \cdot 3^x\) &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;\(
                f(x)=9 \cdot 3x\) &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;b.&amp;nbsp;\(b(x)=3^x\), e. \(e(x)=9 \cdot 3^x\)
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Here are 4 equations defining 4 different functions, \(a, b, c\), and \(d\). List them in order of increasing rate of change. That is, start with the one that grows the slowest and end with the one that grows the quickest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;\(a(x)=5x+3\)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;\(b(x)=3x+5\)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;\(c(x)=x+4\)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;\(d(x)=1+4x\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Option 1: \(a(x)\), \(b(x)\), \(c(x)\), \(d(x)\)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Option 2: \(d(x)\), \(c(x)\), \(b(x)\), \(a(x)\)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Option 3: \(a(x)\),\(d(x)\), \(b(x)\), \(a(x)\)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Option 4: \(c(x)\), \(b(x)\), \(d(x)\), \(a(x)\)
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;Option 4: \(c(x)\), \(b(x)\), \(d(x)\), \(a(x)\)
&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Use the given information for problems 4–6. Technology is required. Function \(f\) is defined by \(f(x)=3x+5\), and function \(g\) is defined by \(g(x)=(1.1)^x\).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="56"&gt;
        &lt;col width="94"&gt;
        &lt;col width="92"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td align="center"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(x\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td align="center"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt; \(f(x)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td align="center"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;\(g(x)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td align="center"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td align="center"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td align="center"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;10&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td align="center"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;20&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Which values will complete the table for \(f(x)\)?
        &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;8, 11, 14, 17
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                8, 20, 35, 65
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                3, 15, 30, 60
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                8, 15, 30, 60
            &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;


    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; b. 8, 20, 35, 65
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;ol start="5"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Which of the following sets of values will complete the table for \(g(x)\)? \(g(x)=(1.1)^x\)
        &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                8, 20, 35, 65
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;1.1, 5.5, 10.10, 20.20
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                1.1, 1.6, 2.59, 6.73
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                1.1, 1.21, 1.33, 1.46
            &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; c. 1.1, 1.6, 2.59, 6.73
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol start="6"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Which function is linear, and which function is exponential?
      &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;________ is a linear function.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;________ is an exponential function.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp; a. \(f(x)\) is a linear function; b. \(g(x)\) is an exponential function.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;ol start="7"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Functions \(m\) and \(n\)&amp;nbsp;are given by \(m(x)=(1.05)^x\) and \(n(x)=\frac{5}{8}x\). As&amp;nbsp;\(x\)&amp;nbsp;increases from 0, &amp;nbsp;DROPDOWN [\(m(x)\), \(n(x)\), neither] reaches 30 first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;\(n(x)\)
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol start="8"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Functions \(m\) and \(n\) are given by \(m(x)=(1.05)^x\) and \(n(x)=\frac{5}{8}x\). As \(x\)&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;increases from 0, DROPDOWN [\(m(x)\), \(n(x)\), neither] reaches 100 first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(m(x)\)
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;ol start="9"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The functions \(f\) and \(g\) are defined by \(f(x)=8x+33\) and \(g(x)=2 \cdot(1.2)^x\). Which function eventually grows faster, \(f\) or \(g\)? Explain how you know.
        &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                \(f(x)\) grows faster because 8 is greater than 1.2.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                \(f(x)\) grows faster because 33 is greater than 2.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                \(g(x)\) grows faster because it is a linear function.
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                \(g(x)\) grows faster because it is an exponential function.
            &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;d. \(g(x)\) grows faster because it is an exponential function.
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol start="10"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A line segment of length \(l\)&amp;nbsp;is scaled by a factor of 1.5 to produce a segment with length \(m\). The new segment is then scaled by a factor of 1.5 to give a segment of length \(n\).&lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        What scale factor takes the segment of length \(l\)&amp;nbsp;to the segment of length \(n\)?&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;2.25
&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3002">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662249639</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3003">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662249639</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1338">
        <prevpageid>1337</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1662332934</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1663685715</timemodified>
        <title>5.14.6: Lesson Synthesis </title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;In this course, students have looked at many examples of exponential functions and linear functions. They have studied their graphs, equations, and tables of values. Help students review the features and behaviors of the two kinds of functions by presenting these pairs of functions (all of which represent growth):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two linear functions&amp;nbsp;\(f\)&amp;nbsp;and&lt;i&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;\(g\), for example: \(f(x)=\frac{1}{2}x+100\) and \(g(x)=2x\) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two exponential functions \(p\) and&amp;nbsp;\(q\), for example: \(p(x)=100 \cdot (1.5)^x\) and \(q(x)=5 \cdot2^x\) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A linear function&amp;nbsp;\(m\)&amp;nbsp;and an exponential function &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;\(n\), for example: \(m(x)=300x+1,000\) and \(n(x)=(0.4) \cdot 2^x\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each pair for functions, ask students these questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“How can we tell which one grows more quickly?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Will the one that started out with the lower initial value catch up with the function that starts with a higher initial value?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“What are some ways to check if one function will overtake another?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reiterate that even though an exponential function might seem to be growing too slowly to catch up to a linear function with large numbers for its \(y\)-intercept and slope, at some value of&amp;nbsp;\(x\)&amp;nbsp;down the line, the exponential function will catch up with the linear function. Remind students how this was the case in the genie activity early in the unit. (The starting value for the linear function was 100,000 times that of the exponential function, and the slope of the linear function was 2,000, while the growth factor of the exponential function was 2. But within 3 weeks, the exponential function surpassed the linear.)&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3004">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662332934</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3005">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662332934</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>