<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="6" moduleid="43" modulename="page" contextid="54">
  <page id="6">
    <name>Unit 1 Wrap Up</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, you learned that Arthur Noriega, Miami City Manager, has to consider constraints when planning a budget for various departments. He has to examine the relationships among quantities. He can use expressions, equations, and inequalities to represent the constraints for each department &amp;mdash; such as the number of workers needed, the salaries of the employees, or the cost of supplies &amp;mdash; to make sure he stays in budget. He can use graphs of equations to make sense of constraints and identify values that satisfy them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, in this unit, you learned how to use expressions, equations, and inequalities to represent constraints on quantities. You also used graphs of equations to make sense of constraints and identify values to solve them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also learned to recognize moves that transform one equation into an equivalent equation. You used these moves to manipulate and solve equations. You also used these moves to write equations in point-slope form, standard form, and point-slope form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, you learned how the form and parts of a linear equation in two variables are related to the features of its graph. You identified lines that are parallel and perpendicular using the relationship between slopes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;

 
Building Character: Social Intelligence 

&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, you learned that social intelligence is important for developing relationships that are mutually beneficial and supportive. You learned that you can encourage social intelligence in others by waiting your turn before speaking, acknowledging other&amp;rsquo;s points of view, encouraging teamwork and loyalty over hierarchy and competition, and by creating opportunities for everyone to feel equal.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:2:{s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";s:17:"printlastmodified";s:1:"1";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>27</revision>
    <timemodified>1656962225</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>
