<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="105" moduleid="141" modulename="lesson" contextid="152">
  <lesson id="105">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Lesson 4.13 Teacher Guide: Sequences</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>1</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password/>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>0</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>144</activitylink>
    <mediafile/>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>1</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1660691176</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="959">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>960</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659663585</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662592774</timemodified>
        <title>4.13.0: Lesson Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Narrative&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this lesson is for students to work with sequences and describe them recursively in an informal way. A sequence is defined here as a list of numbers, while a term (of a sequence) is one of the numbers in the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the Tower of Hanoi puzzle, students first make sense of the rules of the puzzle before playing with different numbers of discs to generate a sequence representing the minimum number of moves needed to complete the puzzle. Solving the puzzles provides students opportunities to express regularity in repeated reasoning when they informally state a recursive rule for generating the next term in a sequence from the previous term. If students try to convince each other that they have found the minimum number of moves to solve the puzzle, they are constructing mathematical arguments and critiquing the reasoning of others. While geometric and arithmetic sequences are a focus of the unit, the sequence generated from the Tower of Hanoi is neither. This was a deliberate choice to promote student discussion since the pattern to generate the sequence is one students are less likely to guess correctly than a more straightforward linear or exponential pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second activity is optional and provides additional practice with another context if needed, or as an alternative activity if students have familiarity with the Tower of Hanoi puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Learning Goals (Teacher Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Comprehend the term &amp;ldquo;sequence&amp;rdquo; (in written and spoken language) as a list of numbers. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Describe (orally) a recursive rule for identifying the next term of a simple sequence. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Generate a sequence that arises from a mathematical context. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Targets (Student Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Give examples of a sequence &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Explain the meaning of the term &amp;ldquo;sequence.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Explain the meaning of the term &amp;ldquo;term,&amp;rdquo; as it is used in a mathematical sequence. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="312"&gt;
&lt;col width="312"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TEKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation of Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;A12(C) identify terms of arithmetic and geometric sequences when the sequences are given in function form using recursive processes;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foundational: Lesson provides foundational content necessary for students to be able to perform this TEKS in later lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the instructional activities for the lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.13.1: Describe the Pattern &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.13.2: What Is a Sequence? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.13.2: Self Check &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.13.2: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.13.3: The Connection Between Sequences and Terms &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.13.3: Self Check &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.13.3: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.13.4: Rules for a Sequence &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will also complete a series of problems in the 4.13.5: Practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Internet-enabled device for applet activity &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; If not using the digital applet, each student could use a quarter, nickel, penny, and dime, and a piece of paper with 3 circles drawn on it. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students should manipulate either physical or digital objects to experiment with the Tower of Hanoi puzzle. For physical, each group could use a quarter, nickel, penny, and dime, and a piece of paper with 3 circles drawn on it. For students using the digital version of the materials, acquire devices that can run the digital applet. It is ideal if each student has their own device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are doing the checker jumping puzzle, each group needs at least 3 tokens each of 2 different colors. These could be actual checkers, counting chips, pennies and nickels, or any other appropriate tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Vocabulary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this lesson, it is important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Familiarize students with the vocabulary words they will see throughout the lesson. Encourage students to look for these words and notice their use and meanings. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Encourage students to use key vocabulary words in &amp;ldquo;math talk&amp;rdquo; and their written and oral explanations. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Utilize a word wall. Sample cards are located here: &lt;a href="https://www.doe.virginia.gov/instruction/mathematics/resources/vocab_cards/" target="_blank"&gt;Mathematics Vocabulary Word Wall Cards&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary words that are emphasized in this lesson include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; sequence &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; term (of a sequence) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Support for Building Character&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, find ways to encourage and support students to work on cultivating their &lt;strong&gt;creativity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to try during this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/sample-then-specialize/" target="_blank"&gt;Sample, Then Specialize&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/work-smarter-sooner/" target="_blank"&gt;Work Smarter, Sooner&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other tips located here in the &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/playbooks/creativity" target="_blank"&gt;Playbook on Creativity&lt;/a&gt; from Character Lab.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2151">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659663585</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="960">
        <prevpageid>959</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>961</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659663742</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662592797</timemodified>
        <title>4.13.1: Describe the Pattern</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Warm Up (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this task is for students to generate a list of numbers based on a rule. Since this activity is also meant to help set the expectation that students are responsible for creating mathematical objects, like lists of numbers, and making sense of activities, there is no need to identify any specific vocabulary, such as &amp;ldquo;sequence,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;term,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;arithmetic,&amp;rdquo; at this time. In the next activity, students will generate a list of numbers from a puzzle and then describe the pattern in the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As students are working, monitor for students who have generated a successful sequence and invite them to share during the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2. Tell students there are many possible answers. After brief quiet work time, ask students to compare their responses to their partner&amp;rsquo;s and decide whether they are both correct, even if they are different. Follow with a whole-class discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avoid demonstrating a possible sequence of 5 numbers for the whole class first to set up the expectation that students are responsible for making sense of the activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a rule for making a list of numbers: &lt;em&gt;Each number is 1 less than twice the previous number.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pick a number to start with. Then follow the rule to build a list of 5 numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample responses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 2, 3, 5, 9, 17 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 5, 9, 17, 33, 65 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 1, 1, 1, 1, 1 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a student has trouble getting started, ask them to first pick a number. Once they&amp;rsquo;ve picked a number, ask what the next number would be, according to the rule. Then invite them to continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some students may interpret &amp;ldquo;1 less than twice a number&amp;rdquo; as \(1-2x\) (where \(x\) is the number). Ask these students questions like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s 1 less than 5?&amp;rdquo; (4) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s 1 less than 5 times 2?&amp;rdquo; (9) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s 1 less than 100?&amp;rdquo; (99) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s 1 less than 100 times 2?&amp;rdquo; (199) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write some of these statements on the board along with their translation into mathematical expressions. For example, write &amp;ldquo;1 less than 5 times 2&amp;rdquo; next to \(5\cdot2-1\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite previously identified students to present their lists. Ask the other students to verify their calculations.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2152">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659663742</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2153">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659663742</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="961">
        <prevpageid>960</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>962</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659664359</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662695219</timemodified>
        <title>4.13.2: What Is a Sequence?</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (30 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this activity is to define the word &amp;ldquo;sequence.&amp;rdquo; In this activity, students experiment with solving the Tower of Hanoi puzzle for different numbers of starting discs. They look for a pattern in the sequence generated by listing the number of moves needed to solve the puzzle for different numbers of discs and then describe the pattern informally. The other purpose of this activity is to establish that students are expected to try things out, look for patterns, explain their thinking, justify their responses, and listen respectfully to their classmates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This activity works best when each group has access to manipulatives or devices that can run the GeoGebra applet because students will benefit from seeing the relationship in a dynamic way. If students don&amp;rsquo;t have individual access, projecting the applet during the launch would be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitor for students writing clear explanations for Jada&amp;rsquo;s reasoning and for the number of moves needed for 5 discs to share during the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students should manipulate either physical or digital objects to experiment with the Tower of Hanoi puzzle. For physical, each group could use a quarter, nickel, penny, and dime, and a piece of paper with 3 circles drawn on it. For students using the digital version of the materials, acquire devices that can run the digital applet. It is ideal if each student has their own device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2. Set up either a physical puzzle with 2 discs or the digital version with 2 discs and display a table for all to see that looks like this throughout the discussion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="198"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;number of discs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center" valign="top" width="42"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center" valign="top" width="36"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center" valign="top" width="36"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center" valign="top" width="36"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center" valign="top" width="36"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center" valign="top" width="36"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center" valign="top" width="36"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="198"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;number of moves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="42"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="36"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="36"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="36"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="36"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="36"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="36"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students to read the two rules of the puzzle. Next, invite students to name what moves are possible (move the top small disc to the middle peg) and which are not allowed (move both discs at once to the middle peg). Complete the puzzle for two discs, asking students to suggest moves to complete the puzzle in the smallest number of moves (3). Fill in the table for the number of moves needed for 2 discs. Tell students that now it is their turn to figure out the number of moves needed for different numbers of discs. Distribute objects with which to experiment with the puzzle. Alternatively, help students access the digital applet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students to read the rules to the puzzle and then give them time to solve the puzzle with 2 discs. Before students start working, remind them they need to keep track of the number of moves needed for each new number of discs, and that they need to try to find the smallest number of moves. Encourage groups to check in with those around them to see if anyone found a solution with fewer moves. If necessary, before students begin work on the rest of the questions, select a student to demonstrate why it takes 3 moves to solve the puzzle with 2 discs as a check that everyone understands the rules of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use this routine to give students a structured opportunity to revise and refine their explanations for how Jada used the solution for 3 discs to help her solve the puzzle for 4 discs. As students share their responses with their partner, listeners should press for details and clarity as appropriate based on what each speaker produces. Provide students with prompts for feedback that will help individuals strengthen their ideas and clarify their language. For example, &amp;ldquo;What pattern did Jada notice?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;How do you know your answer is the smallest number of moves?&amp;rdquo; Students can borrow ideas and language from each partner to strengthen their final product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; If the applet is not available, provide physical manipulatives to represent the discs and each tower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Student-Facing Statement &lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;iframe height="483px" scrolling="no" src="https://www.geogebra.org/material/iframe/id/nB8CUK3Y/width/678/height/483/border/888888/sfsb/true/smb/false/stb/false/stbh/false/ai/false/asb/false/sri/true/rc/false/ld/false/sdz/false/ctl/false" title="F5.L.A1 Towering Sequence (Hanoi)" width="678px"&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Tower of Hanoi puzzle, a set of discs sits on a peg, while there are 2 other empty pegs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A move in the Tower of Hanoi puzzle involves taking a disc and moving it to another peg. There are two rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Only move 1 disc at a time. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Never put a larger disc on top of a smaller one. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You complete the puzzle by building the complete tower on a different peg from the starting peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What is the smallest number of moves in which you are able to complete the puzzle with 3 discs? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What is the smallest number of moves in which you are able to complete the puzzle with 4 discs? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Jada says she used the solution for 3 discs to help her solve the puzzle for 4 discs. Describe how this might happen. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How many moves do you think it will take to complete a puzzle with 5 discs? Explain. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How many moves do you think it will take to complete a puzzle with 7 discs? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this activity, you have started to find a sequence of terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write these definitions in your math notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A sequence is a list of numbers, possibly going on forever, such as all the odd positive integers arranged in order: 1, 3, 5, 7, . . . .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The term (of a sequence) is one of the numbers in a sequence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7 moves &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 15 moves &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Sample response: Jada moved the tower of discs 1&amp;ndash;3, then moved disc 4, and then moved the remaining discs 1&amp;ndash;3 onto it. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 31 moves. Sample response: Double the previous answer, and then add 1. The number of moves is 31 because \(2\cdot15+1=31\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 127 moves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students may incorrectly interpret the rules or presume there is no better solution once they find one solution that works. Encourage groups to regularly switch who is in charge of moving the discs and to check with other groups around them once they think they have found a solution with the smallest number of moves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this discussion is to define sequence and term (of a sequence). This is also an opportunity to establish classroom norms regarding the flow of an activity from working time to a synthesis of the main ideas, listening to other students&amp;rsquo; explanations, and formally naming important mathematical concepts or objects after students have had an opportunity to interact with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin the discussion by asking students, &amp;ldquo;How many moves does it take to complete the puzzle with 1 disc?&amp;rdquo; (Just 1, since the puzzle specifies the discs have to end up on a different peg.) Select students to share the smallest number of moves they found for 3 and 4 discs. Each time, ask whether anyone in the class solved it with fewer moves. If no one finds the minimal solution, ask students to keep looking if time allows, or share the minimum number of moves and challenge them to do it, or demonstrate the minimal solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite previously identified students to share their explanation for Jada&amp;rsquo;s strategy and the number of moves needed to complete a puzzle with 5 discs. The bottom row of the table should now have the numbers 1, 3, 7, 15, and 31 filled in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encourage groups to check in with those around them to see if anyone found a solution with fewer moves. If necessary, before students begin work on the rest of the questions, select a student to demonstrate why it takes 3 moves to solve the puzzle with 2 discs as a check that everyone understands the rules of the game. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a display of important terms and vocabulary. Invite students to suggest language or diagrams to include that will support their understanding of &amp;ldquo;term&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sequence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.13.2: Self Check&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="302"&gt;
&lt;col width="322"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table below shows the number of chips in a game and the number of moves that can be made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of chips&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of possible moves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many moves would be possible with 7 chips?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This is the number of possible moves for 5 chips. The answer is 15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This is twice the number of chips. The rule is twice the number of chips plus 1. The answer is 15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: As the number of chips increases by 1, the number of moves increases by 2. When the table reaches 5 chips, there will be 15 possible moves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This is the number of possible moves for 6 chips. The answer is 15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.13.2: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Using a Table to Find the Pattern&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it is helpful to keep a table to find the pattern needed to answer a question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Tower of Hanoi game, enter the number of discs used and the smallest number of moves to solve the puzzle in a table like the one below. Use the answers from the activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of discs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of moves to solve puzzle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;31&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;127&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pattern was to double the previous answer and then add 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this pattern, complete the table for 6 discs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(2(31)+1=63\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then use this rule to find how many moves are needed to complete the puzzle with 8 discs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were 127 moves for 7 discs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, double 127 and add 1: \(2(127)+1=255\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Using a Table to Find the Pattern&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;rsquo;s your turn. For the same game, how many moves would it take to solve the puzzle with 9 discs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your notebook, write down your answer. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to solve this problem using a general strategy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pattern is still the same. Double the number of moves before and add 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 8 discs, 255 moves were needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Double 255, and then add 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(2(255)+1=511\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did you do? Know that you learn more from wrong answers than from right answers! Wrong answers help us find flaws in our thinking. Take a minute to think about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you got the question wrong. Then you won&amp;rsquo;t get this type of question wrong again!&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2154">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659664359</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2155">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659664359</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="962">
        <prevpageid>961</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>963</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659664915</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662695562</timemodified>
        <title>4.13.3: The Connection Between Sequences and Terms</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (30 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This activity is provided in case an additional activity is needed to reinforce the lesson goal. Alternatively, if students are familiar with the Tower of Hanoi puzzle, use this activity instead, and use the structure of the launch and discussion for the Tower of Hanoi activity for the discussion of this activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This activity works best when each student has access to manipulatives or devices that can run the GeoGebra applet because students will benefit from seeing the relationship in a dynamic way. If students don&amp;rsquo;t have individual access, projecting the applet during the launch is helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitor for students writing clear explanations for Noah&amp;rsquo;s reasoning and for the number of moves needed for 7 checkers on each side to share during the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students can use the embedded applet below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students to read the rules to the puzzle and then give them time to solve the puzzle when there are 3 spaces and 1 checker on each side. Remind them they need to keep track of the number of moves needed since the goal is to find the smallest number of moves. Encourage groups to check in with those around them to see if anyone found a solution with fewer moves. Before groups begin work on the rest of the questions, select a student to demonstrate, using the applet, why it takes 3 moves to solve the puzzle when there are 3 spaces and 1 checker on each side as a check that everyone understands the rules of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Access for Students with Disabilities&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use virtual or concrete manipulatives to connect symbols to concrete objects. Provide black and red checkers if the applet is not available.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Student-Facing Statement &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;iframe height="350px" scrolling="no" src="https://www.geogebra.org/material/iframe/id/qugvaudj/width/681/height/350/border/888888/sfsb/true/smb/false/stb/false/stbh/false/ai/false/asb/false/sri/true/rc/false/ld/false/sdz/false/ctl/false" title="Alg2 Moving Checkers" width="681px"&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some checkers are lined up, with blue on one side, red on the other, and 1 empty space between them. A move in this checker game pushes any checker forward 1 space, or jumps over any 1 checker of the other color. Jumping the same color is not allowed, moving backward is not allowed, and 2 checkers cannot occupy the same space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="THREE BLACK CHECKERS, A SPACE, AND THEN THREE RED CHECKERS.
" class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="43" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/ZFUxXuQDNyrm1YDs9EEUvTrN" width="298"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You complete the puzzle by switching the colors completely: ending up with black on the right, red on the left, and 1 empty space between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Using 1 checker on each side, complete the puzzle. What is the smallest number of moves needed? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Using 3 checkers on each side, complete the puzzle. What is the smallest number of moves needed? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Estimate the number of moves needed if there are 2 or 4 checkers on each side. Then test your guesses. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Noah says he used the solution for 3 checkers on each side to help him solve the puzzle for 4 checkers. Describe how this might happen. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How many moves do you think it will take to complete a puzzle with 7 checkers on each side? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 3 moves &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 15 moves &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 8 moves and 24 moves &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Sample response: The moves that don&amp;rsquo;t involve the fourth checker on each side are the same as before, so it is possible to decide the number of moves by running the first half of the three-checker game, then moving the fourth checkers, and then running the second half. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 63 moves &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students may incorrectly interpret the rules or presume that there is no better solution once they find one solution that works. Encourage groups to regularly switch who is in charge of moving the checkers and to check with other groups around them once they think they have found a solution with the smallest number of moves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select students to share the smallest number of moves they found for 2, 3, and 4 checkers on each side. Each time, ask whether anyone in the class solved it with fewer moves. If no one finds the minimal solution, ask students to keep looking if time allows, or share the minimum number of moves and challenge them to do it, or demonstrate the minimal solution.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite previously identified students to share their explanation for Noah&amp;rsquo;s strategy and the number of moves needed to complete a puzzle with 3 checkers on each side. The bottom row of the table should now have the numbers 3, 8, 15, and 24 filled in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this activity was used instead of the Tower of Hanoi, make sure to define &amp;ldquo;sequence&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;term&amp;rdquo; for students before inviting students to describe a rule for the next term in the pattern. After a brief quiet think time, select 2&amp;ndash;3 students to share their thinking and write down any notation they come up with to describe the recursive rule, such as &amp;ldquo;first add 5, and then keep adding the next odd number.&amp;rdquo; There is no need to introduce formal notation or discuss a specific rule for finding term \(n\) at this time, but if students suggest these (time permitting), welcome their explanations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.13.3: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="312"&gt;
&lt;col width="312"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table below shows the number of checkers and the number of moves needed to win a skipping game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of Checkers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of Skips Needed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;32&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many skips are needed with 6 checkers on each side?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;50&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This is the number of skips needed with 5 checkers. The answer is 72.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;72&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: In every column, the number of checkers is multiplied by 2 more than the number in the previous column. 6 will be multiplied by 12, which results in 72 moves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;128&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This assumes the number of skips needed started to double, which is not the case. The answer is 72.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;48&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This did not change the number being multiplied by each time and kept multiplying the number of checkers by 8. The answer is 72.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.13.3: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Using a Table to Find Missing Values&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of Checkers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of Moves Needed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;24&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;63&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the pattern that you used in the previous activity to find the number of moves depending on the number of checkers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each row is multiplied by 1 more, so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(1\cdot3=3\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(2\cdot4=8\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(3\cdot5=15\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(4\cdot6=24\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many moves are needed with 5 checkers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(5\cdot7=35\) moves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about 6 checkers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(6\cdot8=48\) moves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Using a Table to Find Missing Values&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the table and the pattern, how many moves are needed with 8 checkers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your notebook, write down your answer. Then select the&lt;strong&gt; Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to solve this problem using a general strategy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next column in the table had 7 checkers and then multiplied 7 by 9 to get 63 moves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, the 8 would need to be multiplied by 10, so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(8\cdot10=80\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;80 moves are needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did you do? Know that you learn more from wrong answers than from right answers! Wrong answers help us find flaws in our thinking. Take a minute to think about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you got the question wrong. Then you won&amp;rsquo;t get this type of question wrong again!&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2156">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659664915</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2157">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659664915</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="963">
        <prevpageid>962</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>964</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659665059</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662592965</timemodified>
        <title>4.13.4: Rules for a Sequence </title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Cool Down (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sequence starts 3, 6, . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Give a rule the sequence could follow, and list the next 3 terms. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Give a different rule the sequence could follow, and list the next 3 terms. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Sample Responses: Each term adds 3 from the previous term. The next three terms are 9, 12, 15. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Sample Responses: Each term doubles the previous term. The next three terms are 12, 24, 48. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Video: Finding Rules of Sequences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the following video to learn more about function notations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls="true" crossorigin="anonymous" width="550"&gt;
&lt;source src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/e161d96dbd905859e9bc82ee894b9c9733f17953"&gt;
&lt;track default="true" kind="captions" label="On" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/bcf6b06bd6d99a7589eec56c19a72fee9c936e93" srclang="en_us"&gt;
  https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/e161d96dbd905859e9bc82ee894b9c9733f17953 &lt;/video&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2158">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659665059</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2159">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659665059</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="964">
        <prevpageid>963</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>965</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659665331</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662598207</timemodified>
        <title>4.13.5: Practice </title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Students will complete the following questions to practice the skills they have learned in this lesson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here is a rule to make a list of numbers: Each number is the sum of the previous two numbers. Start with the numbers 0 and 1, and then follow the rule to build a sequence of 10 numbers. Enter the 10th number in the sequence. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;34; 0, 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21, 34&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A sequence of numbers follows the rule: multiply the previous number by &amp;ndash;2 and add 3. The 4th term in the sequence is &amp;ndash;7.
    &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give the 8th term in the sequence. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;65&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give the term that came before &amp;ndash;7 in the sequence.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the 4th term if the first term is 2 and each term is 3 more than the previous number. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the 8th term of the sequence:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
    4, 7, 12, 19, 28, . . . &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 67&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="5"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the 8th term of the sequence:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
    &amp;ndash;8, &amp;ndash;6, &amp;ndash;3, 1, 6, . . . &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="6"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the next term in the sequence:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
    &amp;ndash;3, 6, &amp;ndash;12, 24, . . . &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ndash;48&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="7"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting with 2, each number is three times the previous number. What is the 4th term in the sequence?&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;54&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2160">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659665331</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2161">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659665331</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="965">
        <prevpageid>964</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659665380</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662592985</timemodified>
        <title>4.13.6: Lesson Synthesis</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2. Ask students to come up with a sequence of 5 numbers that follows some rule and write it down on a piece of paper. After a brief quiet think time, tell students to exchange papers with their partners and then try to find the next term in their partner&amp;rsquo;s sequence along with the rule they used. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclude the lesson by inviting students to share a sequence and rule their partner wrote that they found interesting. Display these for all to see while students share. &lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2162">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659665380</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2163">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659665380</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>
