<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="23" moduleid="194" modulename="page" contextid="205">
  <page id="23">
    <name>Unit 5 Wrap Up</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, you learned that Operation Hope founder John Hope Bryant helped underserved populations become part of the economy and work toward financial freedom. Teaching people about finance charges and the growth of investments involves looking at exponential models and comparing rates of change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, in this unit, you learned about exponential relationships. You learned that in an exponential relationship, the \(y\) values are being multiplied by the same number called the growth factor. You learned that exponential growth functions increase as \(x\) increases and exponential decay functions decrease as \(x\) increases.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also learned to identify key features of exponential graphs and to interpret graphs related to real world contexts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, you compared exponential functions to linear functions. While linear functions have a constant rate of change, exponential functions use the average rate of change over different intervals to describe how the data is changing. You compared linear growth to exponential growth using tables and graphs to verify that exponential functions eventually overtake the linear function.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Building Character: Grit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, you learned that grit is important to your success. It is your ability to use your passion and persevere to accomplish long term goals. Take time to find a purpose that will require you to find value in yourself and serve others. Grit is held up with determination and toughness which allows you to follow through on things you started. Look at your struggles as opportunities to learn.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:2:{s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";s:17:"printlastmodified";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>2</revision>
    <timemodified>1663657263</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>
