<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="178" moduleid="237" modulename="lesson" contextid="248">
  <lesson id="178">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Lesson 7.6 Teacher Guide: Building Quadratic Functions to Describe Situations, Part 2</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>1</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password/>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>0</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>238</activitylink>
    <mediafile/>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>0</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1665638270</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="1638">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1639</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1664836163</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665775914</timemodified>
        <title>7.6.0: Lesson Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Narrative&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, students used simple quadratic functions to describe how an object falls over time, given the effect of gravity. In this lesson, they build on that understanding and construct quadratic functions to represent projectile motions. Along the way, they learn about the zeros of a function and the vertex of a graph. They also begin to consider appropriate domains for a function, given the situation it represents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students use a linear model to describe the height of an object that is launched directly upward at a constant speed. Because of the influence of gravity, however, the object will not continue to travel at a constant rate. Eventually it will stop going higher and will start falling, so the model will have to be adjusted. They notice that this phenomenon can be represented with a quadratic function and that adding a squared term to the linear term seems to &amp;ldquo;bend&amp;rdquo; the graph and change its direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Goals (Teacher Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Create graphs of quadratic functions that represent a physical phenomenon and determine an appropriate domain when graphing. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Identify and interpret (orally and in writing) the meaning of the vertex of a graph and the zeros of a function represented in tables and graphs. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Write and interpret (orally and in writing) quadratic functions that represent a physical phenomenon. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Targets (Student Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Create quadratic functions and graphs that represent a situation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Relate the vertex of a graph and the zeros of a function to a situation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Know that the domain of a function can depend on the situation it represents. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TEKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation of Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;A7(A) graph quadratic functions on the coordinate plane and use the graph to identify key attributes, if possible, including \(x\)-intercept, \(y\)intercept, zeros, maximum value, minimum values, vertex, and the equation of the axis of symmetry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foundational: Lesson provides foundational content necessary for students to be able to perform this TEKS in later lessons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the instructional activities for the lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.6.1: Using Linear Functions to Describe Constant Speed &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.6.2: The Force of Gravity Change in Quadratic Functions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li aria-level="2"&gt; 7.6.2: Self Check &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li aria-level="2"&gt; 7.6.2: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.6.3: Using Quadratic Functions to Describe Height &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li aria-level="2"&gt; 7.6.3: Self Check &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li aria-level="2"&gt; 7.6.3: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.6.4: Interpreting Graphs of Quadratic Functions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will also complete a series of problems in the 7.6.5: Practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Graphing technology &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acquire devices that can run Desmos (recommended) or other graphing technology. It is ideal if each student has their own device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Vocabulary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this lesson, it is important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Familiarize students with the vocabulary words they will see throughout the lesson. Encourage students to look for these words and notice their use and meanings. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Encourage students to use key vocabulary words in &amp;ldquo;math talk&amp;rdquo; and their written and oral explanations. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Utilize a word wall. Sample cards are located here: &lt;a href="https://www.doe.virginia.gov/instruction/mathematics/resources/vocab_cards/" target="_blank"&gt;Mathematics Vocabulary Word Wall Cards&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary words that are emphasized in this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; constant &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; equation &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; expression &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; functions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; quadratic functions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; term &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;zero (of a function)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; parabola &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; vertex (of a graph)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; initial velocity &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Support for Building Character&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, find ways to encourage and support students to work on cultivating their proactivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to try during this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/think-it-do-it/" target="_blank"&gt;Think It, Do It&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/the-power-of-proactivity/" target="_blank"&gt;The Power of Proactivity&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other tips located here in the &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/playbooks/proactivity/" target="_blank"&gt;Playbook on Proactivity&lt;/a&gt; from Character Lab.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3682">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664836163</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1639">
        <prevpageid>1638</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1640</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1664836558</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665696890</timemodified>
        <title>7.6.1: Using Linear Functions to Describe Constant Speed</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Warm Up (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this warm up, students consider what happens if an object is launched up in the air unaffected by gravity. The work here serves two purposes. It reminds students that an object that travels at a constant speed can be described with a linear function. It also familiarizes students with a projectile context used in the next activity, in which students will investigate a quadratic function that more realistically models the movement of a projectile&amp;mdash;with gravity in play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students who use a spreadsheet to complete the table practice choosing tools strategically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask a student to read the opening paragraph of the activity aloud. To help students visualize the situation described, consider sketching a picture of a cannon pointing straight up, 10 feet above the ground. Ask students to consider what a speed of 406 feet per second means in more concrete terms. How fast is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students may be more familiar with miles per hour. Tell students that the speed of 406 feet per second is about 277 miles per hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider arranging students in groups of two so they can divide up the calculations needed to complete the table. Provide access to calculators, if requested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cannon is 10 feet off the ground. It launches a cannonball straight up with a velocity of 406 feet per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine that there is no gravity and that the cannonball continues to travel upward with the same velocity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Answer questions a&amp;ndash;f using the table with the heights of the cannonball at different times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="126"&gt;
&lt;col width="227"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seconds&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Distance above ground (feet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;10&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;a. _____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;b. _____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;c. _____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;d. _____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;e. _____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;\(t\)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;f. _____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How far above the ground is the cannonball at 1 second? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;416&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How far above the ground is the cannonball at 2 seconds? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;822&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How far above the ground is the cannonball at 3 seconds? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;1228&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How far above the ground is the cannonball at 4 seconds? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;1634&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="5" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How far above the ground is the cannonball at 5 seconds? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;2040&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="6" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How far above the ground is the cannonball at \(t\) seconds? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;The cannonball is \(10+406t\) feet above the ground at \(t\) seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write an equation to model the distance in feet, \(d\), of the ball \(t\) seconds after it was fired from the cannon, if there was no gravity.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;\(d=10+406t\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Ask students how the values in the table are changing and what equation would describe the height of the cannonball if there were no gravity. Even without graphing, students should notice that the height of the cannonball over time is a linear function, given the repeated addition of 406 feet every time \(t\) increases by 1. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Tell students that, in the next activity, they will look at some actual heights of the cannonball. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3683">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664836558</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3684">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664836558</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1640">
        <prevpageid>1639</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1641</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1664837192</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665723646</timemodified>
        <title>7.6.2: The Force of Gravity Change in Quadratic Functions</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to this course, students learned that an object traveling at a constant speed can be described with a linear function whose graph is a straight line. Here, they see a model that accounts for the fact that an object that is launched straight up at a constant speed does not keep going at the same rate when the influence of gravity is taken into account. Adding a quadratic term to a linear function has an effect of &amp;ldquo;bending&amp;rdquo; the graph, as the output values are no longer changing at a constant rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If students are unsure how to write an equation to represent the values in the table, ask them to compare how the actual heights of the cannonball at each second (when \(t\) is 1, 2, 3, etc.) differ from those in the no-gravity case (as shown in the table in the warm up). Finding the differences between the two outputs (16, 64, 144 . . .) at the same input values should help students think of the numbers and the functions they saw in the previous lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To generalize the relationship between time and distance, students reason repeatedly with numerical values and look for regularity. If students opt to use a spreadsheet or graphing technology, they practice choosing appropriate tools strategically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of two. Give students a minute of quiet time to think about the first question, and then time to share their observations with their partner. Tell students that they will need to reference their work in the warm up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some students may choose to use a spreadsheet tool to extend the pattern, and subsequently to use graphing technology to plot the data. Make these tools accessible, in case requested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier, in activity 7.6.1, you completed a table that represents the height of a cannonball, in feet, as a function of time, in seconds, if there was no gravity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This table shows the actual heights of the ball at different times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="221"&gt;
&lt;col width="35"&gt;
&lt;col width="39"&gt;
&lt;col width="35"&gt;
&lt;col width="47"&gt;
&lt;col width="52"&gt;
&lt;col width="56"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seconds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distance above ground (feet)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;400&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;758&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1084&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1378&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1640&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare the values in this table with those in the table you completed earlier. What are two similarities or differences that you notice?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The actual height values are all less than the hypothetical ones (except the first, before the cannonball has been fired). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The difference between the distances after some number of seconds is not constant. For example, 1 second after firing, the distances in the two tables are 416 and 400, a difference of 16 feet. Two seconds after firing, the difference between the two values is 64 feet. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the graphing tool or technology outside the course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Plot the two sets of data you have on the same coordinate plane. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Grid with points plotted. X-axis labeled with time in seconds and y-axis labeled with distance above ground in feet." height="243" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/q4aCtCg9ikMsEHoiFRpbHea3" width="472"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How are the two graphs alike? How are they different? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The dots (triangles) that form a straight line represent the hypothetical data that ignore gravity. The dots that form a curve represent the actual heights. They both start at the same place (0,10). The hypothetical data show the heights increasing at a constant rate, in a linear pattern, while the actual data show values growing more slowly each successive second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the starting position for both graphs?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;10
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the constant rate of change for the cannonball without gravity?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 406
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The constant rate of change is also the initial velocity. Recall that the effect of gravity is represented by \(16t^2\). Gravity causes the bend in the curve for the second table and graph because it pulls the cannonball down toward the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="5"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a partner, write an equation to model the actual distance \(d\), in feet, of the ball \(t\) seconds after it was fired from the cannon. Consider gravity and how the points changed on the graph.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Notice that gravity caused the heights to decrease, so, the effect of gravity is to subtract \(16t^2\). An equation for the actual height of the cannonball is \(d=10+406t-16t^2\).
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When comparing the tables, some students may make observations that lack the detail needed to write an equation for the actual height. Prompt them to rewrite the outputs for the actual height in terms of the hypothetical height (\(400=416-16\), \(758=822-64\), \(1084=1228-144\), and so on). Show them values of \(16t^2\) from a previous lesson to help them see and extend the pattern to write the equation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite students to share their observations about the two tables (the one from the warm up and the one here) and how the two graphs compare. Highlight responses that suggest that the values in the second table account for the effect of gravity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help students see how the output for each \(t\)-value varies across the two tables. When \(t\) is 1, the output in feet in the second table is 16 less than in the first table. When \(t\) is 2, there is a difference of 64 feet. When \(t\) is 3, that difference is 144 feet, and so on. The values 16, 64, 144 . . . correspond to the expression \(16t^2\) that we saw in the previous lesson (the distance fallen in feet as a function of time in seconds), so we can represent the values in the second table with the equation \(d=10+406t-16t^2\). Ask students:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;What do the 10, \(406t\), and \(-16t^2\) mean in this situation?&amp;rdquo; (The 10 is the vertical position of the cannonball before it was launched: 10 feet above ground. In \(406t\), the 406 tells us the vertical velocity at which it was shot up. The \(-16t^2\) accounts for the effect of gravity on the height of the cannonball after it was shot up.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;Why do you think the graph that represents \(d=10+406t\) changes from a straight line to a curve when \(-16t^2\) is added to the equation?&amp;rdquo; (Before that term was added, the height increased by 406 feet every second. Adding \(-16t^2\) decreases how much the cannonball travels up by some amount, but that amount gets larger each successive second. Eventually, the cannonball stops increasing in height and starts to fall.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.6.2: Self Check&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="302"&gt;
&lt;col width="322"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An arrow is shot up into the air from 5 feet, at an initial velocity of 200 feet per second. Which equation can represent the height, \(h(t)\), for any time, \(t\)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(t)=5+220t\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: Be sure to subtract the effects of gravity. The answer is \(h(t)=5+220t-16t^2\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(t)=5+220t+16t^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: Be sure to subtract the effects of gravity. The answer is \(h(t)=5+220t-16t^2\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(t)=5+220t-16t^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: Subtract the effect of gravity from the starting point and constant rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(t)=220+5t-16t^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The 220 is the initial velocity, not the starting height. The answer is \(h(t)=5+220t-16t^2\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.6.2: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Effect of Gravity on Motion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A firework is sent up in the air, at an initial velocity of 130 feet per second, from a height of 6 feet. Write an equation that represents the height, \(h(t)\), of the firework for any second, \(t\). Remember to consider the effect of gravity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 1&lt;br&gt;
    Identify the initial velocity, \(v_0\).&lt;br&gt;
    130 ft per second&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 2&lt;br&gt;
    Identify the starting height, \(h_0\).&lt;br&gt;
    6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 3&lt;br&gt;
    Write an equation of this form: \(h(t)=h_0+v_0t-16t^2\).&lt;br&gt;
    \(h(t)=6+130t-16t^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: The Effect of Gravity on Motion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write an equation if a firework is shot from 2 feet off the ground at an initial velocity of 110 feet per second. Write an equation that represents the height, \(h(t)\), of the firework for any second, \(t\). Remember to consider the effect of gravity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution &lt;/strong&gt;button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to write the equation for the height of the firework:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 1&lt;br&gt;
    Identify the initial velocity, \(v_0\).&lt;br&gt;
    110 ft per second&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 2&lt;br&gt;
    Identify the starting height, \(h_0\).&lt;br&gt;
    2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 3&lt;br&gt;
    Write an equation of this form: \(h(t)=h_0+v_0t-16t^2\).&lt;br&gt;
    \(h(t)=2+110t-16t^2\)&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3685">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664837192</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3686">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664837192</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1641">
        <prevpageid>1640</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1642</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1664838366</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665723801</timemodified>
        <title>7.6.3: Using Quadratic Functions to Describe Height</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this activity, students explore another model of a projectile motion. They graph and interpret a quadratic function in context and begin considering a reasonable domain for the function. Along the way, they practice reasoning concretely and abstractly. By the end of the lesson, they relate the vertex of the graph to the maximum height of the cannonball and the positive zero of the function to the time when the cannonball hits the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide access to devices that can run Desmos or other graphing technology. If needed, demonstrate how to adjust the graphing boundaries of the graphing tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the graphing tool available and their facility with it, students may approach the estimations in the third question in different ways (including by eyeballing). If desired, demonstrate how to use the graphing tool to trace the graph and identify the coordinates of any point on it (which may include values that are precise or values rounded to a specified decimal place). Or, first observe how students go about estimating and give additional guidance as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To support students with the last question, ask students: &amp;ldquo;Is the equation a good model for predicting the height of the cannonball 10 seconds after it is fired? What about 1 minute after it is fired?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The function defined by \(d=50+312t-16t^2\) gives the height in feet of a cannonball \(t\) seconds after the ball leaves the cannon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What does the term 50 tell us about the cannonball? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;The 50 tells us the cannonball is fired from 50 feet off of the ground.
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What does the term \(312t\) tell us about the cannonball?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;The \(312t\) tells us that the initial upward velocity is 312 feet per second.
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What does \(-16t^2\) tell us about the cannonball? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt; The \(-16t^2\) represents the effect of gravity pulling the cannonball back to the ground.
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the graphing tool or technology outside the course. Graph the function. Adjust the graphing window to the following boundaries: \(0&amp;lt;x&amp;lt;25\) and \(0&amp;lt;y&amp;lt;2000\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graph with time in seconds on x-axis and distance above ground in feet on y-axis." height="243" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/Xn3p9pxe8EpgDWuWSZzJKUm8" width="331"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Observe the graph and:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Describe the shape of the graph. What does it tell us about the movement of the cannonball? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;The distance from the ground increases, reaches a peak, and then decreases, which makes sense in the situation. It also looks like the distance from the ground decreases in the same way that it increased on the way up. The graph tells us the cannonball went up in the air, and then fell back down to the ground.
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shape of the quadratic function is called a parabola. It has a &amp;ldquo;U&amp;rdquo; shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Estimate the maximum height the ball reaches. When does this happen? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;The cannonball gets up to a little over 1500 feet, maybe to 1600 feet, at around 10 seconds.
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peak of the parabola, where the maximum occurs, is also called the vertex of the graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Estimate when the ball hits the ground. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;The cannonball hits the ground a little bit before 20 seconds.
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The zero of a function is where the function equals 0, or where it crosses the \(x\)-axis. In this case, there is only one zero where the cannonball hits the ground. The parabola does cross the \(x\)-axis in the negative \(x\)-values, but that does not make sense in this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What domain is appropriate for this function? Explain your reasoning.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;The equation is a good model for the height of the cannonball from the time it is launched, \(t=0\), until the time it lands, just before \(t=20\). For times outside of these values, the function values do not mean anything in the context (for example, for \(t=21\) the function would place the cannonball underground).
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Extension&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Are you ready for more?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the cannonball were fired at 800 feet per second, would it reach a mile in height? Remember there are 5280 feet in a mile. Explain your reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The equation here would be \(g(t)=50+800t-16t^2\). Since \(g(10)=6450\) and there are 5280 feet in a mile, this cannonball would reach over a mile in height. This could also be seen by graphing the function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Video: Using Quadratic Functions to Describe Height&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the following video to learn more about quadratic functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls="true" crossorigin="anonymous" width="550"&gt;
&lt;source src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/093e5117403a8baf805f1828e852741db18c5d56"&gt;
&lt;track default="true" kind="captions" label="On" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/4396d0c134864dce33a50af0f794467db0f6d55d" srclang="en_us"&gt;https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/093e5117403a8baf805f1828e852741db18c5d56
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite students to share their observations and interpretations of the graph. Highlight the following points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The graph representing a quadratic function is a parabola, which is a special kind of U shape. We will learn more about the geometry of this shape in a later course, but for now, notice that there is a point when the graph changes direction, from going up as \(x\) increases to going down (or changes from going down to going up). We call this point the vertex of the graph. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; In the previous activity, we plotted a limited set of points, so we could not tell where the vertex of the graph was. In this graph, we are able to identify the vertex. In this situation, the vertex tells us the maximum height that the cannonball reaches and the number of seconds after launch that it took before it starts to fall. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; In this graph, we can also see that the height of the cannonball is 0 when \(t\) is a little less than 20. That point, the horizontal intercept, relates to the zero of the function, or an input value that produces 0 for the output. In this situation, the zero tells us when the cannonball hits the ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Even though we can continue the graph beyond \(t = 20\), in this situation any output values beyond that point would not have any meaning. After the cannonball hits the ground, the function is no longer appropriate for modeling the movement of the cannonball. Likewise, the function is not appropriate before t=0 or before the cannon is fired. In this situation, a domain between 0 and just below 20 seconds is appropriate. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.6.3: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A toy rocket is launched from a platform 4 feet above the ground at a velocity of 128 feet per second. Its height is graphed below. Approximately what is the rocket&amp;rsquo;s maximum height?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height="245" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/7058010f9b3e45a72d284e4e7b7e615871fdab5d" width="244"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This is the time when the rocket hits the ground. The answer is 260 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;260&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: The peak, or vertex, of the graph is at approximately 260 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;110&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This is the height at 1 second. The answer is 260 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;128&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This is the velocity. The answer is 260 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.6.3: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Reading Graphs of Quadratics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An object is thrown upward from a height of 5 feet with a velocity of 60 feet per second. Its height, \(h(t)\), in feet after \(t\) seconds is modeled by the function \(h(t)=5+60t-16t^2\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graph of the quadratic function h(t)=5+60t&amp;minus;16t2  on a coordinate plane, origin  O. Horizontal axis scale 0 to 4 by 1&amp;rsquo;s, labeled &amp;ldquo;time (seconds)&amp;rdquo;. Vertical axis scale 0 to 80 by&amp;nbsp;20&amp;rsquo;s, labeled &amp;ldquo;distance above ground (feet)&amp;rdquo;. Some of the points of this function are (0 comma 5), (1 comma 49), to a maximum near (1 point 9 comma 61 point 2 5) then decreasing through (2 comma 61), (3 comma 41) and (3.8 comma 0)." height="231" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/KaMw3hqcauLrZMY6cEpX6ez1" width="311"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 1&lt;br&gt;Identify the starting height.&lt;br&gt;
    5 feet &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 2&lt;br&gt;Identify the maximum height by looking at the vertex or peak of the parabola.&lt;br&gt;
    approximately 62 feet &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 3&lt;br&gt;Identify when the object reaches its maximum by matching the maximum with its matching time from the \(x\)-axis.&lt;br&gt;
    approximately 1.75 seconds &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 4&lt;br&gt;When does the object hit the ground?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
    Look at where the object has a height of 0 feet, or the zero of the function. This happens at approximately 3.75 seconds. Notice there would be another zero on the graph of the function to the left of \(x=0\), but that does not make sense in the problem because the object was thrown from 5 feet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Try It: Reading Graphs of Quadratics &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rock is launched into the air, and its height is represented by the graph below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height="147" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/b461dcedda003c376d9dfa1281928c118887b198" width="295"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the maximum height of the rock?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to find the maximum height:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at the peak, or vertex of the parabola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maximum height is 25 feet after 2 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3687">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664838366</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3688">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664838366</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1642">
        <prevpageid>1641</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1643</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1664839957</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1664841517</timemodified>
        <title>7.6.4: Interpreting Graphs of Quadratic Functions</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Cool Down (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The height in feet, \(h\), of a stomp rocket (propelled by a short blast of air) above the ground after \(t\) seconds is given by the equation \(h(t)=5+100t-16t^2\). Here is a graph that represents \(h\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graph of the quadratic function h(t)=5+100t&amp;minus;16t2 on a coordinate plane, origin O . Horizontal axis scale 0 to 7 by 1&amp;rsquo;s, labeled &amp;ldquo;time (seconds)&amp;rdquo;. Vertical axis scale 0 to 200 by&amp;nbsp;50&amp;rsquo;s, labeled &amp;ldquo;height above ground (feet)&amp;rdquo;. Some of the points are (0 comma 5), (1 comma 89), (2 comma 141), (3 comma 161) to a maximum near (3 point 125 comma 161 point 25), then decreasing through (4 comma 149), (5 comma 105), (6 comma 29) and (6.3 comma 0)." height="224" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/NHBcaCebqTAG2xJkFXVmATP4" width="305"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the 5 in the equation relate to the graph?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;The graph intersects the vertical axis at 5.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does \(100t\) in the equation mean in terms of the rocket?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;It indicates that the initial velocity of the rocket was 100 feet per second upward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does the \(-16t^2\) mean in terms of the rocket?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;This indicates the effect of gravity pulling the rocket back toward Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; About when does the rocket hit the ground?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;At about 6.3 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Response to Student Thinking&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;More Chances&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will have more opportunities to understand the mathematical ideas in this cool down, so there is no need to slow down or add additional work to the next lessons. Instead, use the results of this cool down to provide guidance for what to look for and emphasize over the next several lessons to support students in advancing their current understanding.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3689">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664839957</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3690">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664839957</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1643">
        <prevpageid>1642</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1644</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1664841708</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665723215</timemodified>
        <title>7.6.5: Practice </title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Students will complete the following questions to practice the skills they have learned in this lesson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The height of a diver above the water is given by \(h(t)=-5t2+10t+3, where \(t\) is time measured in seconds and \(h(t)\) is measured in meters. &lt;strong&gt;Select two&lt;/strong&gt; statements that are true about the situation.
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The diver begins 5 meters above the water. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The diver begins 3 meters above the water. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The function has 1 zero that makes sense in this situation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The function has 2 zeros that make sense in this situation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The graph that represents \(h\) starts at the origin and curves upward. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The diver begins at the same height as the water level. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;The diver begins 3 meters above the water. The function has 1 zero that makes sense in this situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The height of a baseball, in feet, is modeled by the function \(h\) given by the equation \(h(t)=3+60t-16t^2\). The graph of the function is shown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A curve on a graph, origin O, with grid. Horizontal axis, time, seconds, scale 0 to 8, by 1&amp;rsquo;s. Vertical axis, height, feet, scale 0 to 200, by 20&amp;rsquo;s. A curve passes through the points 0 comma 3, 2 comma 59, and 3 comma 36." height="213" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/1Tc3u6N6uvwts8aDXqHXNdBC" width="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; About when does the baseball reach its maximum height? Round to the nearest second. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; About how high is the maximum height of the baseball? Round to the nearest ten. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 60&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; When does the baseball hit the ground? Round to the nearest second. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two rocks are launched straight up in the air. The height of Rock A is given by the function \(f\), where \(f(t)=4+30t-16ta^2\). The height of Rock B is given by \(g\), where \(g(t)=5+20t-16t^2\). In both functions, \(t\) is time measured in seconds and height is measured in feet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a graph of the functions. Use the graph to answer the questions a&amp;ndash;c.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height="268" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/f80174aede0833222b5c9b332dec4092d4db5bbe" width="279"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Which graph is the height of Rock A, \(f(t)=4+30t-16t^2\)?
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Red Graph &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Green Graph &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; Red Graph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Which graph is the height of Rock B, \(g(t)=5+20t-16t^2\)?
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Red Graph &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Green Graph &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; Green Graph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Determine which rock hits the ground first.
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Rock A &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Rock B &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; Rock B hits the ground first. The graph for Rock B (\(g(t)=5+20t-16t^2 function\)) crosses the x-axis at about 1.5, which means it hits the ground about 1.5 seconds after launch. The graph for Rock A \((f(t)=4+30t-16t^2 function\)) crosses the \(x\)-axis at about 2, which means it hits the ground about 2 seconds after launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each expression represents an object&amp;rsquo;s distance from the ground, in meters, as a function of time, \(t\), in seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Object A: \(-5t^2+25t+50\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Object B: \(-5t^2+50t+25\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Which object was launched with the greater vertical speed?
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Object A &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Object B &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; Object B&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Which object was launched from the greater height?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Object A &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Object B &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;Object A&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3691">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664841708</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3692">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664841708</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1644">
        <prevpageid>1643</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1664842742</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665683824</timemodified>
        <title>7.6.6: Lesson Synthesis </title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;To reinforce the connections between the parameters of a quadratic expression and the situation it describes, ask students:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve seen different expressions that represent vertical distances. Here are three expressions that all represent distance, in feet, as a function of time, in seconds, for an object that is dropped or launched. What does each of them tell us? Draw a diagram to illustrate the distances, if helpful.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(16t^2\) (The distance an object travels \(t\) seconds after being dropped.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(400-16t^2\) (The height of an object that is dropped from a height of 400 feet.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(50+100t-16t^2\) (The height of an object that is shot up from 50 feet above the ground at a vertical speed of 100 feet per second, \(t\) seconds after being launched.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;If each expression defines a function, what does the zero of that function tell us?&amp;rdquo; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(16t^2\) (The zero is the time when the object has traveled a distance of 0 feet. This happens at \(t=0\), before the object is dropped.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(400-16t^2\) (The zero is the time when the height of the object is 0 feet, which is when it hits the ground.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(50+100t-16t^2\) (The zero is the time when the height of the object is 0 feet, which is also when it hits the ground.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain to students that the models seen here are simplified models, and they ignore other factors, such as air resistance. The models that scientists use to study physical phenomena are likely to be more complex than what students have seen here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time permits, consider addressing a common misconception: that a graph of a quadratic function that represents distance-time relationship shows the physical trajectory of the object. Ask students to draw a sketch of what a bystander would see if they are facing the cannon as the ball is being launched. If needed, revisit the GeoGebra applet &amp;ldquo;Distance as a Quadratic Function of Elapsed Time&amp;rdquo; (from the previous lesson) to further emphasize this difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clarify that the graph represents the height of the object as a function of time, not the path that the object travels. In the examples given here, the object just goes straight up and straight down.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3693">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664842742</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3694">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664842742</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>
