<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="79" moduleid="108" modulename="lesson" contextid="119">
  <lesson id="79">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Unit 4 Teacher Guide</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>0</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password/>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>1</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>0</activitylink>
    <mediafile/>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>1</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1662572943</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="702">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>703</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659991324</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662344479</timemodified>
        <title>Unit 4 Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;In this unit, students will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide whether relations define a function and evaluate functions expressed in function notation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph linear functions on the coordinate plane and identify key features, identify transformations of the parent function \(f(x)=x\), and represent domain and range using inequalities for real-world situations.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify terms of arithmetic and geometric sequences and write a formula for the nth term of arithmetic and geometric sequences, given the value of several of their terms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To accomplish these unit-level learning goals, students will complete the following lessons and activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="94"&gt;
&lt;col width="246"&gt;
&lt;col width="284"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Number&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson Title&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Associated TEKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="3"&gt;Unit 4, Section A Overview: Functions and Their Representations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Describing and Graphing Situations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A12(A) decide whether relations represented verbally, tabularly, graphically, and symbolically define a function; define a function;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Function Notation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A12(A) decide whether relations represented verbally, tabularly, graphically, and symbolically define a function; define a function; A12(B) evaluate functions, expressed in function notation, given one or more elements in their domains;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Interpreting &amp;amp; Using Function Notation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A12(B) evaluate functions, expressed in function notation, given one or more elements in their domains;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Using Function Notation to Describe Rules, Part 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A12(B) evaluate functions, expressed in function notation, given one or more elements in their domains;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Using Function Notation to Describe Rules, Part 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A12(B) evaluate functions, expressed in function notation, given one or more elements in their domains;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="3"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Unit 4, Section A Quiz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="3"&gt;Unit 4, Section B Overview: Analyzing and Creating Graphs of Functions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Features of Graphs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A3(C) graph linear functions on the coordinate plane and identify key features, including \(x\)-intercept, \(y\)-intercept, zeros, and slope, in mathematical and real-world problems; A7(A) graph quadratic functions on the coordinate plane and use the graph to identify key attributes, if possible, including \(x\)-intercept, \(y\)-intercept, zeros, maximum value, minimum values, vertex, and the equation of the axis of symmetry;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Using Graphs to Find Average Rate of Change&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A3(A) determine the slope of a line given a table of values, a graph, two points on the line, and an equation written in various forms, including \(y = mx + b\), \(Ax + By = C\), and \(y - y1 = m(x - x1)\); A3(B) calculate the rate of change of a linear function represented tabularly, graphically, or algebraically in context of mathematical and real-world problems;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Interpreting and Creating Graphs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A3(B) calculate the rate of change of a linear function represented tabularly, graphically, or algebraically in context of mathematical and real-world problems;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Comparing Graphs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A3(B) calculate the rate of change of a linear function represented tabularly, graphically, or algebraically in context of mathematical and real-world problems;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Graphing a Function Using Transformations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A3(E) determine the effects on the graph of the parent function \(f(x) = x\) when \(f(x)\) is replaced by \(af(x)\), \(f(x) + d\), \(f(x - c)\), \(f(bx)\) for specific values of a, b, c, and d; \(A2(C)\) write linear equations in two variables given a table of values, a graph, and a verbal description(this standard is also covered in lessons 1.1-1.5); A2(E) write the equation of a line that contains a given point and is parallel to a given line; A.2(F) write the equation of a line that contains a given point and is perpendicular to a given line; ; A.2(G) write an equation of a line that is parallel or perpendicular to the \(x\)- or \(y\)-axis and determine whether the slope of the line is zero or undefined&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="3"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Unit 4, Section B Quiz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="3"&gt;Unit 4, Section C Overview: A Closer Look at Inputs and Outputs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Domain and Range (Part 1)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A2(A) determine the domain and range of a linear function in mathematical problems; determine reasonable domain and range values for real-world situations, both continuous and discrete; and represent domain and range using inequalities;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Domain and Range (Part 2)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A2(B) write linear equations in two A2(A) determine the domain and range of a linear function in mathematical problems; determine reasonable domain and range values for real-world situations, both continuous and discrete; and represent domain and range using inequalities;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="3"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Unit 4, Section C Quiz&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="3"&gt;Unit 4, Section D Overview: Sequences&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sequences&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;prep for A12(C) identify terms of arithmetic and geometric sequences when the sequences are given in function form using recursive processes;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Introducing Geometric Sequences&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A12(C) identify terms of arithmetic and geometric sequences when the sequences are given in function form using recursive processes;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Different Types of Sequences&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A12(C) identify terms of arithmetic and geometric sequences when the sequences are given in function form using recursive processes;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sequences Are Functions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A12(C) identify terms of arithmetic and geometric sequences when the sequences are given in function form using recursive processes;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The nth Term of an Arithmetic Sequence&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A12(D) write a formula for the nth term of arithmetic and geometric sequences, given the value of several of their terms; and&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="3"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Unit 4, Section D Quiz
            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="3"&gt;Unit 4, Section D Overview: Sequences&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unit 4 Project&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Using Functions to Model Battery Power&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A3(B) calculate the rate of change of a linear function represented tabularly, graphically, or algebraically in context of mathematical and real-world problems; 4(C) write, with and without technology, linear functions that provide a reasonable fit to data to estimate solutions and make predictions for real-world problems.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="3"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Unit 4 Project&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="3"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unit 4 STAAR Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Answer and alignment guide located &lt;a href="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/8ad58cf9d7251ea5980ae670592db294078b6b1b" target="_blank" title="here"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="3"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Unit 4 Test&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="3"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Unit 4 Wrap Up&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1567">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659991324</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="703">
        <prevpageid>702</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>704</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659992610</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1660759225</timemodified>
        <title>Unit 4 Narrative</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Unit 4: Functions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In grade 8, students learned that a function is a rule that assigns exactly one output to each input. They represented functions in different ways&amp;mdash;with verbal descriptions, algebraic expressions, graphs, and tables&amp;mdash;and used functions to model relationships between quantities, linear relationships in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this unit, students expand and deepen their understanding of functions. They develop new knowledge and skills for communicating about functions clearly and precisely, investigate different kinds of functions, and hone their ability to interpret functions. Students also use functions to model a wider variety of mathematical and real-world situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unit opens with a refresher on what functions are and what they are not. Students use descriptions, tables, and graphs to reason about the idea of &amp;ldquo;exactly one output for each input.&amp;rdquo; Then, students learn that function notation is an efficient way to communicate succinctly about functions and devote some focused time to interpreting this new notation and using it. They continue this work throughout the unit, employing the notation to perform increasingly sophisticated mathematical work: to analyze and compare functions, to write rules of functions (primarily linear functions), to solve for an input, to graph functions, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, students focus their attention on graphs of functions and on how they help tell stories about the relationships between the quantities in the functions. Students interpret features of graphs and relate them to features of situations, using terms such as &amp;ldquo;maximum,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;minimum,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;intercepts&amp;rdquo; to describe their observations. From a graph, students can see intervals where the values of a function increase or decrease. They learn to use average rates of change to more precisely describe how quickly these values rise or fall. Students also sketch graphs to depict qualitative behavior of functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students then go on to take a closer look at the input and output of a function. They think about possible and reasonable input and output values and learn to identify the domain and range of a function based on contextual and graphical information. This new awareness of input and output in turn helps students make sense of piecewise-defined functions, in which different rules apply to different intervals of the domain, producing different sets of output values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students close the unit by examining a sequence as a particular type of function. Through many concrete examples, students learn to identify geometric and arithmetic sequences. Students begin with an invitation to describe sequences with informal language. They write out the terms of sequences arising from mathematical situations, in addition to interpreting and creating tables and graphs about the given relationship. Students learn that sequences are a type of function in which the input variable is the position and the output variable is the term at that position. They learn to interpret and then write their own definitions for sequences recursively using function notation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expressions for the nth term of a sequence are built up through expressing regularity in repeated reasoning, building on students&amp;rsquo; prior experiences studying linear functions and experience with exponent patterns, which will lead to the study of exponential functions.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1568">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659992610</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1572">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659992610</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="704">
        <prevpageid>703</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>705</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659996005</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662491050</timemodified>
        <title>Unit 4 Family Support Materials</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;The following information can be shared with students&amp;rsquo; families to help support student engagement and encouragement at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Family Support Materials: Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this unit, students learn about functions, building on their work in middle school. A function is a relationship between an input and an output, where for every input there is exactly one output. Here are some examples of functions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The relationship between a name (input) and the number of letters in it (output). If the input is &amp;ldquo;Maya Angelou,&amp;rdquo; the only possible output is 11.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The relationship between the number of seconds since an oven was turned on (input) and the temperature in the oven (output). For example, 50 seconds after the oven was turned on, the temperature in the oven was 124 degrees Fahrenheit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often use the phrase &amp;ldquo;(output) is a function of (input)&amp;rdquo; to express how the input and output sets are related. For example, &amp;ldquo;the number of letters in a name is a function of the name,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;the temperature in the oven is a function of time since it was turned on.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make it easier to talk about and work with functions, we often use letters to name them, and we use function notation to represent their input and output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose \(f\) is a function that tells us the distance, in feet, that a child ran over time, \(t\), in seconds. So: \(f\) is the name of the function, time is the input, and distance is the output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how we represent this information in function notation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="5" cellspacing="0"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="312"&gt;
&lt;col width="312"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;&lt;img alt="Function notation, annotated." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/DeuzNp3oHAjyfqCfJ3uk7cot" width="200"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;The notation is read &amp;ldquo;\(f\) of \(t\).&amp;ldquo;&lt;br&gt;
                Here are some examples of some things we can say with function notation:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5" cellspacing="0"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center" valign="top" width="108"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center" valign="top" width="288"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;meaning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center" valign="top" width="228"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;interpretation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="108"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(f(t)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="288"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The output of \(f\) when \(t\) is the input&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="228"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distance run after \(t\)&amp;nbsp;seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="108"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(f(3)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="288"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The output of \(f\)&amp;nbsp;when 3 is the input&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="228"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distance run after 3 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="108"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(f(6)=14\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="288"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the input is 6, the output of&amp;nbsp;\(f\)&amp;nbsp;is 14.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="228"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 6 seconds, the child ran 14 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="108"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(f(t)=50\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="288"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the input is \(t\), the output of&amp;nbsp;\(f\)&amp;nbsp;is 50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="228"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In \(t\)&amp;nbsp;seconds, the child ran 50 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A function can also be represented with a graph. Here is a graph of function \(f\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A piecewise function on a coordinate plane." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/8CUKjLLs7RpqZEacVHHqMKEZ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can use it to estimate the input and output values of the function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, the graph shows that \(f(3) = 10\), which means that 3 seconds after she started running, the child has run 10 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can also use the graph to find out the time when the child has run 50 feet, or the value of \(t\) in \(f(t) = 50\). We can see that it happened when \(t = 18\) seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a rule tells us what to do to the input of a function to get the output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose function \(g\) gives the dollar cost of buying \(x\) burritos at $5 each. To get the output (the cost), we multiply the input (the number of burritos) by 5. We can write: \(g(x) = 5x\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a task to try with your students:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The height of a plant in centimeters is a function of its height in inches, \(h\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let \(p\) represent this function. Name the input and output of \(p\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does \(p(10)\) mean in this situation? What about \(p(h) = 50.8\)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because there are 2.54 centimeters in 1 inch, a rule that defines \(p\) is \(p(h) = 2.54h\). What is the value of \(p(10)\)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the value of \(h\) when \(p(h)\) is 50.8?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The input is height in inches. The output is height in centimeters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(p(10)\) represents the plant&amp;rsquo;s height in centimeters when its height is 10 inches.
        &lt;br&gt;\(p(h) = 50.8\) tells us that the plant is 50.8 centimeters tall when its height is \(h\) inches.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25.4 centimeters. \((p(10) = 2.54(10) = 25.4 )\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 inches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Video Lesson Summaries&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the video lesson summaries for Algebra 1, Unit 4: Functions. Each video highlights key concepts and vocabulary that students learn across one or more lessons in the unit. The content of these video lesson summaries is based on the written Lesson Summaries found at the end of lessons in the curriculum. The goal of these videos is to support students in reviewing and checking their understanding of important concepts and vocabulary. Here are some possible ways families can use these videos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep informed on concepts and vocabulary students are learning about in class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch with their students and pause at key points to predict what comes next or think up other examples of vocabulary terms (the bolded words).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider following the Connecting to Other Units links to review the math concepts that led up to this unit or to preview where the concepts in this unit lead to in future units.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="250"&gt;
&lt;col width="150"&gt;
&lt;col width="150"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Unit 4: Functions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Vimeo&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;YouTube&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Functions and Function Notation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/475138382/c246df1ee7" target="_blank"&gt;https://vimeo.com/475138382/c246df1ee7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video 'VLS Alg1U4V1 Functions and Function Notation (Lessons 1&amp;ndash;2)' available here: &lt;a href="https://player.vimeo.com/video/475138382" target="_blank"&gt;https://player.vimeo.com/video/475138382&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/XDTw5NaeRzs" target="_blank"&gt;https://youtu.be/XDTw5NaeRzs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Interpreting Function Notation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/475175352/1706e86bec" target="_blank"&gt;https://vimeo.com/475175352/1706e86bec&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video 'VLS Alg1U4V2 Interpreting Function Notation (Lessons 3&amp;ndash;5)' available here: &lt;a href="https://player.vimeo.com/video/475175352" target="_blank"&gt;https://player.vimeo.com/video/475175352&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/MDTCMqRH9-Y" target="_blank"&gt;https://youtu.be/MDTCMqRH9-Y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Graphs of Functions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/475177841/4a8310fcac" target="_blank"&gt;https://vimeo.com/475177841/4a8310fcac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video 'VLS Alg1U4V3 Graphs of Functions (Lessons 6&amp;ndash;7)' available here: &lt;a href="https://player.vimeo.com/video/475177841" target="_blank"&gt;https://player.vimeo.com/video/475177841&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/qC2CyJpKBwo" target="_blank"&gt;https://youtu.be/qC2CyJpKBwo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Making and Interpreting Graphs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/476640104/4fd26242cc" target="_blank"&gt;https://vimeo.com/476640104/4fd26242cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video 'VLS Alg1U4V4 Making and Interpreting Graphs (Lessons 8&amp;ndash;9)' available here: &lt;a href="https://player.vimeo.com/video/476640104" target="_blank"&gt;https://player.vimeo.com/video/476640104&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/NW5cEepE_Ds" target="_blank"&gt;https://youtu.be/NW5cEepE_Ds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Domain and Range&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/476642212/d791f981e7" target="_blank"&gt;https://vimeo.com/476642212/d791f981e7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video 'VLS Alg1U4V5 Domain and Range (Lessons 10&amp;ndash;11)' available here: &lt;a href="https://player.vimeo.com/video/476642212" target="_blank"&gt;https://player.vimeo.com/video/476642212&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/tsnfPccqdFU" target="_blank"&gt;https://youtu.be/tsnfPccqdFU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1569">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659996005</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1571">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659996005</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="705">
        <prevpageid>704</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659996682</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662664349</timemodified>
        <title>Building Character: Creativity</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;Throughout the unit, you will be provided with resources to promote students&amp;rsquo; character development. These resources come from &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/"&gt;Character Lab&lt;/a&gt; and their &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/playbooks/"&gt;Playbooks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus for this unit is on creativity: the use of imagination and original ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the Unit 4 Overview and Readiness lesson, students will see an example of how this trait is modeled through a real-world scenario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In each lesson&amp;rsquo;s Teacher Guide, you will be provided with links to tips that may help you foster this trait in students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Why Does Creativity Matter?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you approach life with a creative attitude, you are more open to new ideas and possibilities, better able to understand others&amp;rsquo; perspectives, and more likely to seek out multiple solutions to problems. Despite the stereotype of the mad genius, everyday creativity is just as important. You can use it to help you improve your mood and cope with stress, feel more connected with other people and the world&amp;mdash;and even help you find meaning and purpose in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How Do I Encourage Creativity in My Students?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider some of these suggestions for promoting creativity in your classroom:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Model it. Try new experiences and look for new ways of seeing things. Be flexible in your path to reaching a goal: &amp;ldquo;I thought I knew how to perform this cello concerto, but in hearing how it sounds, I realize I need to try a different approach.&amp;rdquo; Rather than focus on completing a task, think of all the different ways you might accomplish the same goal&amp;mdash;or even question why you are doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Celebrate it. Appreciate creative thinking in others: &amp;ldquo;I didn&amp;rsquo;t think of that idea, but it really works.&amp;rdquo; Look for examples of creativity among exemplary artists, scientists, and leaders throughout history or in your local community, and talk about them to your family, friends, and students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enable it. Ask open-ended questions. Point out that there usually isn&amp;rsquo;t a single straightforward answer to any complex problem: &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s come up with as many different possible solutions as we can.&amp;rdquo; Allow time for mind-wandering, play, and daydreaming. It is easy to get stuck in the same routine every day, so help the young people in your life find even small ways to shake things up.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="1570">
            <jumpto>704</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659996682</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="1573">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659996682</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>
