<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="39" moduleid="334" modulename="page" contextid="345">
  <page id="39">
    <name>Unit 9 Wrap Up</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;In this unit, you learned how companies like The Ensemble Theatre use quadratic equations to solve problems. Business managers use quadratics to represent revenue as a product of the price of a ticket and the quantity sold. Quadratic equations can also be used to predict profit and loss. Other companies use quadratics to determine the best materials to use or to determine which dimensions will be best to maximize a given space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, you learned how to solve quadratic equations using the methods of completing the square and the quadratic formula. You also learned how to use graphs and other methods to check your solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, you wrote quadratic expressions in vertex form to identify the vertex as well as the maximum or minimum value of the quadratic function. This value was then used to solve real-life problems involving the maximum revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Building Character: Intellectual Humility&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, you learned that &lt;strong&gt;intellectual humility&lt;/strong&gt; is important for recognizing the limitations of your knowledge. You learned that when you approach life with intellectual humility, you open your mind to learning. You are able to learn from opposing views and have more constructive discussions, even when you disagree. You learned that no matter how old you are, with intellectual humility, you become wiser. It helps you be less judgmental of others, learn more in school, and be a better leader.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:2:{s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";s:17:"printlastmodified";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>2</revision>
    <timemodified>1667312435</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>
