<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="138" moduleid="181" modulename="lesson" contextid="192">
  <lesson id="138">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Lesson 5.11 Teacher Guide: Modeling Exponential Behavior</name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>1</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password></password>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>0</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>182</activitylink>
    <mediafile></mediafile>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>1</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1662772956</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="1276">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1277</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1661993011</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1663776169</timemodified>
        <title>5.11.0: Lesson Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Narrative&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this lesson, students study the successive bounce heights of balls, model the relationship between the number of bounces and the bounce heights, and use that model to answer questions about the balls’ bounciness. There are options for how much of the modeling cycle students undertake. In one optional activity, students collect data for the bounce heights of different balls, while in two activities the data are provided. In all cases, the data are deliberately “messy” to mirror data students would gather through experimentation, and students are left to decide what kind of model to use. Though the data are not perfectly exponential or linear, an exponential model fits much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once students decide to use an exponential model, they still have to find the parameters that best fit the data while maintaining a reasonable level of accuracy. Some may just use the quotient of the first two bounce heights, while others may look more closely at all of the bounce heights. As they compare and critique the different models, students construct viable arguments and critique the reasoning of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology isn’t required for this lesson, but there are opportunities for students to choose to use appropriate technology to solve problems. We recommend making technology available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making internet-enabled devices available gives students an opportunity to choose appropriate tools strategically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Learning Goals (Teacher Facing)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Choose an appropriate model for a situation when given data. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Determine graphing windows that would make a graph more informative or meaningful. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Use exponential functions to model situations that involve exponential growth or decay. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Targets (Student Facing)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Use exponential functions to model situations that involve exponential growth or decay. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Determine an appropriate model for a situation described by data. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TEKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation of Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;A9(C) write exponential functions in the form \(f(x) = ab^x\) (where \(b\)&amp;nbsp;is a rational number) to describe problems arising from mathematical and real-world situations, including growth and decay;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Foundational: Lesson provides foundational content necessary for students to be able to perform this TEKS in later lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the instructional activities for the lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 5.11.1: Changing the Graphing Window &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 5.11.2: Choosing an Appropriate Model &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; 5.11.2: Self Check&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; 5.11.2: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 5.11.3: (Optional) Modeling with Exponential Functions &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 5.11.4: Examine Exponential Decay in Context &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; 5.11.4: Self Check&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; 5.11.4: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 5.11.5: Using Relationship Models to Answer Questions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will also complete a series of problems in the 5.11.6: Practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; A collection of balls that bounce (optional activity) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Measuring tapes (optional activity) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Graphing technology &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graphing technology should be available if students request it. Measuring tapes and balls that bounce are only needed if doing the optional activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Vocabulary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this lesson, it is important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Familiarize students with the vocabulary words they will see throughout the lesson. Encourage students to look for these words and notice their use and meanings. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Encourage students to use key vocabulary words in “math talk” and their written and oral explanations. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Utilize a word wall. Sample cards are located here: &lt;a href="https://www.doe.virginia.gov/instruction/mathematics/resources/vocab_cards/" target="_blank"&gt;Mathematics Vocabulary Word Wall Cards&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary words that are emphasized in this lesson include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Previous Vocabulary&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;New Vocabulary&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt; exponential function &lt;/li&gt;

                &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;ul&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt; none&lt;/li&gt;

                &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; Support for Building Character&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, find ways to encourage and support students to work on cultivating their &lt;strong&gt;grit&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to try during this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/other-side-of-stress/" target="_blank"&gt;The Other Side of Stress&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/preach-what-you-practice/" target="_blank"&gt;Preach What You Practice&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other tips located here in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/playbooks/grit/" target="_blank"&gt;Playbook on Grit&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;from Character Lab.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2869">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1661993011</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1277">
        <prevpageid>1276</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1278</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1661993716</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1663667230</timemodified>
        <title>5.11.1: Changing the Graphing Window</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Warm Up (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This warm-up prompts students to think about how changing the graphing window influences what you can see and understand about an exponential function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a graph of a function \(f(x)=400 \cdot (0.2)^x\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/v7GjPUBskaj9LhokrNb1pGTc" alt="Graph of a function on grid, origin O. Horizontal axis, x, from 0 to 40 by 10's. Vertical axis, y, from 0 to 1,000, by 500's. Line crosses &amp;nbsp;y axis at 0 comma 400, quickly decreasing then running horizontal to x axis."&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Identify the approximate graphing window shown. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(0&amp;lt;x&amp;lt;44\) and \(0&amp;lt;y&amp;lt;1,100\) or equivalent
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Suggest a new graphing window that would: &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; make the graph more informative or meaningful .&lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(
            0&amp;lt;x&amp;lt;10\) and \(0&amp;lt;y&amp;lt;450\). This window would include \(x\)-values where meaningful changes happen and exclude the parts where the changes are very small. The \(y\)-values are limited to values that matter, between 0 and 400, allowing us to see more clearly the changes in that range.
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; make the graph less informative or meaningful.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(-10&amp;lt;x&amp;lt;80\) and \(10&amp;lt;y&amp;lt;700\). This window would show a lot of useless \(x\)-values and cut off the \(y\)-values at 100, which would hide the behavior of the function when \(x\) is between 0 and 1.
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be prepared to explain your reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite students to share some suggestions for a graphing window that are more helpful and those that are less helpful. Ask them to explain their reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help students understand that, as a general rule, the \(x\)-values to show for a graph are usually determined by the quantity we are interested in studying. The \(y\)-values need to be selected carefully so that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;data of interest show up on the graph. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;interesting trends (of increase or decrease) are as visible as possible. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time permits, discuss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;“Why does the graph show such a sharp decrease between \(x\)-values of 0 and 2 and then start to flatten out?” (The decay factor is 0.2, which means that whenever \(x\) increases by 1, it loses 0.8 of its quantity and keeps only 0.2. That decay is more apparent when the quantity is larger. As it gets smaller, and given the scale of the graph, it is harder to see the change. For example, when \(x\) increases from 0 to 1, \(f(x)\) decreases by 320 because \((0.8) \cdot 400=320\). But when \(x\) increases from 2 to 3, \(f(x)\) decreases by \((0.8) \cdot 16\) or 10.8, which is a much smaller drop.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2870">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1661993716</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2871">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1661993716</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1278">
        <prevpageid>1277</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1279</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1661994165</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1663710120</timemodified>
        <title>5.11.2: Choosing an Appropriate Model</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this activity, students examine the successive heights that a tennis ball reaches after several bounces on a hard surface and consider how to model the relationship between the number of bounces and the height of the rebound. To do so, they need to determine the growth factor of successive bounce heights. Because some data are provided here, students engage in only some aspects of mathematical modeling. To engage students in the full modeling cycle that includes data gathering, consider asking students to measure the bounce heights of a ball, as suggested in the next optional activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real-world data are often messy, and that is the case for the data provided here. Monitor for students who try the following approaches in deciding whether a linear or exponential model is more appropriate for modeling the data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Use the table of values and look at successive differences. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Use the table of values and look at successive quotients. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Plot the points and observe the general trend in bounce height. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Plot the points using graphing technology and use the technology to generate a line or curve of best fit. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While each successive bounce height is about half of the preceding height, there is variation in the data, with the largest factor being a little more than 0.55 and the smallest a little less than 0.47. Monitor the way students choose to deal with this variation, which affects the model they consider appropriate. They may:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Decide that an exponential model is not appropriate because the growth factor is different from bounce to bounce. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Make a rough approximation for the growth factor, for example, by observing that each bounce height \(h\) is about half the preceding bounce height: \(h=150\cdot\left(\frac12\right)^n\). &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Find and use the growth factor from the first two points: \(h=150\cdot\left(\frac8{15}\right)^n\). &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Take an average of the successive quotients: \(h=150\cdot\left(0.53\right)^n\). &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Use graphing technology to generate a regression equation: \(h=150.389\cdot\left(0.527\right)^n\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select students who use these strategies to share during the discussion. Encourage those who do not think an exponential model is appropriate to look for an exponential model that best fits the given data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making graphing technology available gives students an opportunity to choose appropriate tools strategically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2–4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div style="border:1px solid black; padding:5px; background-color:#f2f2f2;"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt; Use this routine to prepare students for the whole-class discussion. At the appropriate time, ask students to prepare a visual display that shows their mathematical thinking and reasoning for the first question. Invite students to quietly circulate and read at least 2 other posters or visual displays in the room. Give students quiet think time to consider what is the same and what is different about the displays. Next, ask students to return to their group to discuss what they noticed. Listen for and amplify observations for choosing an exponential or linear model. This will help students interpret real-world data and provide justification for choosing an exponential model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h5&gt; Support for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div style="border:1px solid black; padding:5px; background-color:#f2f2f2;"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Begin with a demonstration or video of bouncing a ball to clarify what bounce height means. Highlight connections between representations by using color coding or annotations to connect the numbers in the table to the symbols in the equation \(y=1000⋅(\frac{1}{2})^x\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/525933d5a4d45841a7d948c4bb5692b2f0f1be0f" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are measurements for the maximum height of a tennis ball after bouncing several times on a concrete surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="153"&gt;
        &lt;col width="186"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(n\)&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bounce number&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(h\)&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;height (centimeters)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;150&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;80&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;43&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;20&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;11&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Which is more appropriate for modeling the maximum height \(h\), in centimeters, of the tennis ball after \(n\) bounces: A linear function or an exponential function? Use data from the table to support your answer. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Exponential. Sample explanations:
        &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; Plotting the points in the plane, they are not close to being on a line. &lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt;
              &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/HhgdNLu7MgnvqoVB7sh6BMxZ" alt="5 points on coordinate plane, showing exponential decay. Horizontal axis from 0 to 8, labeled number of bounces. Vertical axis from 0 to 200, labeled height in centimeters."&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A linear function of the bounce height would decrease by the same amount for each successive bounce. The differences in heights between successive bounces are not close to being the same, as shown in the table. They are decreasing with each bounce, so the function is not linear.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
                &lt;colgroup&gt;
                    &lt;col width="134"&gt;
                    &lt;col width="205"&gt;
                &lt;/colgroup&gt;
                &lt;tbody&gt;
                    &lt;tr&gt;
                        &lt;td&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bounce number&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;td&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;difference from height&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;of previous bounce&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;/td&gt;
                    &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;tr&gt;
                        &lt;td&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;td&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;/td&gt;
                    &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;tr&gt;
                        &lt;td&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;td&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;70&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;/td&gt;
                    &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;tr&gt;
                        &lt;td&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;td&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;37&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;/td&gt;
                    &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;tr&gt;
                        &lt;td&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;td&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;23&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;/td&gt;
                    &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;tr&gt;
                        &lt;td&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;td&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;/td&gt;
                    &lt;/tr&gt;
                &lt;/tbody&gt;
            &lt;/table&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;An exponential function of the bounce height would decrease by the same factor for each successive bounce. It looks like each successive bounce is about half as high as the previous bounce, making an exponential model appropriate.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Regulations say that a tennis ball, dropped on concrete, should rebound to a height between 53% and 58% of the height from which it is dropped. Does the tennis ball here meet this requirement? Explain your reasoning. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Answers vary. Sample responses:
        &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; Yes. The first rebound is a little over 53%, the second is almost 54%, and the fourth is 55%. The third rebound is only about 47%, but there could be some measurement error. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; No, the third rebound is less than 50% of the height from which the tennis ball fell, falling out of the allowable range. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; It is not possible to tell. One of the values is too low, and the others are close enough to 53% that it is impossible to be sure whether the bounces of this ball fall within the regulations. &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Write an equation that models the bounce height \(h\) after \(n\) bounces for this tennis ball. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(
        h=150 \cdot (0.53)^n\) (A factor of exactly 0.5 is also acceptable, or any value between 0.53 and 0.58.)
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; About how many bounces will it take before the rebound height of the tennis ball is less than 1 centimeter? Explain your reasoning. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 8 bounces. Sample reasoning:
        &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; The height of the ball is decreasing by a factor of about \(\frac12\) after each bounce. So after 3 more bounces, it will decrease by a factor of about \(\frac18\) (giving a little more than 1 cm), but after 4 more bounces, it will decrease by a factor of about \(\frac{1}{16}\). &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; Graphing \(
                h=150 \cdot (0.53)^n\) and \(h=1\) simultaneously using graphing technology shows the bounce height first goes below \(h=1\) on the 8th bounce. &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students may not be comfortable with the data not fitting an exponential function exactly. Remind them that real-world data is messy, so, when modeling, we must do our best to approximate the data. If an exponential model does a good job at approximating the data and showing its general trend, then this is a reasonable model to use even though it does not accurately predict or match all of the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students to share how they decided whether a linear or exponential function is more appropriate for modeling the data. Once the class concludes that a linear model is less suitable, select previously identified students to share how they determined a growth factor to use for their models and the resulting equations. Sequence the strategies being presented as shown in the Activity Narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connect the discussion about growth factors to the data and what the factors tell us about whether the tennis ball satisfies the bounce regulations. Ask questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;“Do most of the data support the conclusion?”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;“How can we explain the third bounce?” (E.g., it is too low, but there could have been a mis-measurement, or the tennis ball could have hit something on the floor.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To follow up on the last question, consider discussing the practical domain in this context. Ask, for instance: “How long could we expect this behavior to continue? Can it go on indefinitely? What is a reasonable domain for our model?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Video: Determining a Model and an Equation from a Real-World Scenario&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the following video to learn more about modeling exponential functions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls="true" crossorigin="anonymous" width="550"&gt;
  &lt;source src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/a7ccee1ed903f5974363946e57e5279ce4e0db1c"&gt;
    &lt;track src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/d4f86121e68fb579446a1e7b45585e8eebd495f6" kind="captions" srclang="en_us" label="On" default="true"&gt;https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/a7ccee1ed903f5974363946e57e5279ce4e0db1c
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5.11.2: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-266c0a4a-7fff-840c-2bf5-2a5f06d6454e"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Following the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="302"&gt;
        &lt;col width="322"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;The table gives predictions of the average costs of a gasoline car after the year 2030.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Which graph best represents the relationship between time and the predicted cost?&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="5"&gt;
                    &lt;tbody&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="347" colspan="2" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p align="center"&gt;Gasoline car&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="173" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;Time (years)&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="173" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;Cost (thousand of dollars)&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="173" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="173" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;35&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="173" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="173" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;40.2&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="173" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;10&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="173" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;46.3&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="173" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;15&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="173" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;53.2&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td width="173" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;20&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td width="173" valign="top"&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;61.2&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;/tbody&gt;
                &lt;/table&gt;
                &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/4ecc375fae81d430969b613cdbed81b772e704c8" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This graph shows a linear model. The table represents an exponential relationship. The answer is&lt;br&gt;
                    &lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/d78c1c1afbc3953042d0e40268d490ffb665603f" width="300"&gt;
                &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/e2ed088b53630b2221604b92225da5de51764eb4" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This graph shows a decreasing linear relationship. The numbers in the table are growing in a nonlinear and increasing way. The answer is &lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/d78c1c1afbc3953042d0e40268d490ffb665603f" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/d78c1c1afbc3953042d0e40268d490ffb665603f" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;That’s correct! Check yourself: The cost of the car increases at an increasing rate over time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/05b6651962e9fe8195bb74c06444b20fd1aa92c6" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This graph shows a decreasing relationship. The cost of the car increases over time. The answer is&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/d78c1c1afbc3953042d0e40268d490ffb665603f" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt; 5.11.2: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Using an Exponential Model&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lab researcher records the growth of the population of a yeast colony and finds that the population doubles every hour. The table below records the first four hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td width="168" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Hours into study&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td width="16" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td width="22" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="22" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="22" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="26" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td width="168" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Yeast colony population (thousands)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="16" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="22" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;10&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="22" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;20&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="22" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;40&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td width="26" valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;80&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The starting value is 5 (in thousands) and the population doubles, so the growth factor is 2.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The equation to model this growth is \(P(t)=5 \cdot 2^t\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph is below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/f9d129f48e1afeea6abea1cb7c3e862bb59c2b95" alt="" width="250" height="253" role="presentation" class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Using an Exponential Model&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A ball bounces up and down from a starting height of 65 centimeters. As it bounces, its height decreases to \(\frac13\) the previous height. Complete a table to represent the first 4 bounces. Then write a function, \(h(x)\), to determine the height after \(x\) bounces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to find the model for this situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Number of bounces, \(x\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Height, \(h(x)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;65&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(\frac{65}{3}\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(\frac{65}{9}\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(\frac{65}{27}\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(\frac{65}{81}\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial height is 65, and the growth factor is \(\frac13\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maximum height, \(h(x)\), after \(x\) bounces can be represented by \(h(x)=65 (\frac{1}{3})^x\).&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2872">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1661994165</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2873">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1661994165</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1279">
        <prevpageid>1278</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1280</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1661996611</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1663693579</timemodified>
        <title>5.11.3: (Optional) Modeling with Exponential Functions</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Optional Activity (40 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This optional activity, designed for an extra class period, gives students an opportunity to gather and analyze data for bounce heights for multiple balls. Each ball should be sufficiently bouncy to allow measurement of at least 4 bounces. Good examples include: tennis balls, basketballs, super balls, golf balls, and soccer balls. It will also be important to find a surface that is hard, flat, and level. Any padding will dampen the bounces, and any slant or irregularity on the surface will affect the direction of the bounce. A tiled or concrete floor or a flat and paved surface outdoors should work. Students will need measuring tapes and may need some practice gathering the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice how students record the bounce heights. Recording these heights to the nearest inch or centimeter will already be challenging, and anything beyond that is too much precision. This activity is a good opportunity to choose a degree of precision appropriate to the context and the measuring device used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in the previous task, monitor how students process their data and decide on an appropriate factor to quantify the bounciness of each ball. Students should now be comfortable with the fact that the data are not exactly exponential, but they may still choose different ways for deciding on an appropriate exponential decay factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are typical rebound factors for several types of balls:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Tennis ball: 0.5 to 0.6 &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Super ball: 0.9 &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Basketball: about 0.6 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making graphing or spreadsheet technology available gives students an opportunity to choose appropriate tools strategically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 3 or 4. Give each group a measuring tape and a ball. Explain to students that their job is to determine the rebound factors of several balls by gathering data on their rebound heights. They then need to use mathematics to model the relationship between the number of bounces and the height of a bounced ball.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students should drop all the balls from the same height. Consider letting students realize this on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***If you are not able to give groups of students 3 balls to collect their own data, or if you would like to save time, have students “click to reveal” the sample table prefilled with data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div style="border:1px solid black; padding:5px; background-color:#f2f2f2;"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Leverage choice around perceived challenge. Invite students to select 1 or 2 balls to bounce, instead of 3. Chunking this task into more manageable parts may also benefit students who benefit from additional processing time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your teacher will give your group three different kinds of balls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your goal is to measure the rebound heights, model the relationship between the number of bounces and the heights, and compare the bounciness of the balls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/mMaVZjLeWUBCQPiPsG34GLUb" alt="Group of different types of sport balls." width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Complete the table. Make sure to note which ball goes with which column. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="148"&gt;
        &lt;col width="153"&gt;
        &lt;col width="153"&gt;
        &lt;col width="150"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(n\), number of bounces&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(a\), height for ball 1 (cm)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(b\), height for ball 2 (cm)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(c\), height for ball 3 (cm)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="148"&gt;
        &lt;col width="153"&gt;
        &lt;col width="153"&gt;
        &lt;col width="150"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(n\), number of bounces&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(a\), height for ball 1 (cm)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(b\), height for ball 2 (cm)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(c\), height for ball 3 (cm)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;150&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;150&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;150&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;80&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;100&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;60&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;41&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;70&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;25&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;20&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;50&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;13&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;11&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;35&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Which one appears to be the bounciest? Which one appears to be the least bouncy? Explain your reasoning. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The second ball is the bounciest. The balls were all dropped from the same height, and its bounces are the highest. The third ball is the least bouncy.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; For each one, write an equation expressing the bounce height in terms of the bounce number \(n\). &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Sample response:
        &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; Ball 1: \(a=150 \cdot (\frac{1}{2})^n\) or \(a=150 \cdot (0.5)^n\) &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; Ball 2: \(b=150 \cdot (\frac{7}{10})^n\) or \(b=150 \cdot (0.7)^n\) &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; Ball 3: \(c=150 \cdot (\frac{2}{5})^n\) or \(c=150 (0.4)^n\)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Explain how the equations could tell us which one is the most bouncy. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The bounciness of the ball is measured by the rebound factor, which is the base of the exponential expression. This is \(\frac12\) for the first ball, \(\frac{7}{10}\) for the second ball, and \(\frac25\) for the third ball. The larger this number, the bouncier the ball.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; If the bounciest one were dropped from a height of 300 cm, what equation would model its bounce height \(h\)? &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(h=300 \cdot (\frac{7}{10})^n\)
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Student-Facing Extension&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Are you ready for more?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; If Ball 1 were dropped from a point that is twice as high, would its bounciness be greater, less, or the same? Explain your reasoning. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Sample response: The same. The bounciness of the ball does not depend on the height from which it is dropped. This is why the successive rebound heights are modeled by an exponential function.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Ball 4 is half as bouncy as the least bouncy ball. What equation would describe its height \(h\) in terms of the number of bounces \(n\)? &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Sample response: \(h=150(\frac{1}{5})^n\)
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Ball 5 was dropped from a height of 150 centimeters. It bounced up very slightly once or twice and then began rolling. How would you describe its rebound factor? Explain your reasoning. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Sample response: The rebound factor is very close to 0. Because the ball barely left the ground after hitting it, we could say that it lost almost all of its height with each bounce.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students may struggle to measure the heights of the bounces. Consider allowing phones or other technology that can record a video of the bounces so that it can be replayed in slow motion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on available time, you may choose to have groups of students prepare a presentation for sharing their findings or simply discuss the data and findings as a whole class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in the previous task, highlight different methods for estimating the rebound factor (taking the quotient of two successive values, taking an average of successive quotients, or making a general estimate of successive quotients). Also highlight the inherent inaccuracy of bounce height measurements, which, in turn, influences how accurately we should report the successive quotients. Probably no more than one significant decimal digit should be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus the discussion on the meaning of the rebound factors. Ask questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;“Does a larger factor mean that the ball is more bouncy or less bouncy?”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;”Does a larger factor mean that the heights are decreasing more quickly or more slowly?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emphasize the fact that in a situation modeled by a function \(f\) given by \(f(n)=a \cdot b^n\), the number \(b\) expresses the growth factor. In situations where \(0&amp;lt;b&amp;lt;1\), a larger value of \(b\)&amp;nbsp;means that the function decays more slowly (because more of the quantity remains). In terms of comparing the bounciness of the balls, the larger the successive quotients in the table columns, the bouncier the ball is. While all of the balls will eventually lie still on the ground, a larger successive quotient (or rebound factor) means that the bounce heights decrease more slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt; Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div style="border:1px solid black; padding:5px; background-color:#f2f2f2;"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use this routine to help students improve their writing by providing them with multiple opportunities to clarify their explanations through conversation within their group. Give students time to share their response to the question, “Explain how the equations could tell us which one is the most bouncy.” Provide listeners with prompts for feedback that will help their partner add detail to strengthen and clarify their ideas. For example, students can ask their partner, “How did you use the data in the table?” or “Can you explain the rebound factor in your equations?” Next, provide students with 3–4 minutes to revise their initial draft based on feedback from their group. This will help students produce a written generalization for how they can estimate the rebound factor and use successive quotients in a real-world exponential situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2874">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1661996611</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2875">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1661996611</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1280">
        <prevpageid>1279</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1281</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1661998126</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1663667348</timemodified>
        <title>5.11.4: Examine Exponential Decay in Context</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt; Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This activity continues to examine exponential decay in the context of successive ball bounces. Students use the given data to calculate a rebound factor and use it to write a function that models the relationship between number of bounces and bounce heights. They then use the function to answer questions about the ball and its bounces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students also think about the domain of the function and address the fact that this is a discrete context, i.e., it does not make sense to examine \(\frac23\) of a bounce, so the graphs should not be continuous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt; Support for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div style="border:1px solid black; padding:5px; background-color:#f2f2f2;"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Activate or supply background knowledge about discrete and continuous contexts. The number of bounces is counted every time the ball hits the floor. If a student asks about \(1\frac12\) bounces, clarify that would be measuring the time since the ball had been released, not the number of bounces; a “bounce” is the event of hitting the floor and changing direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table shows some heights of a ball after a certain number of bounces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="154"&gt;
        &lt;col width="133"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bounce number&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;height in centimeters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;73.5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;51.5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;36&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Is this ball more or less bouncy than the tennis ball in activity 5.11.2, which has the equation \(h=150 \cdot (0.53)^n\)? Explain or show your reasoning. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; This ball is more bouncy. Each bounce of this ball reaches a height that is about 0.7 times that of the previous bounce \((51.5 \div 73.5 \approx 0.7)\). The tennis ball in the earlier task loses about half of its height with each bounce.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; From what height was the ball dropped? Explain or show your reasoning. Remember your units! &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 150 centimeters; \(73.5 \div 0.7=105\) and \(105 \div 0.7=150\).
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Write an equation that represents the bounce height of the ball, \(h\), in centimeters after \(n\) bounces. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(9h=150 \cdot (0.7)^n\)
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Which graph would more appropriately represent the equation for \(h\): Graph A or Graph B? Explain your reasoning. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Graph B is more appropriate. Only whole-number \(n\) values make sense in this context. We cannot have bounce number 3.4, for example.&lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;ol type="A"&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/fcjAU3q2svNgycRVUHfMNNKz" alt="Graph of a function on grid, origin O. Horizontal axis, bounce number, Vertical axis, height in centimeters. Solid line crosses vertical axis and moves downwards and to the right.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/xGSyL2STfFxTMM9tH5yjow57" alt="Graph of a function on grid, origin O. Horizontal axis, bounce number, Vertical axis, height in centimeters. Dotted line crosses vertical axis and moves downwards and to the right. &amp;nbsp;"&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Will the nth bounce of this ball be lower than the nth bounce of the tennis ball? Explain your reasoning. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; No, the height of this ball after any given bounce will not be lower than that of the tennis ball because they were dropped from the same height and this ball has a greater rebound factor, so it will always bounce up to a higher point than the tennis ball.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If students struggle to make sense of the graph, remind them that the horizontal axis depicts the number of bounces, not the height of the ball or time. Although height and time are continuous, the number of bounces is discrete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite students to share how they decided on the bounciness of the balls and to reflect on their reasoning process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;“How are the data here different from the data in the first activity?” (In this case, the successive quotients are very close to the same value, making the choice of rebound factor more straightforward.) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;“When working with the table, how is calculating the missing value in the row above a given value different from calculating a missing value in the row below?” (To find the missing value in the row above, we need to divide by the rebound factor rather than multiply.) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;“In the final question, why are both the initial height and the bounciness important?” (The value of \(h\) is found by multiplying the initial height by the rebound factor \(n\) times, so both values matter.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div style="border:1px solid black; padding:5px; background-color:#f2f2f2;"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use this routine to help students reflect on their reasoning process in deciding on the bounciness of the balls. Before the whole-class discussion, arrange students in groups of 2. Provide the following sentence frames as partners share their ideas: “In the table, I noticed that . . .”; “I interpreted the successive quotients to mean . . .”; or “The equation helped determine the bounciness by . . . .” This will help students make sense of exponential decay through discussing the ball-bouncing situation with a partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt; 5.11.4: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;The population of deer in a forest is divided in half every decade. Which of the following graphs could represent this situation?&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/4ecc375fae81d430969b613cdbed81b772e704c8" alt="4ecc375fae81d430969b613cdbed81b772e704c8 (513×506)" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This graph shows an increasing linear model. The population is decreasing in a nonlinear way. The answer is &lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/05b6651962e9fe8195bb74c06444b20fd1aa92c6" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/e2ed088b53630b2221604b92225da5de51764eb4" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This graph shows a decreasing linear relationship. The population is decreasing in a nonlinear way. The answer is&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/05b6651962e9fe8195bb74c06444b20fd1aa92c6" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/d78c1c1afbc3953042d0e40268d490ffb665603f" alt="d78c1c1afbc3953042d0e40268d490ffb665603f (555×506)" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This shows an increasing relationship. The population is decreasing by a factor of \(\frac12\). The answer is&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/05b6651962e9fe8195bb74c06444b20fd1aa92c6" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/05b6651962e9fe8195bb74c06444b20fd1aa92c6" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;That’s correct! Check yourself: The population of deer will decrease over time, but the rate at which it decreases will slow down.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt; 5.11.4: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Writing Exponential Decay Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A car sells for $4,000 and loses \(\frac18\) of its value each year. Write a function that gives the car’s value, \(V(t)\), \(t\)&amp;nbsp;years after it is sold.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the car loses \(\frac18\) of its value each year, it keeps \(\frac78\) of its value from year to year, so the growth factor is \(\frac78\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(V(t)=4000 \cdot (\frac{7}{8})^t\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Writing Exponential Decay Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A computer is purchased for $1,000 and loses \(\frac15\) of its value per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a function for the computer’s value, \(V(t)\), \(t\)&amp;nbsp;years after it is purchased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to write the exponential function:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The starting amount is $1,000. The computer loses \(\frac15\) of its value each year, so it maintains \(\frac45\) of its value. The growth factor is &amp;nbsp;\(\frac45\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function is then \(V(t)=1000 \cdot (\frac{4}{5})^t\).&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2876">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1661998126</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2877">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1661998126</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1281">
        <prevpageid>1280</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1282</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1661999536</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1663667383</timemodified>
        <title>5.11.5: Using Relationship Models to Answer Questions</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Cool Down (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A ball is dropped from a certain height. The table shows the rebound heights of the ball after a series of bounces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="126"&gt;
        &lt;col width="165"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bounce number&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;height in centimeters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;30&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what height, approximately, do you think the ball was dropped? Explain your reasoning.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Sample response: Between 150 cm and 180 cm. The rebound factors are \(\frac15\), \(\frac16\), and 0 (this last measurement is probably not reliable because it could have been a very small bounce height, which would be difficult to measure). Because \(\frac15\) of 150 is 30 and \(\frac16\) of 180 is 30, the ball was probably dropped from between 150 cm and 180 cm.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Response to Student Thinking&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;More Chances&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will have more opportunities to understand the mathematical ideas in this cool-down, so there is no need to slow down or add additional work to the next lessons. Instead, use the results of this cool-down to provide guidance for what to look for and emphasize over the next several lessons to support students in advancing their current understanding.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2878">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1661999536</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2879">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1661999536</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1282">
        <prevpageid>1281</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1283</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1662000015</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1663642725</timemodified>
        <title>5.11.6: Practice </title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Students will complete the following questions to practice the skills they have learned in this lesson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For questions 1–4, use the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Function \(h\)&amp;nbsp;describes the height of a ball, in inches, after \(n\)&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;bounces and is defined by the equation \(h(n)=120 \cdot (\frac{4}{5})^n\).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        What is \(h(3)\)? Round to the nearest integer. Think about what it represents in this situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 61
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Could \(h(n)\) be 150?&amp;nbsp;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;No
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Which ball loses its height more quickly: This ball, modeled by \(h(n)=120 \cdot (\frac{4}{5})^n\), or a tennis ball whose height in inches after \(n\) bounces is modeled by the function \(f\) where \(f(n)=50 \cdot (\frac{5}{9})^n\)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;The ball modeled by \(f(n)\)
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        How many bounces would it take before the ball bounces less than 12 inches from the surface? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

    &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 11

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="5"&gt;

    &lt;li&gt;
        After a second bounce, a ball reached a height of 70 cm. The rebound factor for the ball was 0.8. From approximately what height, in cm, was the ball dropped?
        &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                560
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                56
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                21
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                88

            &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;d. 88

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="6"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Using the table below, find the height, in cm, from which the ball was dropped.

        &lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
            &lt;colgroup&gt;
                &lt;col&gt;
                &lt;col&gt;
                &lt;col&gt;
                &lt;col&gt;
                &lt;col&gt;
            &lt;/colgroup&gt;
            &lt;tbody&gt;
                &lt;tr&gt;
                    &lt;td&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of bounces&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/td&gt;
                    &lt;td&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/td&gt;
                    &lt;td&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/td&gt;
                    &lt;td&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/td&gt;
                    &lt;td&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;/tr&gt;
                &lt;tr&gt;
                    &lt;td&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Height in cm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/td&gt;
                    &lt;td&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;90&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/td&gt;
                    &lt;td&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;54&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/td&gt;
                    &lt;td&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;32&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/td&gt;
                    &lt;td&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;19&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;/tbody&gt;
        &lt;/table&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 150
&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2880">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662000015</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2881">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662000015</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1283">
        <prevpageid>1282</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1662000685</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1663618962</timemodified>
        <title>5.11.7: Lesson Synthesis  </title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;In this lesson, students explored models to represent successive bounce heights of different kinds of balls. The data they used were rather messy. Invite students to reflect on the process of modeling with such data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Were the data completely accurate? Why or why not?” (Depending on the tools used, it can be very hard to get exact measurements of rebound heights, and it gets harder the lower the bounces are. Measurement errors are likely.) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“We saw different rebound factors for different pairs of successive data points. How do we decide if an exponential model is still appropriate?” (We might want to see if the differences are small enough to treat them as measurement error. In the lesson, they are all within about 0.05 of 0.5, and most of them are close to about 0.54.) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Given the inconsistency, how do we find an appropriate factor to use for our model?” (We might disregard the factor(s) that are very different from the rest, or we might consider finding an average of the factors.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time permits, discuss possible limitations of the models. Ask questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Do the models we produce work well after 45 bounces? After 78 bounces? What about when the rebound height is less than 1 cm?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Can we rely on the models to be appropriate if we bounce the ball on a different hard surface?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“What level of accuracy should we consider? For example, is 0.5 or 0.54 more appropriate for the rebound factor?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2882">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662000685</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2883">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1662000685</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>