<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="207" moduleid="275" modulename="lesson" contextid="286">
  <lesson id="207">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Lesson 8.2 Teacher Guide: When and Why Do We Write Quadratic Equations?</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>1</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password/>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>0</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>276</activitylink>
    <mediafile/>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>0</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1667072809</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="1896">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1897</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1666132922</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1666314117</timemodified>
        <title>8.2.0: Lesson Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Narrative&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this lesson, students revisit some situations that can be modeled with quadratic functions. They analyze and interpret given equations, write equations to represent relationships and constraints, and work to solve these equations. In doing so, students see that sometimes solutions to quadratic equations cannot be easily or precisely found by graphing or reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an earlier unit, students saw that when a function is defined by a quadratic expression in factored form, the zeros of the function could be easily identified. Here, they notice that when a quadratic equation is written as factored form = 0, solving the equation is also relatively simple. This revelation motivates upcoming work on rewriting quadratic expressions into factored form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Goals (Teacher Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Recognize the limitations of certain strategies used to solve a quadratic equation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Explain that the factored form of a quadratic expression can help us find the zeros of a quadratic function and solve a quadratic equation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Write quadratic equations and reason about their solutions in terms of a situation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Targets (Student Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Recognize the factored form of a quadratic expression and know when it can be useful for solving problems. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Use a graph to find the solutions to a quadratic equation but also know its limitations. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table class="os-raise-standardtable"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TEKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation of Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;A8(A) solve quadratic equations having real solutions by factoring, taking square roots, completing the square, and applying the quadratic formula.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foundational: Lesson provides foundational content necessary for students to be able to perform this TEKS in later lessons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the instructional activities for the lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 8.2.1: Interpreting Equations in Context &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 8.2.2: Exploring Non-Graphing Strategies to Solve Quadratic Equations &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li aria-level="2"&gt; 8.2.2: Self Check &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li aria-level="2"&gt; 8.2.2: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 8.2.3: Solving a Quadratic Equation Set Equal to Zero &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li aria-level="2"&gt; 8.2.3: Self Check &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li aria-level="2"&gt; 8.2.3: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 8.2.4: Solving a Real-World Problem Using Quadratic Equations &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will also complete a series of problems in the 8.2.5: Practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Paper and pencil &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; None &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Vocabulary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this lesson, it is important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Familiarize students with the vocabulary words they will see throughout the lesson. Encourage students to look for these words and notice their use and meanings. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Encourage students to use key vocabulary words in &amp;ldquo;math talk&amp;rdquo; and their written and oral explanations. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Utilize a word wall. Sample cards are located here: &lt;a href="https://www.doe.virginia.gov/instruction/mathematics/resources/vocab_cards/" target="_blank"&gt;Mathematics Vocabulary Word Wall Cards&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary words that are emphasized in this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="os-raise-standardtable"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; quadratic function &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; quadratic equation &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; factored form (of a quadratic expression) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; zero of the function &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; none &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Support for Building Character&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, find ways to encourage and support students to work on cultivating their &lt;strong&gt;curiosity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to try during this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/space-to-learn/" target="_blank"&gt;Space to Learn&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/change-is-good/" target="_blank"&gt;Change Is Good&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other tips located here in the &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/playbooks/curiosity/" target="_blank"&gt;Playbook on Curiosity&lt;/a&gt; from Character Lab.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4259">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666132922</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1897">
        <prevpageid>1896</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1898</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1666133434</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1666503738</timemodified>
        <title>8.2.1: Interpreting Equations in Context</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Warm Up (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This warm up activates what students know about interpreting equations in context and about solving for a variable. The given equation is linear and is relatively straightforward. The work prepares students to reason about quadratic equations in the lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find the unknown input in each question, students might:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Try different values of \(t\) until they find one that yields the specified value of \(c\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Reason backward (subtract 2.5 from 62.50 and then divide the result by 12) without writing out the steps. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Solve \(62.5 = 12t + 2.5\) and \(278.5 = 12t + 2.5\) by performing the same operation to each side to isolate \(t\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the problem aloud to the class. Allow the students to answer the exercises individually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Ticket stubs" height="258" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/4c2ff88a8ad938c925c3489dbf177ecda8d6e508" width="388"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets to a play cost $12, and for each purchase there is a $2.50 fee. The expression \(12t + 2.50\) represents the cost to purchase tickets for the play, where \(t\) is the number of tickets. Be prepared to explain your response to each question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A family paid $62.50 for tickets. How many tickets were bought?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Five tickets were bought. Subtracting 2.50 from 62.50 gives 60. If \(12t\) is 60, then \(t\) is 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A teacher paid $278.50 for tickets for her students. How many tickets were bought?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;Twenty-three tickets were bought. Subtracting 2.50 from 278.50 gives 276. If \(12t\) is 276, then \(t\) is 23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students to share their responses and reasoning. Highlight the different strategies used to answer the questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If no students thought of the situation in terms of a function and wrote an equation, point out that we can think about cost as being a function of the number of tickets. In answering the questions, we were looking for the inputs that produce different outputs. This can be done by solving equations. In the case of linear equations, we can &amp;ldquo;do the same thing to each side&amp;rdquo; to isolate the variable.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4260">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666133434</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4261">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666133434</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1898">
        <prevpageid>1897</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1899</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1666134552</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1666463190</timemodified>
        <title>8.2.2: Exploring Non-Graphing Strategies to Solve Quadratic Equations  </title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This task prompts students to try different ways to solve a quadratic equation. They are familiar with solving equations by performing the same operation to each side of an equation, but here they see that this is not really a workable strategy. Students are also discouraged from using a graph to solve the equation. Because they do not yet know an efficient way to use algebra to solve \(-16t^2 + 80t + 64 = 0\), they need to try different strategies and persevere in problem solving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As students work, notice those who use strategies listed in the Activity Synthesis. Ask them to share their approach during discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of two. Give them a few minutes of quiet think time and then time to collaborate on solving the equations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No graphing technology should be used in this activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a previous lesson, you saw an equation that defines the height of a potato as a function of time after it was launched from a mechanical device. Here is a different function modeling the height of a potato, in feet, \(t\) seconds after being fired from a different device:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(f(t) = -16t^2 + 80t + 64\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What equation would we solve to find the time at which the potato hits the ground?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;\(-16t^2 + 80t + 64 = 0\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the potato hits the ground at a height of 0 feet, set the equation equal to 0. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use any method except graphing to find a solution to the equation from the previous question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;An approximate solution is about 5.7 seconds by using trial and error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poll the class on their solutions to the equation and record and display the solutions for all to see. Then, ask some students to share their strategies and any associated challenges. If not mentioned by students, discuss the limitations of these approaches:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Isolating the variable: If we try to solve by performing the same operation to each side of the equation, we quickly get stuck. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Original equation&lt;br&gt;
    \(-16t^2 + 80t + 64 = 0\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subtract 64 from each side.&lt;br&gt;
    \(-16t^2 + 80t = -64\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Divide each side by &amp;ndash;16.&lt;br&gt;
    \(t^2 - 5t = 4\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then what? If we add \(5t\) to each side, we now have a variable on both sides and&amp;nbsp;cannot combine any like terms. We could multiply or divide each side by any constant&amp;nbsp;we wish, but we are no closer to isolating \(t\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Guessing and checking: We can evaluate the quadratic expression at different values of \(t\) until the expression has a value that is 0 or close to 0. For example, when \(t\) is 4, the expression has a value of 128. At \(t = 5\), it has a value of 64, and at \(t = 6\), it has a value of &amp;ndash;32. That means \(t\) is between 5 and 6, so we need to try different decimal values in that range.
        This process is laborious, and it may not get us to a precise solution. This can be true of guessing and checking for many different quadratic equations. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Graphing: Students may suggest that a graph would allow them to solve the problem much more quickly. Use graphing technology to demonstrate that if we graph the equation \(y = f(t)\), an approximate solution given is 5.702, as shown in the image. If we evaluate \(f(5.702)\), however, we get roughly &amp;ndash;0.044864, rather than exactly 0. A graph is useful for approximating values, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t always possible to use it to find exact values. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height="308" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/ff700614bbdfeb5fdbc4259bee73ba542dd689d3" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell students that in this unit they will learn some efficient strategies for solving equations like these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;8.2.2: Self Check&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="left"&gt;
&lt;table class="os-raise-standardtable"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="302"&gt;
&lt;col width="322"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a flashlight is turned on, it gets brighter as it warms up, and then it grows dimmer as the battery dies. The equation modeling the brightness it emits, in lumens, \(h\) hours after being turned on is shown here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(f(h) = -8h^2 + 30h + 50\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which equation would you solve to determine when the flashlight dies and stops emitting lumens?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(-8h^2 + 30h - 50 = 0\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This equation does not represent when the flashlight dies. The sign on 50 should not have been reversed. The answer is \(-8h^2 + 30h + 50 = 0\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(8h^2 + 30h + 50 = 0\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This equation does not represent when the flashlight dies. The sign on \(8h^2\) should not have been reversed. The answer is \(-8h^2 + 30h + 50 = 0\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(-8h^2 + 30h = 50\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This equation does not represent when the flashlight dies. The answer is \(-8h^2 + 30h + 50 = 0\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(-8h^2 + 30h + 50 = 0\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: By setting the equation equal to 0, we are representing the time when the flashlight is no longer emitting any light (0 lumens).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;8.2.2: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Using Various Methods to Solve Quadratic Equations&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tennis ball is thrown out of the window of a building. The equation modeling the height of the tennis ball, in feet, \(t\) seconds after being thrown is shown here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(f(t) = -24t^2 + 33t + 30\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s find the equation we would solve to find the time at which the ball hits the ground.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the ball hits the ground, its height will be 0. So, we set the equation to 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(-24t^2 + 33t + 30 = 0\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The equation above represents the ball when it hits the ground. The solution to this equation represents the time it takes from when the ball is thrown for it to hit the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s try to solve the equation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 1&lt;br&gt;
    Write the equation to be solved.&lt;br&gt;
    \(-24t^2 + 33t + 30 = 0\) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 2&lt;br&gt;
    Subtract 30 from each side of the equation.&lt;br&gt;
    \(-24t^2 + 33t = -30\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 3&lt;br&gt;
    Divide each side of the equation by 3.&lt;br&gt;
    \(-8t^2 + 11t = -10\) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s try to solve the remaining equation using guess and check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When \(t = 3\), the expression \(-8t^2 + 11t\) has a value of \(-8(3)^2 + 11(3)\), or \(-39\). This value is not equal to the \(-10\) we needed to find.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When \(t = 2\), the expression \(-8t^2 + 11t\) has a value of \(-8(2)^2 + 11(2)\), or \(-10\). This value is equal to the \(-10\) we needed to find.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The equation is true when \(t = 2\), so the ball took 2 seconds to hit the ground. This method works but can be more difficult when the solution is a decimal. Graphing can also work, but it is time consuming and results in an approximate solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Using Various Methods to Solve Quadratic Equations&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An arc of water flows from a water fountain down to a pool below it. The height of the arc above the pool, in inches, can be modeled using the equation \(f(x) = -2x^2 + 5x + 3\), where \(x\) is the horizontal distance the water has traveled, in inches, from the water fountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which equation would you solve to determine how far the arc of water has traveled horizontally when it reaches the pool below?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solve the equation using a non-graphing method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answers, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to write and solve the equation representing the arc of water from the water fountain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The equation \(-2x^2 + 5x + 3 = 0\) represents the arc of the water when it reaches the pool below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To solve the equation \(-2x^2 + 5x + 3 = 0\), let&amp;rsquo;s try using guess and check with substitution.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we try \(x = 2\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(-2(2)^2+5(2)+3\overset?=0\) &lt;br&gt;
    \(5 \neq 0\) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s try \(x = 3\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(-2(3)^2+5(3)+3\overset?=0\)&lt;br&gt;
    \(0 = 0\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the equation is true, \(x = 3\) is correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arc of water has traveled 3 inches horizontally when it reaches the pool below the fountain.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4262">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666134552</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4263">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666134552</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1899">
        <prevpageid>1898</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1900</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1666136363</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1666705880</timemodified>
        <title>8.2.3: Solving a Quadratic Equation Set Equal to Zero </title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This activity aims to show that it is relatively easy to solve a quadratic equation when one side of the equation is zero and the other side is a quadratic expression in factored form, and that it may be a little tricky to solve the equation otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The activity prompts students to recall what they learned in an earlier unit: The zeros of a function correspond to the horizontal intercepts of the graph representing that function, and the zeros are the solutions to an equation of the form quadratic expression \(= 0\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep students in groups of two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the opening paragraph in the task statement. Give students a moment to think about how much the school would collect if it sells the tickets at $5 each (it would collect $875). Briefly survey how they found out the answer. (Students are likely to have used the factored form because it lends itself to simpler calculations.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students to recall the form in which each quadratic expression is written. Then, give them a minute to talk to a partner and recall at least two things about each form and what the form might tell us about the graph of the function that the expression defines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Record their responses for all to see. If no students mentioned the connection between either of the forms to the horizontal intercepts of the graph or the zeros of the function, ask them about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell students that they do not need to find the ticket prices in the second question, but only to think about how to go about doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expressions \(p(200 &amp;minus; 5p)\) and \(-5p^2 + 200p\) define the same function. The function models the revenue a school would earn from selling raffle tickets at \(p\) dollars each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At what price or prices would the school collect $0 revenue from raffle sales? Explain or show your reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; $0 and $40. For example, if the equation \(p(200&amp;minus;5p)=0\) is true, then either \(p\) is equal to 0, or \(200&amp;minus;5p\) is equal to 0. If \(200&amp;minus;5p=0\), then \(p\) is 40, because \(200&amp;minus;5(40)\) is 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The school staff noticed that there are two ticket prices that would result in a revenue of $500. What equation could you use to determine what those two prices are?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; We could write \(p(200 &amp;minus; 5p) = 500\) and \(-5p^2 + 200p = 500\). Approximate solutions can be found using trial and error or graphing. However, we don&amp;rsquo;t yet know an exact way to solve either equation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Extension&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Are you ready for more?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you find the following prices without graphing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; If the school charges $10, it will collect $1500 in revenue. Find another price that would generate $1500 in revenue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;$30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving the same distance away from each horizontal intercept, at $0 and $40, results in equal revenue. This means $10 and $30 earn an equal amount of revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the school charges $28, it will collect $1680 in revenue. Find another price that would generate $1680 in revenue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;$12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving the same distance away from each horizontal intercept, at $0 and $40, results in equal revenue. This means $12 and $28 earn an equal amount of revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the price that would produce the maximum possible revenue. Explain your reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;$20. Moving the same distance away from each horizontal intercept results in equal revenue. The farther away we move from one horizontal intercept in the direction of the other intercept, the greater the revenue. An optimal ticket price of $20, producing $2000 in revenue, is found in the middle point between the two intercepts, at \(p = 20\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If students struggle to connect the expressions that define the function to the questions, ask them what the input and output of the function represent. If students struggle with the first question, ask them what values of \(p\) would yield a value of 0 for the expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite students to share their responses and strategies. Make sure students see that the first question can be represented by solving the equation \(p(200 &amp;minus; 5p) = 0\), and that the second question can be represented by solving either \(p(200 &amp;minus; 5p) = 500\) or \(-5p^2 + 200p = 500\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although students are not yet formally introduced to the zero product property, they do have experience with finding the zeros of a quadratic function when given an expression in factored form. This prior knowledge enables them to reason about the solutions to the equation \(p(200 &amp;minus; 5p) = 0\). For instance, noticing the factor \(p\), students are likely to say that one zero of the function is 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How can you show, without graphing, that \(p = 0\) will produce no revenue, or that it is a solution to the equation \(p(200 &amp;minus; 5p) = 0\)?&amp;rdquo; (When \(p = 0\), the factor \(p\) is 0, and therefore the entire expression equals 0.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How can you show that \(p = 40\) will also produce no revenue, or that it is also a solution to the same equation?&amp;rdquo; (When \(p = 40\), the factor \((200 &amp;minus; 5p)\) is 0, and likewise, the entire expression is 0.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Can we use the same reasoning to find the solutions to \(p(200 &amp;minus; 5p) = 500\) or \(-5p^2 + 200p = 500\)? Why or why not?&amp;rdquo; (No, not easily. Neither shows the zeros of a function. There are many pairs of factors that have 500 as a product.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure students see that it is fairly straightforward to find the solutions to equations such as \(p(200 &amp;minus; 5p) = 0\), but the same cannot be said about equations such as \(p(200 &amp;minus; 5p) = 500\) or \(-5p^2+ 200p = 500\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlight that all the equations in this activity are quadratic equations. Reinforce that a quadratic equation is one that can be written in the form of \(ax^2 + bx + c = 0\), where \(a\) is not 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time permits, ask students to show how all of the equations seen here can be written in this form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Video: Solving a Quadratic Equation Set Equal to Zero&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the following video to learn more about solving a quadratic equation set equal to zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls="true" crossorigin="anonymous" width="550"&gt;
&lt;source src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/77882d2deb7924f80889f50875df2021952a9ba1"&gt;
&lt;track default="true" kind="captions" label="On" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/62f15f9597649cfd5b15f201948fe21c6af899d3" srclang="en_us"&gt;https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/77882d2deb7924f80889f50875df2021952a9ba1
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;8.2.3: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="os-raise-standardtable"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="312"&gt;
&lt;col width="312"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expressions \(s(60 &amp;minus; 12s)\) and \(-122 + 60s\) define the same function. A soap bubble machine can launch many soap bubbles into the air before they begin to pop. The function given models the number of soap bubbles floating in the air in \(s\) seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the function, how many seconds have passed before all of the bubbles have been made and also popped?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: At 0 seconds, there are no bubbles. However, the bubbles have not been made and popped yet. The answer is 5 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: The time passed when all of the bubbles are popped is represented by the equation \(s(60 &amp;minus; 12s) = 0\). Substitute 5 in for \(s\) to check your answer. Since \((5)(60 - 12(5)) = 0\), the answer is correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: Solve the equation \(s(60 &amp;minus; 12s) = 0\) to find the solution. Do this by setting the factor \(60 &amp;minus; 12s\) equal to 0 and solving to find the nonzero solution. The answer is 5 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: Solve the equation \(s(60 &amp;minus; 12s) = 0\) to find the solution. Do this by setting the factor \(60 &amp;minus; 12s\) equal to 0 and solving to find the nonzero solution. The answer is 5 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;8.2.3: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expressions \(h(40 &amp;minus; 10h)\) and \(-10h^2 + 40h\) define the same function. The function models the height of a weather balloon in miles \(h\) hours after it is released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What equation can be used to determine the times the weather balloon is on the ground?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; When the weather balloon is on the ground, the expression will equal 0. So, the equation \(h(40 &amp;minus; 10h) = 0\) represents the weather balloon when it is on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can we solve the equation \(h(40 &amp;minus; 10h) = 0\)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; We know that any value multiplied by 0 equals 0. So, if \(h\) or \((40 - 10h)\) equals 0, then the left side of the equation will also equal 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather balloon is on the ground at 0 hours. Now, let&amp;rsquo;s find the solution to \(40 - 10h = 0\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(40 - 10h = 0\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(40 = 10h\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(4 = h\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather balloon is also on the ground after 4 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A scientist wants to determine the two different times when the weather balloon is 30 miles above Earth. Write an equation to represent these times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;The times when the weather balloon is 30 miles above Earth are represented by the equation \(h(40 &amp;minus; 10h) = 30\) or the equation \(-10h^2 + 40h = 30\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the weather balloon is 30 miles above Earth after 1 hour, find another time that the weather balloon is 30 miles above Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; We know the total trip takes the weather balloon 4 hours. Since the graph representing the flight of the weather balloon is symmetric, if it takes 1 hour to reach 30 miles up, then 1 hour from touching the ground, it will be at 30 miles up again. So, the weather balloon will be 30 miles above Earth after 3 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Solving a Quadratic Equation Set Equal to Zero&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expressions \(p(420 &amp;minus; 60p)\) and \(-60p^2 + 420p\) define the same function. The function models revenue earned at a baseball game from the sale of baseball magazines sold at \(p\) dollars each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At what price or prices would the game organizers collect $0 revenue from magazine sales? Explain or show your reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The organizers determined there are two magazine prices that would result in a revenue of $600. What equation would you use to determine what those two prices are?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answers, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to use your knowledge of quadratic equations to solve the problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$0 and $7. If the equation \(p(420 &amp;minus; 60p) = 0\) is true, then either \(p\) is equal to 0, or \(420 &amp;minus; 60p\) is equal to 0. If \(420 &amp;minus; 60p = 0\), then \(p\) is 7, because \(420 &amp;minus; 60(7)\) is 0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We could write \(p(420 &amp;minus; 60p) = 600\) or \(-60p^2 + 420p = 600\). We can use trial and error or graphing to provide approximate solutions. We do not yet know an exact method to solve either equation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4264">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666136363</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4265">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666136363</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1900">
        <prevpageid>1899</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1901</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1666137648</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1666276293</timemodified>
        <title>8.2.4: Solving a Real-World Problem Using Quadratic Equations</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt; Cool Down (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No graphing technology should be used in this cool down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A movie theater models the revenue from ticket sales in one day as a function of the ticket price, \(p\). Here are two expressions defining the same revenue function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(p(120 &amp;minus; 4p)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(120p &amp;minus; 4p^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to this model, how high would the ticket price have to be for the theater to make $0 in revenue? Explain your reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; $30. If \(p(120 &amp;minus; 4p) = 0\), then either \(p = 0\) or \(120 &amp;minus; 4p = 0\). If the latter is a true equation, \(p\) must be 30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What equation can you write to find out what ticket price(s) would allow the theater to make $600 in revenue?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(p(120&amp;minus;4p) = 600\) or \(120p &amp;minus; 4p^2 = 600\)&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4266">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666137648</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4267">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666137648</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1901">
        <prevpageid>1900</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1902</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1666137879</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1666276569</timemodified>
        <title>8.2.5: Practice</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Students will complete the following questions to practice the skills they have learned in this lesson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The expression \(t + 7.25\) represents the cost to purchase tickets for a concert, where \(t\) is the number of tickets. A group of friends paid $79.25 for tickets. How many tickets were bought?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 6 tickets &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 8 tickets &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 10 tickets &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 12 tickets &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 8 tickets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the following to answer questions 2&amp;ndash;4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A model rocket is launched from a launchpad. The function modeling the height of the rocket, in feet, \(t\) seconds after being launched is shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(f(t) = -15t^2 + 58t + 8\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which equation would you solve to find the time at which the rocket hits the ground?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(-15t^2 + 58t + 8 = 0\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(-15t^2 + 58t = 8\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(-15t^2 + 58t = 0\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(15t^2 + 58t + 8 = 0\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(-15t^2 + 58t + 8 = 0\) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a non-graphing method to find the solution to the previous equation to determine the time that has passed when the rocket hits the ground.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 2 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 3 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 5 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 4 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How high off the ground is the launchpad from which the rocket lifts off?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 0 feet &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 2 feet &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 8 feet &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 15 feet &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 8 feet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the following to answer questions 5&amp;ndash;8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expressions \(t(90 &amp;minus; 3t)\) and \(-3t^2 + 90t\) define the same function. The function models the number of lumens emitted by a spotlight in an art exhibit over the course of \(t\) seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="5"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which equation represents the time when the spotlight is not emitting any light?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(t(90 &amp;minus; 3t) = -3t^2 + 90t\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(-3t^2 + 90t = 675\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(-3t^2 + 90t = 0\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(-3t^2 + 90t = 30\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(-3t^2 + 90t = 0\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="6"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At what time(s) does the spotlight not emit any light?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 0 and 30 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 10 and 25 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only 0 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 15 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 0 and 30 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="7"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The artist planned for the spotlight to emit 600 lumens at 10 seconds from the start. At what other time will the spotlight emit 600 lumens of light?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 0 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 20 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 25 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 30 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 20 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="8"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At 5 seconds, the spotlight will emit 375 lumens. Find another time that the spotlight emits 375 lumens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 0 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 10 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 15 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 25 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 25 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the following to answer questions 9 and 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bowling alley models the revenue from sales in one day as a function of the cost to rent a lane per hour, \(c\). Here are two expressions defining the same revenue function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(c(160 &amp;minus; 10c)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(160c &amp;minus; 10^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="9"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to this model, how high would the cost to rent a lane have to be for the bowling alley to make $0 in revenue?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; $8 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; $10 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; $14 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; $16 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; $16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="10"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What equation can you write to determine the lane cost that would allow the bowling alley to make $640 in revenue?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\( c(160 &amp;minus; 10c) = 0\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\( c(160 &amp;minus; 10c) = 640\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\( 160c &amp;minus; 10c^2 + 640 = 0\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\( 160c &amp;minus; 10c^2 = 0\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(c(160 &amp;minus; 10c) = 640\)&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4268">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666137879</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4269">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666137879</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1902">
        <prevpageid>1901</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1666138793</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1666314317</timemodified>
        <title>8.2.6: Lesson Synthesis</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;Help students reflect on the key ideas of the lesson by discussing, as a class or with a partner, questions such as the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What are some limitations of solving \(-2x^2 &amp;minus; 2x + 40 = 10\) by guessing and checking? What about by graphing?&amp;rdquo; (Sample answer: If the solution is not an integer, then it will be difficult to find the solution. Graphing will also not produce an exact solution, only an estimate.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Which equation do you think is easier to solve: \(-2x^2 &amp;minus; 2x + 40 = 0\) or \((8 &amp;minus; 2x)(x + 5) = 0\)? Why?&amp;rdquo; (Sample answer: The equation in factored form is easier to solve since the equation is set equal to 0. The zeros, or solutions, are easier to identify.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Which appears easier to solve: \((8 &amp;minus; 2x)(x + 5) = 10\) or \(-2x^2 &amp;minus; 2x + 40 = 10\)? Why?&amp;rdquo; (Sample answer: They are both difficult to solve. The factors in the factored form are not equal to zero on their own. The equation \(-2x^2 &amp;minus; 2x + 40 = 10\) is one step closer to solving mathematically, if we can figure out a way to factor it.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4270">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666138793</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4271">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666138793</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>
