<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="103" moduleid="137" modulename="lesson" contextid="148">
  <lesson id="103">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Lesson 4.12 Teacher Guide: Domain and Range, Part 2</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>1</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password/>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>0</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>0</activitylink>
    <mediafile/>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>1</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1662773335</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="937">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>938</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659577910</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662754930</timemodified>
        <title>4.12.0: Lesson Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Narrative&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, students reasoned about the domain and range of a function based on descriptions about the situation it represents, or from a rule that defines the function. In this lesson, students use graphs to learn about the domain and range of functions, while continuing to think about what values are reasonable in the given situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students learn to look for graphical features that would help them identify restrictions to the input or output. For example, they recognize that maximums and minimums, intercepts, and gaps on the graph can be quite informative. They also see that discrete points or breaks in a graph suggest that not all values can be in the domain or range, and that a graph may only partially represent a function. The work here offers opportunities to look for and make use of structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As they examine graphs against situations and vice versa, students practice making sense of quantities and reasoning concretely and abstractly. When describing domain and range, students also practice attending to precision by minding relevant details in the graphs and descriptions of functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In upcoming lessons, students will learn about piecewise functions and absolute value functions. The work here prepares them to make sense of the quantities in those functions, where the dependent variable behaves differently for different parts of the domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced preparation, which includes data collection and organization, is needed for an upcoming lesson on absolute value functions. See Required Preparation for Absolute Value Functions (Part 1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Goals (Teacher Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Given a description of a function that represents a situation, determine reasonable domain and range. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Practice interpreting key features of graphs in terms of the quantities represented. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Targets (Student Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine a reasonable domain and range for the function when given a description of a function in a situation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TEKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation of Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;A2(A) determine the domain and range of a linear function in mathematical problems; determine reasonable domain and range values for real-world situations, both continuous and discrete; and represent domain and range using inequalities;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Full coverage: Lesson provides content that covers all parts of this TEKS.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the instructional activities for the lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.12.1: Different Features of a Graph &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.12.2: Graphs of Functions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.12.2: Self Check &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.12.2: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.12.3: Finding Domain and Range Using a Graph &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.12.3: Self Check &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.12.3: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.12.4: Real-World Domain and Range &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.12.4: Self Check &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.12.4: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 4.12.5: Graph of a Function and the Domain and Range Connection &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will also complete a series of problems in the 4.12.6: Practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/572557fb9ba435a95a66d99e4e8cbd8ca84bd562" target="_blank"&gt;4.12 Graph Handout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy graph handout for each student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Vocabulary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this lesson, it is important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Familiarize students with the vocabulary words they will see throughout the lesson. Encourage students to look for these words and notice their use and meanings. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Encourage students to use key vocabulary words in &amp;ldquo;math talk&amp;rdquo; and their written and oral explanations. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Utilize a word wall. Sample cards are located here: &lt;a href="https://www.doe.virginia.gov/instruction/mathematics/resources/vocab_cards/" target="_blank"&gt;Mathematics Vocabulary Word Wall Cards&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary words that are emphasized in this lesson include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; domain &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; range &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; function &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; discrete function &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; continuous function &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Support for Building Character&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, find ways to encourage and support students to work on cultivating their &lt;strong&gt;creativity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to try during this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/compound-interest/" target="_blank"&gt;Compound Interest&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/free-your-mind/" target="_blank"&gt;Free Your Mind&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other tips located here in the &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/playbooks/creativity/" target="_blank"&gt;Playbook on Creativity&lt;/a&gt; from Character Lab.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2099">
            <jumpto>0</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659577910</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2100">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659577910</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="938">
        <prevpageid>937</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>939</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659578064</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662594493</timemodified>
        <title>4.12.1: Different Features of a Graph</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Warm Up (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This warm-up prompts students to carefully analyze and compare the properties of four graphs. Each graph represents a function, but no labels or scales are shown on the coordinate axes, so students need to look for and make use of the structure of the graphs in determining how each one is like or unlike the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In making comparisons, students have a reason to use language precisely, especially mathematical terms that describe features of graphs or properties of functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on their background knowledge, students may need help understanding what is happening in graph B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which one doesn&amp;rsquo;t belong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A graph with origin O. The graph is a line crossing the vertical axis and slants downward to cross the horizontal axis." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/mTk7GYNw484bih1Tu9Tu2BNo"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/Tr91sPVtGHMxeq1xLdAWjqQr"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A graph with origin O. The graph is a horizontal line passing through the middle of the vertical axis." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/QBPUeCfRXYbfqRRAE8omULmo"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A graph." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/cZB8PuZVR812krNdAbrAvkLi"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Graph A is the only graph that has a positive vertical intercept and a positive horizontal intercept. It is the only one that has a constant, negative rate of change. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Graph B is the only graph that is not a continuous curve and has multiple pieces. It is the only one that shows both points and lines. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Graph C is the only graph that has a constant \(y\)-value. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Graph D is the only graph whose \(y\)-value increases and decreases multiple times. It is the only graph that is not a simple line or curve and that has wave-like features. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask each group to share one reason why a particular item does not belong. Record and display the responses for all to see. Encourage students to use relevant mathematical vocabulary in their explanations, and ask students to explain the meaning of any terminology that they do use, such as &amp;ldquo;intercepts,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;minimum,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;linear functions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After each response, ask the class if they agree or disagree. Since there is no single correct answer to the question of which one does not belong, attend to students&amp;rsquo; explanations and ensure the reasons given are correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now students are well aware that certain features of a graph have special significance in that they tell us something about the quantities or relationships in the situation. Tell students that features of graphs can also help us understand the domain and range of a function. We will explore this in the lesson.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2101">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659578064</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2102">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659578064</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="939">
        <prevpageid>938</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>940</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659578632</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662594664</timemodified>
        <title>4.12.2: Graphs of Functions</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (20 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this activity, students are given the same four graphs they saw in the warm-up and four descriptions of functions and are asked to match them. All of the functions share the same context. Students then use these features to reason about the likely domain and range of each function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make the matches, students analyze and interpret features of the graphs, looking for and making use of structure in the situation and in the graph. Here are some possible ways students may reason about each match:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The swing goes up and down while the child is swinging, so D could be a graph for function \(h\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The time left on the swing decreases as the time on the swing increases, so A is a possible graph for function \(r\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The distance of the child from the top beam of the swing doesn&amp;rsquo;t change as long as the child is on the swing, so C is a possible graph for function \(d\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The total number of times the swing is pushed must be a counting number and cannot be fractional. Graph B has multiple pieces, and each one could represent the total number of pushes for certain intervals of time, so B is a possible graph of function \(s\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students reason quantitatively and abstractly as they connect verbal and graphical representations of functions and as they think about the domain and range of each function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students to imagine a child getting on a swing, swinging for 30 seconds, and then getting off the swing. Explain that they will look at four functions that can be found in this situation. Their job is to match verbal descriptions and graphs that define the same functions, and then to think about reasonable domain and range for each function. Tell students they will need additional information for the last question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2. Give students a few minutes of quiet time to think about the first two questions and then time to discuss their thinking with their partner. Follow with a whole-class discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite students to share their matching decisions and explanations as to how they know each pair of representations belongs together. Make sure that students can offer an explanation for each match, including for their last pair (other than because the description and the graph are the only pair left). See some possible explanations in the Activity Narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, ask students to share the points that they think would be helpful for determining the domain and range of each function. (Students are to mark these on their handout of graphs.) If students gesture to the intercepts, a maximum, or a minimum on a graph but do not use those terms to refer to points, ask them to use mathematical terms to clarify what they mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the information students will need for question 3. Display it for all to see, or provide it as requested. If the requested information is not shown or cannot be reasoned from what is available, ask students to request a different piece of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The child is given 30 seconds on the swing. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; While the child is on the swing, an adult pushes the swing a total of 5 times. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The swing is 1.5 feet (18 inches) above ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The chains that hold the seat and suspend it from the top beam are 7 feet long. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The highest point that the child swings up to is 4 feet above the ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time is limited, ask each partner to choose two functions (different from their partner&amp;rsquo;s) and write the domain and range for only those functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Use this routine to support whole-class discussion as students explain how they matched the function description to the graph. Display the following sentence frames for all to see: &amp;ldquo;_____ matches the graph _____ because . . .&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;I noticed _____, so . . . .&amp;rdquo; Encourage students to challenge each other when they disagree. The sentence frames will help students consider the domain and range of functions as they connect written descriptions with graphical representations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use color coding and annotations to highlight connections between representations in a problem. For example, invite students to highlight the input in each description using one color, label the horizontal axis of each graph, and highlight the label in the same color. Then they can repeat the process for the outputs and the vertical axes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Student-Facing Statement &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A child gets on a swing in a playground, swings for 30 seconds, and then gets off the swing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Here are descriptions of four functions in the situation and four graphs representing them.
    The independent variable in each function is time, measured in seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A girl on a swing.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/2EfqvzexVsWAUzUAyZXPjQQQ" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Match each function with a graph that could represent it. Then, label the axes with the appropriate variables. Be prepared to explain how you make your matches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Function \(h\): The height of the swing, in feet, as a function of time since the child gets on the swing &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Function \(r\): The amount of time left on the swing as a function of time since the child gets on the swing &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Function \(d\): The distance, in feet, of the swing from the top beam (from which the swing is suspended) as a function of time since the child gets on the swing &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Function \(s\): The total number of times an adult pushes the swing as a function of time since the child gets on the swing &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A graph with origin O. The graph is a line crossing the vertical axis and slants downward to cross the horizontal axis." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/mTk7GYNw484bih1Tu9Tu2BNo"&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/Tr91sPVtGHMxeq1xLdAWjqQr"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A graph with origin O. The graph is a horizontal line passing through the middle of the vertical axis." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/QBPUeCfRXYbfqRRAE8omULmo"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A graph." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/cZB8PuZVR812krNdAbrAvkLi"&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; On each graph, mark one or two points that&amp;mdash;if you have the coordinates&amp;mdash;could help you determine the domain and range of the function. Be prepared to explain why you chose those points. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Once you receive the information you need from your teacher, describe the domain and range that would be reasonable for each function in this situation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Function \(h\): Graph D; horizontal axis: time (seconds); vertical axis: height (feet) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Function \(r\): Graph A; horizontal axis: time (seconds); vertical axis: time (seconds) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Function \(d\): Graph C; horizontal axis: time (seconds); vertical axis: distance (feet) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Function \(s\): Graph B; horizontal axis: time (seconds); vertical axis: number of pushes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Answers vary, but students are likely to choose the vertical and horizontal intercepts and the maximum and minimum points. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Sample response: The domain for all functions is time in seconds, so they include all numbers from 0 to 30. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Function \(h\): The range includes all numbers from 1.5 to 4. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Function \(r\): The range includes all numbers from 0 to 30. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Function \(d\): The range includes only one value, 7. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Function \(s\): The range includes only whole numbers from 0 to 5. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some students may struggle to match the descriptions and the graphs because they confuse the independent and dependent variables and think that, in each situation, time is represented by the vertical axis. Encourage them to reread the activity statement, clarify the input and output in each situation, label the horizontal graph with the input, and then try interpreting the graphs again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select students to share the domain and range for each function and their reasoning. Record and display their responses for all to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One key point to highlight is that the range of a function could be a single value (say 7, as shown in graph C), a bunch of isolated values (say, only some whole numbers, as shown in graph B), all values in an interval (say, all values from 1.5 to 4, as shown in graph D, or all values between 0 and 30, as in graph A), or a combination of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain of a function may also be limited in similar ways. Tell students that, in upcoming lessons, we will look at functions in which the rules relating their input and output are a bit more complex, so their domain and range are also a bit more complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.12.2: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="302"&gt;
&lt;col width="322"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which of the following is true about the range of the graph below?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/LU8LEDyHe9Qdz21F2PqbXeD2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;The range of this function includes all values that are at least 0 and no more than 70.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This describes the domain values of the graph. The answer is the range of this function includes all values that are at least 10 and at most 75.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;The range of this function includes all values that are at least 0 and no more than 90.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This describes the window of the graph, not the range. The answer is the range of this function includes all values that are at least 10 and at most 75.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;The range of this function includes all values that are at least 10 and at most 75.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: The minimum \(y\)-value of the graph is 10, and the maximum \(y\)-value of the graph is 75.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;The range of this function only includes 10 and 75.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This describes the minimum and maximum values of the range of the graph, but the range includes many more between these values. The answer is the range of this function includes all values that are at least 10 and at most 75.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.12.2: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Describing Domain and Range Graphs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a previous lesson, you explored the height, \(h\), of a bungee jumper at \(t\) seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/LU8LEDyHe9Qdz21F2PqbXeD2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming the jump ended at 35 seconds, what is the domain?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For domain, consider the \(x\)-values, so look from left to right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leftmost \(x\)-value is 0, and the rightmost \(x\)-value is 35.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain includes all the values from at least 0 up to and including 35 meters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the values in the range?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the range, consider the \(y\)-values, so look from bottom to top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lowest \(y\)-value is 10, and the highest \(y\)-value is about 75.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the range includes all of the values from at least 10 up to about 75.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Try It: Describing Domain and Range Graphs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the values of the domain and range using the graph below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graph of curve. Horizontal axis, 0 to 4, time, seconds. Vertical axis, 0 to 25 by 5&amp;rsquo;s, height, meters. Curve goes through labeled point 0 comma 20, 1 comma 25, and 3 point 2 comma 0." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/bpLy9uEJvcT4F63rcSwWQZ2U"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your notebook, write down your answer. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt; Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to find the domain and range values of this function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the domain, consider the \(x\)-values on the graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain includes all of the values from at least 0 through and including 3.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the range, consider the \(y\)-values on the graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The range includes all of the values from at least 0 through and including 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did you do? Know that you learn more from wrong answers than from right answers! Wrong answers help us find flaws in our thinking. Take a minute to think about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you got the question wrong. Then you won&amp;rsquo;t get this type of question wrong again!&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2103">
            <jumpto>0</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659578632</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2104">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659578632</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="940">
        <prevpageid>939</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>941</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659642435</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662594704</timemodified>
        <title>4.12.3: Finding Domain and Range Using a Graph</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (10 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this activity, students continue to interpret a graph of a function in terms of a situation and relate the features of the graph to the domain and range of the function. The context is a familiar one, allowing students to focus their reasoning on domain and range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike in the activity about a child on a swing, the graph includes a scale on each axis and the coordinate pairs of some points, allowing students to identify the range more definitively. However, the graph is a partial representation of the function because it does not show what happens after a dropped ball hits the ground the fifth time. When describing the domain, students need to attend to what is reasonable in this situation (that is, noting that the ball likely does not just stop after the fifth bounce).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tennis ball was dropped from a certain height. It bounced several times, rolled along for a short period, and then stopped. Function \(H\) gives its height over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a partial graph of \(H\). Height is measured in feet. Time is measured in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the graph to help you answer the questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be prepared to explain what each value or set of values means in this situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nonlinear function. Time (seconds) and height (feet)." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/UDsrkZpUMABAf7f6ALH6aXuN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Find \(H(0)\). What point is this on the graph? What does it represent?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Solve \(H(x)=0\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Describe the domain of the function. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Describe the range of the function. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(H(0)=6\). It tells us the ball was dropped from a height of 6 feet at \(t=0\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(x=0.54\), \(x=1.48\), and \(x=2.25\) are three possible solutions, but there are others. Each one represents the time when the ball hit the ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Sample response: The domain includes all values between 0 and the time when the ball stopped moving, which, based on the graph, is about 3.8. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Sample response: The range includes all values between 0 and 6 feet, the height from which the ball was dropped. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Video: Interpreting Function Notation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the following video to learn more about function notation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls="true" crossorigin="anonymous" width="550"&gt;
&lt;source src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/20f903eb50ca52bd9b9bfa4a7db8be6af298e6be"&gt;
&lt;track default="true" kind="captions" label="On" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/f67996d2238d2d8b26549d8065f6ae3382299f62" srclang="en_us"&gt;
  https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/20f903eb50ca52bd9b9bfa4a7db8be6af298e6be &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Extension&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Are you ready for more?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In function \(H\), the input was time in seconds, and the output was height in feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about some other quantities that could be inputs or outputs in this situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Describe a function whose domain includes only integers. Be sure to specify the units. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Describe a function whose range includes only integers. Be sure to specify the units. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Sketch a graph of each function. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A blank graph. Origin O.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/74JMzMQEdH9YKb7rwqkXwqh3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A blank graph. Origin O.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/74JMzMQEdH9YKb7rwqkXwqh3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Extension Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample responses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The maximum height, in feet, that the ball reaches after \(n\) bounces as a function of the number of bounces. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The number of times the ball has hit the ground as a function of time, in seconds, since the ball was dropped. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Sample graphs: &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Scatter plot graph&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/VJPut5N1Gc6cRyJQXGPjTFHv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graph of a piece wise function&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/DA11HNpPrgJappyjLnZivdsN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus the discussion on how students reasoned about the domain and the range for the function. Highlight explanations that account for what is realistic in the context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The domain tells us all the possible amounts of time that passed since the moment the tennis ball was dropped until it stopped rolling. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The range includes all the possible heights of the tennis ball from the time it was dropped until the time it stopped rolling. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students if there are points on the graph whose coordinates are particularly useful for identifying the domain and range of the function. (The heights of the bounces? The points where the ball hits the ground? Points between the two? Others?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emphasize that, just like in the activity about the swing, some points and features on a graph can give us more information than others about possible input-output values of a function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Use this routine to support whole-class discussion of the meaning of domain and range in the context of a tennis ball bouncing. As students share explanations of their reasoning about the domain and the range for the function, encourage students to press for details and precision in language in peers&amp;lsquo; responses by asking questions such as, &amp;ldquo;Can you explain this using points on the graph?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Are there values for the domain and range not shown on the graph? How do you know?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.12.3: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&amp;nbsp; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph below shows the number of customers, \(C\), in a restaurant \(x\) hours after 8 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does \(C(14)\) equal, and what does it mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A GRAPHED FUNCTION, WHERE NUMBER OF CUSTOMERS IS A FUNCTION OF THE NUMBER OF HOURS AFTER 8 AM. THE GRAPH INCREASES, DECREASES, INCREASES, AND THEN DECREASES AGAIN." src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/129d13b346d30517bb902d70d66e3365d1a59e4f" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;\(C(14)=0.5\) and means there are 14 customers around 8:30.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The input is 14, so it is the \(x\)-value. The answer is \(C(14)=0\) and is when the restaurant closes and has no more customers around 10 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;\(C(14)=0\) and is when the restaurant closes and has no more customers around 10 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: Since 14 is the input value, look for where 14 is located on the \(x\)-axis. The output there is 0, which means that there are no customers 14 hours after 8 a.m., which is about 10 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;\(C(14)=0\) and means there are 14 customers at 8 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The input and output values and their meanings should be switched. The answer is \(C(14)=0\) and is when the restaurant closes and has no more customers around 10 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;\(C(14)=0\) means there have not been any customers over 14 hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The output gives the number of customers at that time, not over a period of time. The answer is \(C(14)=0\) and is when the restaurant closes and has no more customers around 10 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.12.3: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Domain and Range from Graphs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph below shows the distance Carl drives from home, \(D(t)\), when \(t\) is time in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graph on coordinate grid, origin O." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/miw8u65HUk4HkNcfvqRXqmPo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What is the domain of the graph? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain is \(x\)-values that are at least 0 and a maximum of 400.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What is the range of the graph? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The range is the \(y\)-values that are at least 0 and a maximum of 285.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What are the values of \(x\) where \(D(x)=0\), and what do they mean? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(D(0)=0\) and \(D(400)=0\), and this is when Carl left home and then arrived home, so the distance was 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Domain and Range from Graphs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the values for the domain and range of the graph below?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="298" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/6y4pQn8cjzWnd7sPF7bq9MeH" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your notebook, write down your answer. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to find the domain and range of the graph:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain includes the \(x\)-values or inputs of the graph. The domain is from at least 0 to at most 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The range includes the \(y\)-values or outputs of the graph. The range is from at least 1 to at most 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did you do? Know that you learn more from wrong answers than from right answers! Wrong answers help us find flaws in our thinking. Take a minute to think about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you got the question wrong. Then you won&amp;rsquo;t get this type of question wrong again!&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2105">
            <jumpto>0</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659642435</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2106">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659642435</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="941">
        <prevpageid>940</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>942</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659655238</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662594766</timemodified>
        <title>4.12.4: Real-World Domain and Range</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt;Activity (10 Minutes)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A discrete function has distinct separate values in the domain and range, rather than an interval of values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Below is a graph from the previous lesson that graphs the number of students attending a camp and the amount, in dollars, the camp earns. There must be 5 students to hold the camp.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/idfgHv7hYxqaekvuiQMqSPwJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What are the \(x\)-values of this function that make up the domain? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Why can&amp;rsquo;t we say the domain is all values from 5 to 16? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What are the \(y\)-values of this function that make up the range? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A continuous function refers to a function that does not have any breaks in its graph. The domain and range of a continuous function are often represented by an interval that can be written as an inequality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The graph below represents a continuous function. The function, \(P\), is the cost of parking in a garage for \(t\) hours. It is represented by the function \(P(t)=5h +10\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A GRAPHED LINE WITH A Y-INTERCEPT AT (0, 10), PASSING THROUGH THE POINTS (2, 20) AND (4, 30)." src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/6de33bb25551b188fc2e064fe0dc9c29c5525584" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What does \(P(0)\) represent? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; In words, what are the values of the domain? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How can you write the domain values as an inequality? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; In words, what are the values of the range? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How can you write the range values as an inequality? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the number of students cannot be fractions or decimals, so those values are not in the domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;200, 250, 300, 350, 400, 450, 500, 550, 600, 650&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It represents the starting price of parking for the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The domain includes the values where \(x\) is at least 0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(x\geq0\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The range includes the values where \(y\) is at least 10.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(y\geq10\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.12.4: Self Check&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which of the following correctly describes the domain and range of the graph below?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH OF A LINE FOR ALL X GREATER THAN OR EQUAL TO 2, WITH POINT SHOWN AT (2, 3), AND PASSING THROUGH THE POINTS (5, 9) AND (8, 15).
" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/dc72e451da5630e217892b4e1af7e45896fd003c" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Domain: \(x\geq3\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Range: \(y\geq2\)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The domain is the \(x\)-values. and the lowest \(x\)-value is 2. The answer is Domain: \(x2\) and Range: \(
          y3\).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Domain: \(x\geq2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Range: \(y\geq3\)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: The lowest \(x\)-value is 2, and the graph continues forever right. The lowest \(y\)-value is 3, and then the graph continues forever up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Domain: \(x\leq2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Range: \(y\leq3\)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: Watch the inequality symbol you use. The domain includes the \(x\)-values greater than or equal to 2, and the range includes the \(y\)-values greater than or equal to 3. The answer is Domain: \(x2\) and Range: \(y3\).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Domain: \(x&amp;gt;2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Range: \(y&amp;gt;3\)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The domain includes 2 and the range includes 3, so both inequalities should have an equal sign included. The answer is Domain: \(x2\) and Range: \(y3\).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.12.4: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Domain and Range as Inequalities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the linear function below, use inequalities to represent the domain and range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH OF A LINE FOR ALL X GREATER THAN OR EQUAL TO 5, WITH POINT SHOWN AT (5, 0), AND PASSING THROUGH THE POINTS (10, 5), AND (15, 10).
" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/12d788f0be52aef294188ce1d62b5406230e279f" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the domain is all \(x\)-values, look left to right for the least to greatest values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The smallest \(x\)-value on this linear function is 5, and then the line continues to the right forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the domain is all values that are at least 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an inequality, write this as \(x\geq5\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Range:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the range is all \(y\)-values, look from the bottom to the top for the least to greatest values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The smallest \(y\)-value is 0, and then the line continues up forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the range is all values that are at least 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An an inequality, the range is \(y\geq0\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Domain and Range as Inequalities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the linear function below, use inequalities to represent the domain and range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="GRAPH OF A LINE FOR ALL X GREATER THAN OR EQUAL TO 5, WITH POINT SHOWN AT (5, 6), AND PASSING THROUGH THE POINTS (7, 10) AND (10, 16)." src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/f8570d4ff8597bfd1128c5bfc31210c48eeeeb47" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your notebook, write down your answer. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to write the domain and range of the linear function as an inequality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the domain is all \(x\)-values, look left to right for the least to greatest values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The smallest \(x\)-value on this linear function is 5, and then the line continues to the right forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the domain is all values that are at least 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an inequality, write this as \(x\geq5\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Range:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the range is all \(y\)-values, look from the bottom to the top for the least to greatest values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The smallest \(y\)-value is 6, and then the line continues up forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the range is all values that are at least 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An an inequality, the range is \(y\geq6\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did you do? Know that you learn more from wrong answers than from right answers! Wrong answers help us find flaws in our thinking. Take a minute to think about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you got the question wrong. Then you won&amp;rsquo;t get this type of question wrong again!&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2107">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659655238</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2108">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659655238</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="942">
        <prevpageid>941</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>943</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659655377</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662594808</timemodified>
        <title>4.12.5: Graph of a Function and the Domain and Range Connection</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Cool Down (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function \(W\) gives the temperature, in degrees Fahrenheit, of a pot of water on a stove \(t\) minutes after the stove is turned on. After 30 minutes, the pot is taken off the stove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graph of the function is shown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="graph of temperature of water over time" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/DAHUmXot8XWXoJDfSyT4fTQW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Is 250 in the range of function \(W\)? Explain how you know. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Describe the range of the function. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Does \(W(t)=0\) have a solution? Explain how you know. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; No, 250 is not in the range. The highest temperature is 212 degrees Fahrenheit. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The range is all values between 75 and 212, the lowest and the highest temperature, \(75\leq y\leq212.\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; No, a solution to this equation would be the time when the temperature is 0 degrees Fahrenheit, which is never the case. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Response to Student Thinking&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;More Chances&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If students are still struggling with domain and range, examine errors in the cool-down and make sure to discuss domain and range during each of the activities in Lesson 13.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2109">
            <jumpto>0</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659655377</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2110">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659655377</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="943">
        <prevpageid>942</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>944</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659655400</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662754116</timemodified>
        <title>4.12.6: Practice</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Students will complete the following questions to practice the skills they have learned in this lesson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The graph of function \(H\) shows the height, in meters, of a rocket \(t\) seconds after it was launched.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find \(H(0)\) in meters.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Function on coordinate plane." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/7bLidN2jP6Yz7ZmTXqfEzLEH"&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;15 meters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which of the following describes the domain of this function?
            &lt;ol type="i"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(0\leq x\leq35\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(0\leq x\leq4.5\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(0\leq x\leq2\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(15\leq x\leq35\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \(0\leq x\leq4.5\); The domain includes all values from 0 to approximately 4.5, \(0\leq x\leq4.5\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which of the following describes the range of this function?
            &lt;ol type="i"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(0\leq y\leq35\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(0\leq y\leq4.5\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(0\leq y\leq2\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(15\leq y\leq35\)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \(0\leq y\leq35\); The range includes all values from 0 to 35 meters, \(0\leq y\leq35\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which of the following describes the domain of the function graphed below?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Coordinate grid with wiggly graph. Horizontal axis by twos. Vertical axis by ones. Graphs starts around 2 comma 2 point 2 and ends around 7 comma 4." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/GkB7PHdbH3XwZeri2tG9zkAA"&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(0\leq x\leq9\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(0\leq x\leq4\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(2\leq x\leq7\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(2\leq x\leq4\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;\(2\leq x\leq7\); The domain is all values from at least 2 to a maximum of 7, \(2\leq x\leq7\). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which of the following describes the range of the graph below?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Coordinate grid with wiggly graph. Horizontal axis by twos. Vertical axis by ones. Graphs starts around 2 comma 2 point 2 and ends around 7 comma 4." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/GkB7PHdbH3XwZeri2tG9zkAA"&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(2\leq y\leq4\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(2\leq x\leq4\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(2\leq y\leq7\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(2\leq x\leq7\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;\(2\leq y\leq4\). The range is all values from at least 2 to a maximum of 4, \(2\leq y\leq4\). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select all of the values of the range for the function \(h\), graphed below.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/56d0af3118e4ed206a7350ae234fec3ae6c71cb5" width="300"&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ndash;5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ndash;3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ndash;2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ndash;3, &amp;ndash;2, 2, 4 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="5"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which of the following is the domain of the function graphed below?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/0223a9341fcd7ca2dc3e2ddd4b42c389dbad097e" width="300"&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(-5\leq x\leq5\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(-5 \leq x \leq 7\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(-5 \leq y \leq 5\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(-5 \leq y \leq 7\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;\(-5\leq x\leq5\) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="6"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which of the following represents the domain of the function graphed below?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="GRAPH OF A LINE FOR ALL X GREATER THAN OR EQUAL TO 2, WITH POINT SHOWN AT (2 5), AND PASSING THROUGH THE POINTS (3, 8) AND (5, 14)." src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/a79cc63c6acdd168fd53633b75e6c1594d031438" width="300"&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(y\geq 5\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(x \geq 5\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(y \geq 2\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(x \geq 2\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \(x \geq 2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="7"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which of the following represents the range of the function graphed below?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="GRAPH OF A LINE FOR ALL X GREATER THAN OR EQUAL TO 2, WITH POINT SHOWN AT (2 5), AND PASSING THROUGH THE POINTS (3, 8) AND (5, 14)." src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/a79cc63c6acdd168fd53633b75e6c1594d031438" width="300"&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(y \geq 5\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(x \geq 5\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(y \geq 2\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(x \geq 2\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;\(y \geq 5\) &lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2111">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659655400</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2112">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659655400</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="944">
        <prevpageid>943</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659657662</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662594997</timemodified>
        <title>4.12.7: Lesson Synthesis</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;Display several familiar graphs of functions from this unit. Here are some examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A graph.&amp;nbsp;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/idfgHv7hYxqaekvuiQMqSPwJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="2 graphs. Horizontal axis, 0 to 7, time in seconds. Vertical axis, 0 to 50 by 10&amp;rsquo;s, height in meters. Graph R is a parabolic and opens down. Graph D is piecewise linear." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/M7kSmncpv7Zi5VBoiswbhXcU"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="piecewise function" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/YEBSQKttFH776gTFYUTDqdet"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="squiggly line graphing distance from post over time" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/D1tHXCGiG1SnLnLpLrpvQuQN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students to examine the graphs and use them to help summarize what graphs can tell us about the domain and range of functions. Ask students to complete the following prompts as thoroughly as they can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can learn about the domain and range of a function from a graph by looking for . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A graph may not always show all that is needed to fully describe the domain and range, however. For example, it may not show . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2113">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659657662</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2114">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659657662</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>
