<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="22" moduleid="186" modulename="page" contextid="197">
  <page id="22">
    <name>Unit 5, Section C Overview: Comparing Linear and Exponential Functions</name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-2b3db1db-7fff-0910-83a7-93c7259926cf"&gt;The focus of Operation Hope is financial dignity and inclusion. Their mission is to make free enterprise and capitalism work for the underserved. The core of that movement is teaching people about the power of exponential functions. Participants learn how finance charges and interest work so they can control their debt. They also learn how compounded investments grow to make the most of their investments.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-2b3db1db-7fff-0910-83a7-93c7259926cf"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: calc(0.90375rem + 0.045vw);"&gt;In this section, you will compare types and rates of change. You will learn that, for a linear function, a constant amount is added to the \(y\)-value each time \(x\) increases by 1. For an exponential function, the \(y\)-value is multiplied by a constant value as \(x\) increases by 1. Exponential functions may change gradually at first, but they eventually increase or decrease rapidly. You will learn that the rate of change, or slope, for a linear function is constant. The rate of change for an exponential function is always increasing for exponential growth or decreasing for exponential decay. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: calc(0.90375rem + 0.045vw);"&gt;&lt;br&gt;This section includes 2 lessons:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Which One Changes Faster?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Changes over Equal Intervals
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:2:{s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";s:17:"printlastmodified";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>2</revision>
    <timemodified>1663620137</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>