<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="5" moduleid="40" modulename="page" contextid="51">
  <page id="5">
    <name>Unit 1 Project: Slopes and Intercepts</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;h3&gt;Activity P.1: Notice and Wonder: Sugar and Flour&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you notice? What do you wonder?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt="coordinate plane" class="atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="520" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/24183d1534b12d03a2705b2ac3daa961322851e1" width="801"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Activity P.2: Matching Matching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        Deal out the graph cards, face up. Take turns with your partner to name the three things in each graph:&amp;nbsp;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slope&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(x\)-intercept&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(y\)-intercept&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For each graph you find, tell your partner the slope, \(x\)-intercept, and \(y\)-intercept.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For each graph your partner finds, see if you agree with their thinking. If you agree, write their answers down on the graph for them. If you disagree, discuss your thinking and work to reach an agreement.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deal out the equation cards face up, leaving the graph cards face up as well. Take turns with your partner to match each graph with an equation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For each match that you find, explain to your partner how you know it&amp;rsquo;s a match.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;For each match that your partner finds, listen carefully to their explanation. If you disagree, discuss your thinking and work to reach an agreement.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a real-world problem that could be modeled by one of the equations or graphs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose a point that is on the graph or satisfies the equation and explain to your partner what it means in the context of your problem.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain to your partner what the slope and intercepts represent in the context of your problem.

            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:2:{s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";s:17:"printlastmodified";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>7</revision>
    <timemodified>1657366706</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>
