<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="202" moduleid="267" modulename="lesson" contextid="278">
  <lesson id="202">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Project 7 Teacher Guide: Designing a Fountain</name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>1</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password></password>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>0</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>0</activitylink>
    <mediafile></mediafile>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>0</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1665640235</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="1862">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1863</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665640352</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665640519</timemodified>
        <title>Project 7 Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Narrative&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this culminating project, students integrate ideas from the unit. Students will use the fact that the shape made by water coming out of a jet or fountain can be modeled with a quadratic equation. Students will design a fountain with given criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first activity, students work through a simplified example with one fountain and one jet. Students will think about what information is needed to write the equation. They can use a sketch to draw the path. Students decide on some reasonable measurements and write the equation. Understanding the use of the vertex form of a quadratic equation is helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second activity gives students an opportunity to design a fountain with three to five jets. Students are given certain measurements and criteria to meet to write the equation for paths of the jets. Students may present their equations and an explanation of what information they used and how they wrote the equation of the path of the jets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Goals (Teacher Facing) &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Use quadratic functions to solve a real-world problem. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Targets (Student Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Use quadratic functions to solve a real-world problem. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; A6(B) write equations of quadratic functions given the vertex and another point on the graph, write the equation in vertex form \((f(x)=a(x-h)^2+k)\), and rewrite the equation from vertex form to standard form \((f(x)=ax^2+bx+c\)); and &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; A7(A) graph quadratic functions on the coordinate plane and use the graph to identify key attributes, if possible, including \(x\)-intercept, \(y\)-intercept, zeros, maximum value, minimum values, vertex, and the equation of the axis of symmetry; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; A7(C) determine the effects on the graph of the parent function \(f(x)=x^2\) when \(f(x)\) is replaced by \(af(x)\), \(f(x)+d, f(x-c)\), f(bx) for specific values of \(a\), \(b\), \(c\), and \(d\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Project 7 handouts &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Recommend making technology available. Having access to graphing technology will streamline the process of testing different equations &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Consider demonstrating how to use sliders in Desmos to adjust the parameters of a quadratic equation in vertex form. For example, if \(y=-a(x-h)^2+k\) is used to represent a generic quadratic that opens down, students can easily experiment with its shape by moving sliders on \(a\), \(h\), and \(k\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Project Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Activity P1: Introduction to Fountain Design &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Activity P2: Designing a Fountain &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4181">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665640352</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1863">
        <prevpageid>1862</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1864</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665640902</timecreated>
        <timemodified>0</timemodified>
        <title>Activity P7.1: Introduction to Fountain Design</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity: Introduction to Fountain Design (10 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To introduce the task, make sure students can easily visualize what shape is made by water coming out of a jet or fountain. Ask students what shape water makes when it comes out of a drinking fountain, and either sketch the shape for all to see or invite a student to sketch it. Ask if they have seen fountains with jets that shoot water. Consider showing examples of a few, including videos if possible. Here is an example image:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/yX7kPDM2YFZuE1sizHKpLtWt" width="465" height="310"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important point to highlight is that the water makes a curved path through the air that can be modeled by a quadratic function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then take students through a simplified version of the task, with one statue and one water jet. Here is an image to use if needed. The trapezoid represents the statue and the red dot is the location of the water jet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trapezoid represents the statue and the red dot is the location of the water jet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/UD2cZsatAdYLPD64KA66o4Q2" width="202" height="77"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; What would you need to know in order to write an equation for a path for the water that would make it go over the statue? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; What is a reasonable height of the statue and a reasonable distance from the jet to the statue? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; What strategy would you use to find the equation for the path of the water? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; I would need to know the distance from the jet to the statue and the height of the statue. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Possible answer: The height of the statue is 6 feet and the jet is 8 feet from the statue. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Use the given distances to represent the statue and the location of the jet on a coordinate grid, then write a vertex form equation by choosing a reasonable vertex and adjusting parameters as needed. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have students share their ideas with a partner before inviting students to share with the class. If no student suggests estimating a reasonable vertex for the water’s path and writing a vertex form equation, ask students to discuss this idea. Vertex form is a very convenient way to write the equation if we know the size and distance of the statue so we can represent it on a coordinate grid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample answer for trapezoid example: If the fountain is 8 feet from the statue and the statue is 6 feet tall and 4 feet wide, then a possible vertex is \((-10, 7)\). Using vertex form to solve for \(a\): \(y=a(x+10)^2+7\). Using \((0,0)\) as a point to solve for a: \(0=a(0+10)^2+7\), \(-7=100a\), \(a=\frac{-7}{100}\). Equation is \(y=\frac{-7}{100}(x+10)^2+7\). Have students verify the height is over 6 feet as it goes over the statue. \((-8, 6.72)\) and \((-10, 7)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students may have trouble getting started. It may help for students to use grid paper to sketch the trapezoid and write some measurements for the distance from the fountain to the statue and the height of the statue. They may also need to be reminded that the view of the fountain is from the side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this activity is to prepare students to design their own fountain in the next activity. Students will be required to communicate how they used mathematics to choose the design of their fountains. A review of using the vertex form to write a quadratic equation will be helpful. Students may also use technology to test their equations.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4182">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665640902</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4183">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665640902</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1864">
        <prevpageid>1863</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665640933</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665717204</timemodified>
        <title>Activity P7.2: Designing a Fountain</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity: Designing a Fountain (40 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nearby park has a decorative pool, and the board of commissioners of the park is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;considering installing water jets in the pool to make it into a fountain. They have asked you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to design the water jets. Here is a diagram of the pool from above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/MsgPhhikwH6CEBWaipa2REyX" width="400" height="400"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; A and B are statues which are 4 feet tall.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; C and D are wider statues which are 5.5 feet tall.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; E is a statue with a vase on top, which is 8 feet tall.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; The pool is 15 feet wide. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diagram is drawn to scale. The dots along the edge show where jets can be placed. You don’t have to put jets in all five places. The jets will be at water level.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to figure out how many jets there should be, where they should go, and what path the water should make. Your design needs to meet these criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; The jets can only go in the places indicated by the dots. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; There must be at least two jets. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; The water can’t hit any of the statues. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Some water must go into the vase. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; The water can’t go higher than 10 feet. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have your final design, you should create a presentation to explain it to the commissioners. The presentation should show the paths of the water and include your mathematical descriptions of the paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From measuring the circles, I can tell that the small statues are about 2 feet wide, the larger ones are about 2.5 feet wide, and the vase is about 3.5 feet wide. The centers of the small statues are about 3 feet from the edge of the pool, the centers of the large statues are about 4 feet from the corners, and the center of the vase is 7.5 feet from the edge. I decided to put the water jets where the red dots are in this picture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/GUvUEmiCV3NMp3CZggtgZMuc" width="202" height="202"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The equations for the top two jets are the same. Here is what they will look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/QYHvM4558FfiR4hSj7CRFfV5" width="260" height="219"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If \((0, 0)\) is the location of the jet, then the equation is \(y=-\frac {9}{33.0625}(x−5.75)^2+9\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to make the other jet shoot the water lower so that it wouldn’t go into the vase. This is what it looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/oCB8cSdxYzd2Uea4xSvXCWSQ" width="322" height="306"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The equation for this jet is \(y=- \frac {5}{625}(x−2.5)^2+5\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If students aren’t sure how to get started, suggest that they sketch a coordinate grid on top of their sketch(es) of the pool from the side. They can then choose an origin and fill in the values they know. It is important for students to note that the diagram is drawn to scale and the pool is 15 feet wide. Sketching in a reasonable path for the water should help them estimate the vertex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having access to graphing technology will streamline the process of testing different equations, so making technology available is recommended. Consider demonstrating how to use sliders in Desmos to adjust the parameters of a quadratic equation in vertex form. For example, if \(y=-a(x-h)^2+k\) is used to represent a generic quadratic that opens down, students can easily experiment with its shape by moving sliders on \(a\), \(h\), and \(k\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this discussion is for students to communicate how they used mathematics to justify their findings. Have students present their equations and explain how they found them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; What information did you use to find the equation? (The center of the fountain is 7.5 feet from the edge. I drew a sketch to start at \((0, 0)\) and the path that would end near \((7.5,8)\). I found the vertex would be about 5.75 feet and I wanted the height to be 9 feet. I used vertex form to find a and found the equation \(y=-\frac {9}{33.0625}(x−5.75)2+9)\).&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; "How can you tell if your model meets the criteria? (I graphed the equation \(y=- \frac {9}{33.0625}(x−5.75)^2+9\) and checked that the height would be above around 8 feet near the center of the statue, which is 7.5 feet. The point \((7.667, 8)\) is on the graph, so the fountain hits the vase. The maximum height is 9 feet, so the equation meets the criteria for being less than 10 feet.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4184">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665640933</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4185">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665640933</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>