<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="109" moduleid="145" modulename="lesson" contextid="156">
  <lesson id="109">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Lesson 4.15 Teacher Guide: Different Types of Sequences</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>1</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password/>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>0</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>148</activitylink>
    <mediafile/>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>1</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1660691241</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="995">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>996</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659749020</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662589763</timemodified>
        <title>4.15.0: Lesson Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt; Lesson Narrative&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this lesson is for students to understand what makes a sequence an arithmetic sequence and to connect it to the idea of a linear function. Arithmetic sequences are characterized by adding a constant value to get from one term to the following term, just as linear functions are characterized by a constant rate of change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building from their thinking about geometric sequences, students begin this lesson comparing three different sequences. By articulating how the sequences are alike and different, they demonstrate the need for precise language (MP6). Next, students consider two arguments for what type of sequence is represented in a table, and then they use a graph of the sequence to justify why it could be arithmetic. Throughout the lesson, students will work with and create different representations of functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Goals (Teacher Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        Compare and contrast (orally and in writing) arithmetic and geometric sequences.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        Determine the rate of change of an arithmetic sequence.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        Interpret tables and graphs to determine if a sequence is arithmetic or geometric.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Targets (Student Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        Explain what it means for a sequence to be arithmetic or geometric.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TEKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation of Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A12(C)&lt;u&gt; identify terms of arithmetic and geometric sequences when the sequences are given in function form&lt;/u&gt; using recursive processes;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partial coverage: Lesson provides content that covers part of this TEKS. The parts that are covered have been underlined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the instructional activities for the lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        4.15.1: Interpreting Function Notation
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        4.15.2: What Is an Arithmetic Sequence?
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
            4.15.2: Self Check
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
            4.15.2: Additional Resources
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        4.15.3: A Sequence Is a Type of Function
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
            4.15.3: Self Check
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
            4.15.3: Additional Resources
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        4.15.4: Identify and Generate Sequences
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will also complete a series of problems in the 4.15.5: Practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Vocabulary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this lesson, it is important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        Familiarize students with the vocabulary words they will see throughout the lesson. Encourage students to look for these words and notice their use and meanings.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        Encourage students to use key vocabulary words in &amp;ldquo;math talk&amp;rdquo; and their written and oral explanations.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        Utilize a word wall. Sample cards are located here: &lt;a href="https://www.doe.virginia.gov/instruction/mathematics/resources/vocab_cards/" target="_blank"&gt;Mathematics Vocabulary Word Wall Cards&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary words that are emphasized in this lesson include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        geometric sequence
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        arithmetic sequence
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Support for Building Character&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, find ways to encourage and support students to work on cultivating their &lt;strong&gt;creativity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to try during this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/oh-the-places-youll-go/" target="_blank"&gt;Oh, the Places You&amp;rsquo;ll Go&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/free-your-mind/" target="_blank"&gt;Free Your Mind&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other tips located here in the &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/playbooks/creativity" target="_blank"&gt;Playbook on Creativity&lt;/a&gt; from Character Lab.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2231">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659749020</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2232">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659749020</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="996">
        <prevpageid>995</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>997</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659749288</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662589806</timemodified>
        <title>4.15.1: Interpreting Function Notation</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Warm Up (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this warm-up is to informally assess strategies and understandings students currently have for interpreting function notation, which they learned about in an earlier course. Students will use function notation when they define sequences with equations in later lessons, so this warm-up is an opportunity for practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Display the first two sentences and ask students to read them quietly. Then, display one problem at a time. Give students quiet think time for each problem and ask them to give a signal when they have an answer before displaying the next problem. Keep all problems displayed throughout the warm-up. Follow with a whole-class discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the function \(f\) given by \(f(n)=3n&amp;minus;7\). This function takes an input, multiplies it by 3, and then subtracts 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evaluate mentally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(
        f(10)\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        \(f(10)&amp;minus;1\)
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        \(f(10&amp;minus;1)\)
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        \(f(5)&amp;minus;f(4)\)
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        23
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        22
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        20
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        3
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some students may believe that function notation &amp;ldquo;distributes,&amp;rdquo; that is, that expressions like \(f(5)&amp;minus;f(4)\) are equivalent to \(f(5&amp;minus;4)=f(1)\). Ask these students to work out the value of the expression both ways to make clear that \(f(5)&amp;minus;f(4)\) and \(f(5&amp;minus;4)\) are not equivalent expressions, with a reminder that function notation is not multiplication, but rather a way to write the output of a function for a specific input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students to share their strategies for each problem. Record and display their responses for all to see.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2233">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659749288</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2234">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659749288</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="997">
        <prevpageid>996</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>998</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659750407</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662677392</timemodified>
        <title>4.15.2: What Is an Arithmetic Sequence?</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this activity is for students to contrast three different types of sequences and to introduce the term &amp;ldquo;arithmetic sequence.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitor for students using precise language, either orally or in writing, during work time to invite to share during the whole-class discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2. Give students quiet work time and then time to share their work with a partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As students discuss the sequences, circulate and listen to students talk about the patterns they notice. Write down common or important phrases you hear students say about each type, for example: &amp;ldquo;add 10 each time&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;multiply each term by 2.&amp;rdquo; Collect the responses into a visual display. Throughout the remainder of the lesson, continue to update collected student language and remind students to borrow language from the display as needed. In the lesson synthesis, after the term &amp;ldquo;arithmetic sequence&amp;rdquo; is introduced, ask students to sort the collected language into three groups, one for language used to describe arithmetic sequences, a second for geometric sequences, and the third for neither.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Support for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activate or supply background knowledge about sequences. Allow students to use calculators to ensure inclusive participation in the activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the values of the first 5 terms of 3 sequences:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type="A"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        30, 40, 50, 60, 70, . . .
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        0, 5, 15, 30, 50, . . .
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        1, 2, 4, 8, 16, . . .
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        For each sequence, describe a way to produce a new term from the previous term.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ol type="A"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
            30, 40, 50, 60, 70, . . .
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
            0, 5, 15, 30, 50, . . .
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
            1, 2, 4, 8, 16, . . .
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        If the patterns you described continue, which sequence has the second-greatest value for the 10th term?
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        Which of these could be geometric sequences? Explain how you know.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An arithmetic sequence is a sequence in which each term is the previous term plus a constant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This constant is called the common difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which of these could be arithmetic sequences? Explain how you know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol type="A"&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ol type="A"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
            Sample response: Each term is 10 more than the previous term.
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
            Sample response: Each term is the result of adding 5 more than was added to the previous term (add 5, then add 10, and then add 15).
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
            Sample response: Each term is double the previous term.
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        Sequence&lt;span&gt; B&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        Sequence &lt;span&gt;C&lt;/span&gt;. Sample response: A geometric sequence has the same multiplier from one term to the next, the common ratio, and neither &lt;span&gt;A &lt;/span&gt;nor&lt;span&gt; B&lt;/span&gt; has this. Sequence &lt;span&gt;C &lt;/span&gt;does; the common ratio is 2. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. &lt;span&gt;Sequence &lt;span&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;. Sample response: An arithmetic sequence gets each term by adding the same constant to the previous term. Sequence&lt;span&gt; A&lt;/span&gt; adds 5 to each term to find the next term.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Extension&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Are you ready for more?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elena says that it&amp;rsquo;s not possible to have a sequence of numbers that is both arithmetic and geometric. Do you agree with Elena? Explain your reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Extension Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elena is incorrect. Sample explanation: the sequence 1, 1, 1, . . . is arithmetic (adding 0 each time), but it is also geometric (multiplying by 1 each time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Video: Comparing Sequences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the following video to learn more about comparing arithmetic and geometric sequences.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls="true" crossorigin="anonymous" width="550"&gt;
&lt;source src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/509740b91324e860a23860c580fa239d8a51c4dd"&gt;
&lt;track default="true" kind="captions" label="On" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/12c5ed810194f2f3cdae39856f3db5a28cd0d3c8" srclang="en_us"&gt;https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/509740b91324e860a23860c580fa239d8a51c4dd
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students may need help identifying a pattern for the two non-geometric sequences. Ask, &amp;ldquo;What can you say about the change between consecutive terms in the sequence?&amp;rdquo; Encourage students to use any language they wish to describe the pattern&amp;mdash;they do not need to use an equation at this time. Some students may benefit from creating a table where they can see the term number and the value of the term side by side, particularly for Sequence B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this discussion is to compare different types of sequences and introduce students to the term &amp;ldquo;arithmetic sequence.&amp;rdquo; Begin the discussion by asking students how&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;A and C are alike and different. They might offer things like:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        C is geometric, but A is not.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        In A, you always add 10 to get from term to term, but in C, you always multiply by 2.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        In C, the growth factor is 2. In A, you get the next term by adding 10 to the previous term.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell students that sequence A is an example of an arithmetic sequence. Here are two ways to know a sequence is arithmetic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        You always add the same number to get from one term to the next.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        If you subtract any term from the next term, you always get the same number.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share that the constant in an arithmetic sequence is called the rate of change or common difference. In sequence A, the rate of change is 10 because \(40=30+10\), \(50=40+10\), \(60=50+10\), and \(70=60+10\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some students may notice the similarity between an arithmetic sequence and a linear function. Invite these students to share their observations, such as how both are defined by a constant rate of change. Tell students that arithmetic sequences are a type of linear function and that their knowledge of linear functions will help them describe arithmetic sequences during this unit. If students do not bring up the connection to linear functions, ask: &amp;ldquo;What do you remember about linear functions?&amp;rdquo; Record student responses for all to see and invite comparisons between linear functions and arithmetic sequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.15.2: Self Check&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="302"&gt;
&lt;col width="322"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which of the following sequences is arithmetic?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3, 4, 6, 9, 13, . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: While a constant is added to the previous term to generate the next term, the constant is different each time. The answer is 3, 7, 11, 15, . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1, 4, 16, 64, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This sequence is geometric with a common ratio of 4. The answer is 3, 7, 11, 15, . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3, 7, 11, 15, . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: To find the next term, 4 is added to the previous term. This is arithmetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25, 5, 1, \(\frac15\), . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This sequence has a common ratio of \(\frac15\) and is geometric. The answer is 3, 7, 11, 15, . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.15.2: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Arithmetic Sequences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finding Common Differences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies often make large purchases, such as computers and vehicles, for business use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        A woman who starts a small contracting business purchases a new truck for $25,000.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        After five years, she estimates that she will be able to sell the truck for $8,000. The loss in value of the truck will therefore be $17,000, which is $3,400 per year for five years.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        The truck will be worth $21,600 after the first year; $18,200 after two years; $14,800 after three years; $11,400 after four years; and $8,000 at the end of five years.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The values of the truck in the example are said to form an arithmetic sequence because they change by a constant amount each year. Each term increases or decreases by the same constant value called the common difference of the sequence. For this sequence, the common difference is &amp;ndash;3,400.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ARITHMETIC SEQUENCE WITH SIX TERMS WITH A COMMON DIFFERENCE OF NEGATIVE THREE THOUSAND FOUR HUNDRED, STARTING WITH A VALUE OF TWENTY-FIVE THOUSAND AND ENDING WITH A VALUE OF EIGHT THOUSAND.
" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/b4ef05a451ee9ddbd41a3de6a0018926dcdbd443" width="550"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sequence below is another example of an arithmetic sequence. In this case, the common difference is 3. You can choose any term of the sequence and add 3 to find the subsequent term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ARITHMETIC SEQUENCE WITH A COMMON DIFFERENCE OF THREE, WRITTEN AS THREE, SIX, NINE, TWELVE, FIFTEEN, DOT DOT DOT.
" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/ad2abbd7eab8709bee9fc741c600c38ac25e82a6"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARITHMETIC SEQUENCE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An arithmetic sequence is a sequence that has the property that the difference between any two consecutive terms is a constant. This constant is called the common difference. If \(a_1\) is the first term of an arithmetic sequence and \(d\) is the common difference, the sequence will be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{\(a_n\)}={\(a_1, a_1+d, a_1+2d, a_1+3d\), . . .}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is each sequence arithmetic? If so, find the common difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        {1, 2, 4, 8, 16, . . .}
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        (-3, 1, 5, 9, 13, . . .}
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subtract each term from the subsequent term to determine whether a common difference exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        The sequence is not arithmetic because there is no common difference.
        &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;\(2-1=1\)&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;\(4-2=2\)&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;\(8-4=4\)&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;\(16-8=8\)
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        The sequence is arithmetic because there is a common difference. The common difference is 4.
        &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;\(1-(-3)=4\)&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;\(5-1=4\)&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;\(9-5=4\)&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;\(13-9=4\)
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Arithmetic Sequences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the given sequence arithmetic? If so, find the common difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{18, 16, 14, 12, 10, . . .}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your notebook, write down your answer. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to determine if the sequence is arithmetic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(16-18=-2\)&lt;br&gt;
    \(14-16=-2\)&lt;br&gt;
    \(12-14=-2\)&lt;br&gt;
    \(10-12=-2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an arithmetic sequence with a common difference of &amp;ndash;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did you do? Know that you learn more from wrong answers than from right answers! Wrong answers help us find flaws in our thinking. Take a minute to think about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you got the question wrong. Then you won&amp;rsquo;t get this type of question wrong again!&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2235">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659750407</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2236">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659750407</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="998">
        <prevpageid>997</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>999</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659751188</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662590971</timemodified>
        <title>4.15.3: A Sequence is a Type of Function</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this activity is for students to create another representation of a given sequence and to give them an opportunity to use the vocabulary they have learned for geometric and arithmetic sequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitor for students who create Mai&amp;rsquo;s graph to understand her reasoning and for students who reason about whether the sequence is defined by a rate of change or a growth factor to invite to share during the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jada and Mai are trying to decide what type of sequence this could be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="114"&gt;
&lt;col width="55"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;term number&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;value&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;18&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jada says: &amp;ldquo;I think this sequence is geometric because in the value column, each row is 3 times the previous row.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mai says: &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t think it is geometric. I graphed it, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t look geometric.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you agree with Jada or Mai? Explain or show your reasoning using a graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample response: I agree with Mai. Jada noticed that each value is multiplied by 3 to get to the next row, but the table skips terms. If the sequence were geometric, it would have to be 2, 6, 18, 54, 108. When Mai made a graph, she could see the gap in the sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="186" role="presentation" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/tM9DHpxLoiU8GUDQYGZZ2ybm" width="201"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without knowing the missing terms, we don&amp;rsquo;t know for sure if the sequence is arithmetic, but it could be since the three given points are all on the same line with slope 4. The missing points could be \((3,10)\) and \((4,14)\) so that the sequence would be 2, 6, 10, 14, 18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite previously selected students to share their reasoning, displaying any graphs created for all to see. If the idea of slope or average rate of change does not come up, ask students how they could have found the missing points for an arithmetic sequence just given \((2,6)\) and \((5,18)\). Draw in the slope triangle and show the computation for the average rate of change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.15.3: Self Check&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which two terms could be next in the sequence to make it arithmetic?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5, 8, ____, ____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;12.8, 7.68&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: These would be the next two terms if the sequence were geometric. The answer is 11, 14.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;11, 14&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: The common difference from 5 to 8 is 3, so continue to add 3 to find the next two terms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;13, 20&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This is the result of adding 3, then 5, and then 7. The common difference remains the same in an arithmetic sequence. The answer is 11, 14.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;13, 21&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This is the result of adding the two previous terms. This sequence does not have a common difference. The answer is 11, 14.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3&gt;4.15.3: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Creating a Sequence&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a sequence: 1, 3, . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write the next two terms that would make the sequence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    geometric
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    arithmetic
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    To make the sequence geometric, there must be a common ratio.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(1\cdot3=3\), so use a common ratio of 3 to multiply each term by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sequence becomes: 1, 3, 9, 27 . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    To make the sequence arithmetic, there must be a common difference.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(3-1=2\), so use a common difference of 2 to add to each term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sequence becomes: 1, 3, 5, 7 . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Creating a Sequence&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write the next two terms to create an arithmetic sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2, 6, . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your notebook, write down your answer. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt; Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to create an arithmetic sequence given two terms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the common difference by subtracting the first term from the second term:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(6-2=4\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The common difference is 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add 4 to the previous term to find the next terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sequence becomes: 2, 6, 10, 14 . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did you do? Know that you learn more from wrong answers than from right answers! Wrong answers help us find flaws in our thinking. Take a minute to think about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you got the question wrong. Then you won&amp;rsquo;t get this type of question wrong again!&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2237">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659751188</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2238">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659751188</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="999">
        <prevpageid>998</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1000</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659751302</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662590985</timemodified>
        <title>4.15.4: Identify and Generate Sequences</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Cool Down (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many sequences start with the terms 2 and 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    Find the next two terms of the arithmetic sequence 2, 8, ____, ____.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    Find the next two terms of the geometric sequence 2, 8, ____, ____.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    Find two possible next terms of a sequence 2, 8, ____, ____ that is neither geometric nor arithmetic.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    14, 20
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    32, 128
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    Sample response: 9, 16
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Response to Student Thinking&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;More Chances&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will have more opportunities to understand the mathematical ideas in this cool-down, so there is no need to slow down or add additional work to the next lessons. Instead, use the results of this to provide guidance for what to look for and emphasize over the next several lessons to support students in advancing their current understanding. Both Lessons 4 and 5 include arithmetic and geometric sequences for students to practice identifying and generating, but the focus is on new aspects (spreadsheets and functions), so you&amp;rsquo;ll have to adjust the activities to address this goal.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2239">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659751302</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2240">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659751302</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1000">
        <prevpageid>999</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1001</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659751833</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662601066</timemodified>
        <title>4.15.5: Practice </title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Students will complete the following questions to practice the skills they have learned in this lesson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        Here are the first two terms of some different arithmetic sequences. What is the 5th term of each sequence?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ndash;2, 4
            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 22&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;11, 111
            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 411&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5, 7.5
            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5, &amp;ndash;4
            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ndash;31&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        For each sequence, decide whether it could be arithmetic, geometric, or neither.
      &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
          200, 40, 8, . . .
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; geometric&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
      2, 4, 16, . . .
      &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; neither&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
      10, 20, 30, . . .
      &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; arithmetic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
      100, 20, 4, . . .
      &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; geometric&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="5" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
      6, 12, 18, . . .
      &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;arithmetic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    Complete each arithmetic sequence with its missing terms in your math notebook. Then, state the common difference for each sequence. Enter the common difference as integers only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ndash;3, &amp;ndash;2, ___, ___, 1
        &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
      Common Difference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ndash;1; The missing terms are &amp;ndash;1, 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        ___, 13, 25, ___, ___
          &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
      Common Difference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 12; The sequence should be 1, 13, 25, 37, 49.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        1, 0.25, ___, &amp;ndash;1.25, ___
          &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
      Common Difference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ndash;0.75; The sequence is 1, 0.25, &amp;ndash;0.5, &amp;ndash;1.25, &amp;ndash;2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
        92, ___, ___ ,___, 80
          &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
      Common Difference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ndash;3; The sequence is 92, 89, 86, 83, 80.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="5"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;

    Complete each arithmetic sequence with the missing terms. Then find the common difference for each. Enter the common difference as integers only.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    ___, 6, 10, ___, 18
      &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
    Common Difference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 4; The sequence is 2, 6, 10, 14, 18.
  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ndash;1, ___, &amp;ndash;11, &amp;ndash;16, ___
    &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
  Common Difference&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ndash;5; The sequence is &amp;ndash;1, &amp;ndash;6, &amp;ndash;11, &amp;ndash;16, &amp;ndash;21.
  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    10, 5, ___, ___, &amp;ndash;10
      &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
    Common Difference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ndash;5; The sequence is 10, 5, 0, &amp;ndash;5, &amp;ndash;10.
  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    ___, ___, 4.5, 6, ___
      &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
    Common Difference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;1.5; The sequence is 1.5, 3, 4.5, 6.
  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="5" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    ___, 12, 6, 0, ___
      &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
    Common Difference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ndash;6; The sequence is 18, 12, 6, 0, &amp;ndash;6.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2241">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659751833</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2242">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659751833</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1001">
        <prevpageid>1000</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659753123</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662591009</timemodified>
        <title>4.15.6: Lesson Synthesis</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;Ask students to discuss with a partner: &amp;ldquo;How are arithmetic and geometric sequences alike and different?&amp;rdquo; After they have had a few minutes to discuss, ask several students to share the things that came up. Some things to highlight:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    They are both types of sequences. That is, they are both lists of numbers.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    To get from one term to the next for both arithmetic and geometric sequences, you &amp;ldquo;do the same thing each time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    For geometric sequences, you always multiply by the same number to get the next term. For arithmetic sequences, you always add the same number to get the next term.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
    Geometric sequences have growth factors (the quotient of any term and the previous term), but arithmetic sequences have a constant rate of change (the difference of any term and the previous term).
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2243">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659753123</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2244">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659753123</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>
