<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="26" moduleid="218" modulename="page" contextid="229">
  <page id="26">
    <name>Unit 6 Wrap Up</name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, you learned that Ozzy Gamez and Juan Quezada can use polynomials to make decisions that will help their business, Plant Shop Chicago, run smoothly. Understanding polynomials can help them plan revenue and costs so they can make a profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this unit, you learned how to classify polynomials and determine their degree. You added and subtracted polynomials by combining like terms. You multiplied polynomials using the Distributive Property, vertical alignment, and the FOIL method. You learned to recognize special case products, such as binomial squares and conjugate pairs, to facilitate their multiplication. You divided by monomials using the Quotient of Powers Property, and you divided polynomials by polynomials using long division and synthetic division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You factored the GCF, greatest common factor, from a polynomial by using the “reverse” of the Distributive Property. You learned to factor a polynomial by grouping. You learned methods for factoring trinomials, such as undoing FOIL and trial and error. You learned to recognize patterns of perfect square trinomials and difference of squares. Finally, you learned to analyze a polynomial by its form and to select an appropriate strategy for factoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Building Character: Judgment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, you learned that &lt;strong&gt;judgment&lt;/strong&gt; is important for making sound decisions without bias. You can improve judgment through experience and by trying to understand the qualities that contribute to good judgment.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:2:{s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";s:17:"printlastmodified";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>3</revision>
    <timemodified>1664202905</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>