<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="194" moduleid="257" modulename="lesson" contextid="268">
  <lesson id="194">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Lesson 7.14 Teacher Guide: Graphs That Represent Situations</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>1</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password/>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>0</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>258</activitylink>
    <mediafile/>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>0</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1665692414</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="1786">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1787</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665305345</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665710195</timemodified>
        <title>7.14.0: Lesson Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Narrative&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now, students have seen how the parameters of a quadratic expression in standard form and in factored form relate to the graph representing the function. In the past few lessons, students worked with decontextualized quadratic functions. In this lesson, they transfer what they learned about the graphs to make sense of quadratic functions that model concrete contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students interpret equations and graphs of quadratic functions in terms of the situations they represent. They use their analyses to solve problems and to compare quadratic functions given in different representations. Along the way, they practice reasoning quantitatively and abstractly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Goals (Teacher Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Interpret (orally and in writing) the graph and equation representing a function in terms of the context. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Targets (Student Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Explain how a quadratic equation and its graph relate to a situation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TEKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation of Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A7(A) graph quadratic functions on the coordinate plane and &lt;u&gt;use the graph to identify key attributes, if possible, including x-intercept, y-intercept, zeros, maximum value, minimum values, vertex&lt;/u&gt;, and the equation of the axis of symmetry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partial coverage: Lesson provides content that covers part of this TEKS. The parts that are covered have been underlined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the instructional activities for the lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.14.1: Evaluating Quadratic Functions in the Real World &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.14.2: Interpreting a Functional Relationship Between Two Quantities &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.14.2: Self Check &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.14.2: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.14.3: Analyzing Functions Using Different Representations &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.14.3: Self Check &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.14.3: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.14.4: Using Quadratic Functions to Solve Problems &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.14.5: Identifying Key Features of Graphed Functions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will also complete a series of problems in 7.14.6: Practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Graphing technology &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Pre-printed cards, cut from copies of the blackline master &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Scientific calculators &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acquire devices that can run Desmos (recommended) or other graphing technology. It is ideal if each student has their own device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Vocabulary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this lesson, it is important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Familiarize students with the vocabulary words they will see throughout the lesson. Encourage students to look for these words and notice their use and meanings. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Encourage students to use key vocabulary words in &amp;ldquo;math talk&amp;rdquo; and their written and oral explanations. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Utilize a word wall. Sample cards are located here: &lt;a href="https://www.doe.virginia.gov/instruction/mathematics/resources/vocab_cards/" target="_blank"&gt;Mathematics Vocabulary Word Wall Cards&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary words that are emphasized in this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(y\)-intercept &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; vertex &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; quadratic function &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; maximum &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; none &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Support for Building Character&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, find ways to encourage and support students to work on cultivating their &lt;strong&gt;proactivity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to try during this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/all-together-now/" target="_blank"&gt;All Together Now&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/guided-mastery/" target="_blank"&gt;Guided Mastery&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other tips located here in the &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/playbooks/proactivity/" target="_blank"&gt;Playbook on Proactivity&lt;/a&gt; from Character Lab.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4013">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665305345</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1787">
        <prevpageid>1786</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1788</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665305884</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665691829</timemodified>
        <title>7.14.1: Evaluating Quadratic Functions in the Real World</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Warm Up (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this warm up, students begin to apply their new understandings about graphs to reason about quadratic functions contextually. They evaluate a simple quadratic function, find its maximum, and interpret these values in context. The input values to be evaluated produce an output of 0, reminding students of the meaning of the zeros of a function and their connection to the horizontal intercepts (\(x\)-intercepts) of the graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find the maximum value of the function, students could graph the function, but applying what they learned about the connection between the horizontal intercepts and the vertex (without graphing) would be more efficient. Identify students who make this connection and ask them to share their thinking in the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give students access to a calculator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The height, in inches, of a frog's jump is modeled by the equation \(h(t)=60t-75t^2\), where the time \(t\), after the frog jumps, is measured in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="close-up of a frog on plant stem" height="318" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/isGmozxaUqYPzADMU7sGiJoq" width="478"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For \(h(t)=60t-75t^2\):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Find \(h(0)\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Find \(h(0.8)\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do these values of \(h(0)\) and \(h(0.8)\) mean in terms of the frog's jump?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;They mean that the frog is on the ground when \(t=0\) (before jumping) and when \(t=0.8\) (when the frog lands on the ground).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After it jumped, how much time passed, in seconds, before the frog reached its maximum height?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.4 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain how you know this is the time the frog reached the maximum height.

    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The frog reached its maximum height at \(t=0.4\), as that is the halfway point of the jump. If we graph the function, the vertex of the graph will have a horizontal coordinate (\(t\)-coordinate) of 0.4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select students to share their responses and explanations. Even though students are not asked to graph the function, make sure that they begin to connect the quadratic expression that defines the function to the features of the graph representing that function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students: "If we graph the equation, what would the graph look like? Where would the intercepts be? Would the graph open up or down? Where would the vertex be?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlight the following points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The graph intersects the horizontal axis at \(t=0\) and \(t=0.8\), because \(h(0)\) and \(h(0.8)\) both have a value of 0. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(h(0.4)\) is the maximum height of the frog since \(t=0.4\) is halfway between the horizontal intercepts. If we were to graph it, (\(0.4,h(0.4)\)) would be the vertex. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The graph opens downward because the coefficient of the squared term is a negative number (-75). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graph of parabola" height="213" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/X2c9appiQyJ4XJwSoPhTGj9v" width="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4014">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665305884</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4015">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665305884</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1788">
        <prevpageid>1787</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1789</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665307249</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665743975</timemodified>
        <title>7.14.2: Interpreting a Functional Relationship Between Two Quantities</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier in this unit, students read off of a diagram the position of an object dropped from the top of a building and then observed that the data is modeled by a quadratic function. This lesson continues to develop this idea with an additional layer of complexity, appropriate for this stage in the unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of two. Display the equation \(d=10+406t-16t^2\) for all to see. Remind students that earlier in the unit, we saw this equation used to model the height of a cannonball that is shot up in the air as a function of time in seconds. The height was measured in feet. Ask students to recall what each term in the equation represents and briefly discuss their thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, give students a few minutes of quiet think time to read the first question (all four parts) to themselves and think about their responses. Ask them to share their thoughts with a partner before proceeding to the graphing questions. Clarify, if needed, that "horizontal intercept" and "vertical intercept" are a more general way to refer to \(x\)- and \(y\)-intercepts when the equation that defines a function uses variables other than \(x\) and \(y\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide access to devices that can run Desmos or other graphing technology. If needed, remind students how to use the available graphing technology to identify the coordinates of points on a graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The equation \(h(t)=2+23.7t-4.9t^2\) represents the height of a pumpkin that is catapulted up in the air as a function of time, \(t\), in seconds. The height is measured in meters above ground. The pumpkin is shot up at a vertical velocity of 23.7 meters per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you think the 2 in the equation \(h(t)=2+23.7t-4.9t^2\) tells us in this situation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The 2 tells us the pumpkin is 2 meters above ground before it is launched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you think the \(-4.9t^2\) in the equation \(h(t)=2+23.7t-4.9t^2\) tells us in this situation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The \(-4.9t^2\) shows the height lost due to gravity (like the \(-16t^2\) in the cannonball problem).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we graph the equation, will the graph open upward or downward? Why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The graph would open downward. The height starts at 2 meters and then increases as the pumpkin is shot up, and eventually, it decreases as the pumpkin falls back to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about where the vertical intercept would be. What is the \(y\)-value of that vertical intercept?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 2. The vertical intercept would be at \((0,2)\), because when \(t\) is 0, the height is 2 meters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="5"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What about the horizontal intercepts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The horizontal intercepts are hard to tell without graphing or having the equation in factored form. One of them will be located around \((5,0)\) because substituting 5 for \(t\) gives a height of -2 meters, which is pretty close to 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="6"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the graphing tool or technology outside the course. Graph the equation \(h(t)=2+23.7t-4.9t^2\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="DESCRIPTION: Graph of parabola" height="213" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/LgiUgE2SQ6dvpF9TNCuN4SfN" width="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="7"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now that you have graphed the equation, answer questions a&amp;ndash;c using the graph.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What is the vertical intercept and what does this point mean in our catapulted pumpkin situation? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The vertical intercept is \((0,2)\). It tells us that the pumpkin's initial position is 2 meters above ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What are the horizontal intercepts and what do these points mean in our catapulted pumpkin situation? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The graph intersects the horizontal axis around -0.08 and 4.9. The positive horizontal intercept tells us that the pumpkin hits the ground after about 4.9 seconds. The negative intercept doesn't have any meaning here since the time cannot be negative in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What is the vertex of the parabola and what does this point mean in our catapulted pumpkin situation? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;The vertex is at approximately \((2.4,30.7)\). It tells us that the pumpkin reaches its maximum height of about 30.7 meters around 2.4 seconds after being fired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Extension&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Are you ready for more?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What approximate vertical velocity would this pumpkin need for it to stay in the air for about 10 seconds? (Assume that it is still shot from 2 meters above the ground and that the effect of gravity pulling it down is the same.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; If \(h(t)=2+bt&amp;minus;4.9t^2\) takes the value 0 when \(t\) is close to 10, this means that \(2+10b&amp;minus;490\) is close to zero. That means we want \(b\) to be 48.8. The pumpkin needs to be shot in the air at 48.8 meters per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite students to share their graph and interpretations of the features of the graph. Discuss with students:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; "The graph shows two horizontal intercepts, one with a positive \(t\)-coordinate and the other with a negative \(t\)-coordinate. How do we make sense of the negative \(t\)-coordinate in this situation?" (Only the positive one has any meaning in this situation, since the negative value of time&amp;mdash;the time before the pumpkin was shot into the air&amp;mdash;is not relevant in this model.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; "How would you estimate the coordinates of the vertex without using a graph? Suppose you know both of the horizontal intercepts." (We can find the halfway point of the two horizontal intercepts and evaluate the function at that value of \(t\).) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.14.2: Self Check&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="302"&gt;
&lt;col width="322"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function that gives the height, \(h\), in feet of a cannonball \(t\) seconds after the ball leaves the cannon is graphed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graph with time in seconds on x-axis and distance above ground in feet on y-axis." height="243" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/Xn3p9pxe8EpgDWuWSZzJKUm8" width="331"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the point \((10, 1,600)\) and what does it mean in this situation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(Y\)-intercept, the highest height the cannonball reaches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The \(y\)-intercept occurs when \(x=0\) and represents the height the cannonball is launched from. The answer is maximum height, the highest height the cannonball reaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maximum height, the height the cannonball was launched&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The cannonball travels higher than where it is launched. The answer is maximum height, the highest height the cannonball reaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maximum height, the highest height the cannonball reaches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: The point is at the peak of the graph, or the maximum height. It tells how high the cannonball goes before coming back down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(Y\)-intercept, the height the cannonball was launched&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The \(y\)-intercept occurs when \(x=0\). You are describing the point where \(x=10\) and \(y\) is at the peak of the graph. The answer is maximum height, the highest height the cannonball reaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.14.2: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Meaning of Values on a Graph&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say a tennis ball is hit straight up in the air, and its height in feet above the ground is modeled by the equation \(f(t)=4+12t&amp;minus;16t^2\) where \(t\) represents the time in seconds after the ball is hit. Here is a graph that represents the function, from the time the tennis ball was hit until the time it reached the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height="213" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/hX6arVgtmo6e3oWSzh9aRkj9" width="316"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the graph, we can see some information we already know, and some new information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The 4 in the equation means the graph of the function intersects the vertical axis at 4. It shows that the tennis ball was 4 feet off the ground at  \(t=0\), when it was hit. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The horizontal intercept is \((1,0)\). It tells us that the tennis ball hit the ground 1 second after it was hit. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The vertex of the graph is at approximately \((0.4,6.3)\). This means that about 0.4 second after the ball was hit, it reached the maximum height of about 6.3 feet. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The equation can be written in factored form as \(f(t)=(-16t&amp;minus;4)(t&amp;minus;1)\). From this form, we can see that the zeros of the function are \(t=1\) and \(t=-14\). The negative zero, -14, is not meaningful in this situation because the time before the ball was hit is irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: The Meaning of Values on a Graph&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An object is thrown upward from a height of 5 feet with a velocity of 60 feet per second. Its height h(t) in feet after \(t\) seconds is modeled by the function \(h(t)=5+60t-16t^2\) and graphed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the value of the vertical intercept (\(y\)-intercept) and what does it mean in the function?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height="231" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/KaMw3hqcauLrZMY6cEpX6ez1" width="311"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to determine the \(y\)-intercept:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vertical intercept, or \(y\)-intercept, is where the graph crosses the \(y\)-axis. It occurs when \(x=0\). You can also identify the \(y\)-intercept by looking at the constant in the function. This occurs at \(y=5\). The point is (0,5). The \(y\)-intercept represents the initial height. It means the object is thrown from 5 feet above the ground.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4016">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665307249</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4017">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665307249</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1789">
        <prevpageid>1788</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1790</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665308159</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1666217046</timemodified>
        <title>7.14.3: Analyzing Functions Using Different Representations</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This activity prompts students to analyze two quadratic functions&amp;mdash;one represented by a graph, and the other by an equation&amp;mdash;and solve a problem. Graphs can make it easier to compare functions, but because students are asked not to graph the second function, they need to rely on their knowledge of the connections between equations and their graphs to make the comparison. To answer the questions, students have to interpret various pieces of the given information (the graph, the numbers in the equation, the descriptions in the questions, etc.), allowing them to reason quantitatively and abstractly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As students work, look for students who reason in the ways outlined in the Activity Synthesis so they can share their thinking later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give students a moment to read the task statement. Make sure students understand what it means for a baseball to "stay in flight."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider keeping students in groups of two and asking them to think quietly before discussing their thinking with a partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a graph that represents the height of a baseball, \(h\), in feet as a function of time, \(t\), in seconds after it was hit by Player A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Horizontal axis, time in seconds. Vertical axis, height in feet. Parabola, opens down, x intercepts at about -0.62 and about 5.12, vertex = 2 point 5 comma 105." height="213" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/FYooEvTtt4m5BTWjaV5fzyVo" width="318"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function \(g\) defined by \(g(t)=(-16t&amp;minus;1)(t&amp;minus;4)\) also represents the height in feet of a baseball \(t\) seconds after it was hit by Player B. Without graphing function \(g\), answer the following questions and explain or show how you know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which player's baseball stayed in flight longer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Player A's baseball stayed in flight longer. The zeros of function \(g\) are 4 and -116. The negative zero doesn't have any meaning in this situation. A zero in this situation means the time when the baseball has a height of 0 (or when it hits the ground). For Player B, this happened when \(t=4\) or 4 seconds after it was hit. Player A's baseball hit the ground a little over 5 seconds after it was hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which player's baseball reached a greater maximum height?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Player A's baseball reached a greater maximum height. From the graph for Player A, it looks like the \(y\)-coordinate of the vertex is around 105 feet. For Player B, the vertex of the graph has a \(t\)-coordinate of about 2 (halfway between -116 and 4). We can find g(2) to estimate the height at that point. \(g(2)=(-16(2)&amp;minus;1)(2&amp;minus;4)=(-33)(-2)=66\), so the highest point of Player B's baseball was around 66 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on the graph, what is the approximate height, in feet, of Player A&amp;rsquo;s baseball when hit? How do you know?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; We can look at the \(y\)-intercept of the graph, and it looks like the \(y\)-coordinate is about 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the height, in feet, of Player B&amp;rsquo;s baseball when hit?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 4 feet. Find the height when \(t=0\). \(g(0)=(-16(0)&amp;minus;1)(0&amp;minus;4)=(-1)(-4)=4\), so it was hit at 4 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some students may find it challenging to find the zeros of function \(g\) because of the -16 in \(-16t-1\). Support these students' reasoning about the equation \(-16t-1=0\) by asking whether this equation will have a positive or negative solution and whether it will have a solution close to 0 or not. Another challenge students may face is estimating the location of the vertex. Point out the graph of \(h\) and ask them how the vertex relates to the horizontal intercepts. It is not expected that students will compute the precise location by averaging -116 and 4. Encourage them to use the number between 0 and 4 as a good estimate of the \(t\)-coordinate of the vertex. Encourage struggling students to use technology to graph \(g\) to check their thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Video: Comparing Quadratic Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the following video to learn more about comparing quadratic functions in different forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls="true" crossorigin="anonymous" width="550"&gt;
&lt;source src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/9382d2c3ae0cf04cea052ff2eb4e67c80f49c56d"&gt;
&lt;track default="true" kind="captions" label="On" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/743f0b66d6468327d57d605b1a7b1d931b65ec6f" srclang="en_us"&gt;https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/9382d2c3ae0cf04cea052ff2eb4e67c80f49c56d
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite students to share their responses and reasoning. If not mentioned in students' explanations, highlight the following points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; To determine which baseball stayed in flight longer, we can compare where the graphs intersect the horizontal axis or the zeros of the functions, which tell us when the baseball hits the ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The graph of function \(h\) intersects the horizontal axis around 5. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Function \(g\) is given in factored form, so one zero will be a very small negative number (about -116), and the other zero will be 4. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The maximum height of Player A's baseball (function \(h\)) is shown in the graph. For Player B (function \(g\)), we can approximate the halfway point between the horizontal intercepts, which is around \(t=2\), and then find \(g(2)\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The baseball was hit at \(t=0\), so to find the height we would look at the vertical intercept (\(y\)-intercept). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; For function \(h\), this point is shown on the graph. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; For function \(g\), it is not immediately apparent because the equation is in factored form. If it was in standard form, the constant term is the vertical intercept. We can either expand the \((-16t-1)(t-4)\) and write an equivalent expression in standard form, or find \(g(0)\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.14.3: Self Check&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The functions describing the time that baseballs stayed in the air, in seconds, that four baseball players hit are below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(f(t)=(-16t-1)(t-5)\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(g(t)=(-16t-1)(t-10)\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(h(t)=(t-7)(-16t-1)\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(p(t)=(-8t-1)(2t-5)\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which function represents the ball that stayed in the air the longest?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(f(t)=(-16t-1)(t-5)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This ball traveled 5 seconds. There are other choices that stayed in the air longer. The answer is \(g(t)=(-16t-1)(t-10)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(g(t)=(-16t-1)(t-10)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: Since \(t-10=0\) at \(t=10\), the ball travels 10 seconds. This is the farthest ball.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(t)=(t-7)(-16t-1)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: This ball traveled 7 seconds. There is another choice that stayed in the air longer. The answer is \(g(t)=(-16t-1)(t-10)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(p(t)=(-8t-1)(2t-5)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The zero is at \(x=52\) seconds. There are other choices that stayed in the air longer. The answer is \(g(t)=(-16t-1)(t-10)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.14.3: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Comparing the Graphs and Equations of Quadratic Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jai kicks a football. The graph that represents the height of the football, \(h\), as a function of time, in seconds, is below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="261" role="presentation" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/d10667556156ef8039bcaf02b8679ef27a889a6f" width="259"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kellan kicks a football and the height in feet, \(h\), is represented by the function \(h(t)=(-16t-1)(t-6)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which player&amp;rsquo;s football stayed in the air longer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jai&amp;rsquo;s football landed after 4 seconds since the zero is at \(x=4\). The other zero, where \(x\) is negative, does not make sense in this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the function of Kellan&amp;rsquo;s ball, find the zeros by setting each factor equal to zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(-16t-1=0\) becomes \(t=-116\). A negative time does not make sense in this problem. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(t-6=0\) becomes \(t=6\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kellan&amp;rsquo;s ball was in the air for 6 seconds, so his ball stayed in the air 2 seconds longer than Jai&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Comparing the Graphs and Equations of Quadratic Functions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the same information above, which player&amp;rsquo;s football reached a higher height?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to determine whose ball went higher:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the graph of Jai&amp;rsquo;s football, his football went about 70 feet high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 1&lt;br&gt;
    For Kellan&amp;rsquo;s football, find the vertex.&lt;br&gt;
    The vertex is halfway between the zeros. Since -116 is near 0 and the other \(x\)-intercept is at 6, we can use 3 as an estimate for the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 2&lt;br&gt;
    Substitute this into the function:&lt;br&gt;
    \(h(t)=(-16(3)-1)((3)-6)=(-49)(-3)=147\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kellan&amp;rsquo;s ball went 147 feet into the air so his football went higher.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4018">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665308159</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4019">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665308159</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1790">
        <prevpageid>1789</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1791</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665308932</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665785342</timemodified>
        <title>7.14.4: Using Quadratic Functions to Solve Problems</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt;Optional Activity (20 Minutes)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This optional activity gives students an additional opportunity to apply what they learned about key characteristics of a quadratic function to solve contextual problems. Unlike in previous activities where an equation or a graph that represents the function was given up front, here students are presented only with a familiar situation and need to consider what relevant details are missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The info gap structure requires students to make sense of problems by determining what information is necessary, and then to ask for information they need to solve it. This may take several rounds of discussion if their first requests do not yield the information they need. It also allows them to refine the language they use and ask increasingly more precise questions until they get the information they need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the text of the cards for reference and planning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Problem Card 1&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiran was timing the flight of his toy rocket. It launches straight up from the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; At how many seconds after launch did the rocket reach the highest point? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The rocket was 8.8 feet above ground on the way up and again on the way down. How many seconds passed between the two times it was 8.8 feet above ground? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Problem Card 2&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How many feet above the ground did the toy rocket go? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Jada suggested they put Kiran&amp;rsquo;s rocket on a platform and then launch the rocket from there. Will the rocket reach 20 feet above ground at its highest point? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Data Card 1&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The stopwatch showed 0 seconds when the toy rocket blasted off from the ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; It landed back on the ground when the stopwatch showed 1.6 seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The second time the rocket reached 8.8 feet, the stopwatch showed 1.1 seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Data Card 2&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The equation modeling the the height of Kiran&amp;rsquo;s toy rocket was \(y=-16x(x-16)\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(y\) represents the height above ground in feet, and \(x\) represents time in seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The platform is 4 feet above ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell students they will continue to work with interpreting graphs and equations of a function in terms of a situation involving toy rockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain the info gap structure, and consider demonstrating the protocol if students are unfamiliar with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of two. In each group, distribute a problem card to one student and a data card to the other student. After reviewing students' work on the first problem, give them the cards for a second problem and instruct partners to switch roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your teacher will give you either a problem card or a data card. Do not show or read your card to your partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your teacher gives you the data card:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Silently read the information on your card. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Ask your partner, "What specific information do you need?" and wait for your partner to ask for information. Only give information that is on your card. (Do not figure out anything for your partner!) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Before telling your partner the information, ask, "Why do you need to know (that piece of information)?" &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Read the problem card and solve the problem independently. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Share the data card and discuss your reasoning. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Pause here so your teacher can review your work. Ask your teacher for a new set of cards and repeat the activity (steps 1&amp;ndash;5) for the next problem, trading roles with your partner. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; When you and your partner have solved both problems, enter your answers to the questions below. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your teacher gives you the problem card:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Silently read your card and think about what information you need to answer the question. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Ask your partner for the specific information that you need. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Explain to your partner how you are using the information to solve the problem. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; When you have enough information, share the problem card with your partner, and solve the problem independently. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Read the data card and discuss your reasoning. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Pause here so your teacher can review your work. Ask your teacher for a new set of cards and repeat the activity (steps 1&amp;ndash;5) for the next problem, trading roles with your partner. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; When you and your partner have solved both problems, enter your answers to the questions below. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are copies of the four cards you used to solve each of the problems. Choose the card that has the matching information you used to solve each problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Problem Card 1&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiran was timing the flight of his toy rocket.&amp;nbsp; It launches straight up from the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; At how many seconds after launch did the rocket reach the highest point? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The rocket was 8.8 feet above ground on the way up and again on the way down. How many seconds passed between the two times it was 8.8 feet above ground? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem Card 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How many feet above the ground did the toy rocket go? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Jada suggested they put Kiran&amp;rsquo;s rocket on a platform and then launch the rocket from there. Will the rocket reach 20 feet above ground at its highest point? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Data Card 1&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The stopwatch showed 0 seconds when the toy rocket blasted off from the ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; It landed back on the ground when the stopwatch showed 1.6 seconds.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The second time the rocket reached 8.8 feet, the stopwatch showed 1.1 seconds.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Data Card 2&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The equation modeling the the height of Kiran&amp;rsquo;s toy rocket was y=-16x(x-16). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(y\) represents the height above ground in feet, and \(x\) represents time in seconds.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The platform is 4 feet above ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Card A&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiran was timing the flight of his toy rocket. It launches straight up from the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; At how many seconds after launch did the rocket reach the highest point? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The rocket was 8.8 feet above ground on the way up and again on the way down. How many seconds passed between the two times it was 8.8 feet above ground? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose the card with the information you used to solve the problem on Card A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Card B&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How many feet above the ground did the toy rocket go? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Jada suggested they put Kiran&amp;rsquo;s rocket on a platform and then launch the rocket from there. Will the rocket reach 20 feet above ground at its highest point? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Card C&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The stopwatch showed 0 seconds when the toy rocket blasted off from the ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; It landed back on the ground when the stopwatch showed 1.6 seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The second time the rocket reached 8.8 feet, the stopwatch showed 1.1 seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Card D&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The equation modeling the the height of Kiran&amp;rsquo;s toy rocket was \(y=-16x(x-16)\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(y\) represents the height above ground in feet, and \(x\) represents time in seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The platform is 4 feet above ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss the different card choices with your partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Card C is Data Card 1. It contains the information needed to solve Problem Card 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Card C&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The stopwatch showed 0 seconds when the toy rocket blasted off from the ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; It landed back on the ground when the stopwatch showed 1.6 seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The second time the rocket reached 8.8 feet, the stopwatch showed 1.1 seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Card B&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How many feet above the ground did the toy rocket go? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Jada suggested they put Kiran&amp;rsquo;s rocket on a platform and then launch the rocket from there. Will the rocket reach 20 feet above ground at its highest point? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose the card with the information you used to solve the problem on Card B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Card A&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiran was timing the flight of his toy rocket. It launches straight up from the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; At how many seconds after launch did the rocket reach the highest point? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The rocket was 8.8 feet above ground on the way up and again on the way down. How many seconds passed between the two times it was 8.8 feet above ground? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Card C&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The stopwatch showed 0 seconds when the toy rocket blasted off from the ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; It landed back on the ground when the stopwatch showed 1.6 seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The second time the rocket reached 8.8 feet, the stopwatch showed 1.1 seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Card D&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The equation modeling the the height of Kiran&amp;rsquo;s toy rocket was \(y=-16x(x-16)\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(y\) represents the height above ground in feet, and \(x\) represents time in seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The platform is 4 feet above ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss the different card choices with your partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Card D is Data Card 2. It contains the information needed to solve Problem Card 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Card D&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The equation modeling the the height of Kiran&amp;rsquo;s toy rocket was \(y=-16x(x-16)\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(y\) represents the height above ground in feet, and \(x\) represents time in seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The platform is 4 feet above ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After students have completed their work, share the correct answers and ask students to discuss the process of solving the problems. Here are some questions for discussion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; "How did you determine when Kiran's rocket reached its highest point?" (The rocket launched at 0 seconds and landed at 1.6 seconds. Those times tell us the \(x\)-intercepts of the graph. The rocket will reach its maximum height at the vertex of the graph, which is halfway between the \(x\)-intercepts.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; "How did you determine how high the rocket went?" (The maximum height is at \(x=0.8\). If we replace \(x\) in the expression \(-16x(x&amp;minus;1.6)\) with 0.8, then \(-16(0.8)(0.8&amp;minus;1.6)=10.24\).) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; "How do you know that the function that models the flight of Kiran's toy rocket is quadratic?" (The equation that models the flight of the rocket has an \(x^2\) term when you write it in standard form.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; "What does the \(-16x^2\) in the equation represent?" (The \(-16x^2\) represents the influence of gravity.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; "If we graphed the equation, what would the point \((0.8, 10.24)\) represent?" (The vertex of the graph.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;What would the equation be to find the height of the rocket if it launches from the 4-foot platform?&amp;rdquo;\((y= -16x(x&amp;minus;1.6)+4)\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlight for students how the information in the problem relates to the vertex and intercepts of the graph and the parts of the equation.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4020">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665308932</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4021">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665308932</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1791">
        <prevpageid>1790</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1792</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665309634</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665783168</timemodified>
        <title>7.14.5: Identifying Key Features of Graphed Functions</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Cool Down (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide continued access to graphing technology, in case students choose to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The equation \(y=(-16t&amp;minus;2)(t&amp;minus;1)\) represents the height in feet of a beach ball thrown by a child as a function of time, \(t\), in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the equation is in factored form, we can tell that the graph intersects the horizontal axis at two points. Use this information to find the zeros of the function. Explain or show your reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Find one of the zeros of the functions using \((-16t&amp;minus;2)\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; -0.125 or \(-\frac{1}{8}\). From the factored form, we can tell that the graph intersects the horizontal axis at \(t=-0.125\) or \(-\frac{1}{8}\). The zero of the function is the same value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Find one of the zeros of the functions using \((t&amp;minus;1)\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 1. From the factored form, we can tell that the graph intersects the horizontal axis at \(t=1\). The zero of the function is the same value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do the zeros tell us in this situation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The zeros mean the time in seconds when the ball is on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are both zeros meaningful?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;No. Only one of them is meaningful. The negative zero doesn't mean anything here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From what height, in feet, is the beach ball thrown? Explain or show your reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 2. The height when \(t=0\) is \((-16(0)&amp;minus;2)(0&amp;minus;1)=(-2)(-1)=2\). If you graph the function, the graph shows a y-intercept of \((0,2)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Response to Student Thinking&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Press Pause&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If students struggle to interpret functions in context, plan to spend extra time on this topic before the assessment by reviewing activities and practice problems.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4022">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665309634</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4023">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665309634</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1792">
        <prevpageid>1791</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1793</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665309686</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665696205</timemodified>
        <title>7.14.6: Practice</title>
        <contents>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will complete the following questions to practice the skills they have learned in this lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here are graphs of functions \(f\) and \(g\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each represents the height of an object being launched into the air as a function of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graphs of functions f and g. Vertical axis, height. Horizontal axis, time. Function f begins low on the y axis, increases in height quickly, then ends at about halfway down the x axis. Function g begins high on the y axis, moves gradually downward, and ends toward the end of the x axis." height="184" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/kjKwgMaM1VtBDGRi8NZKuGYW" width="284"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Which object was launched from a higher point?
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The object represented by function \(f\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The object represented by function \(g\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; The object represented by function \(g\) because its \(y\)-intercept is above the \(y\)-intercept of the graph of \(f\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Which object reached a higher point?
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The object represented by function \(f\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The object represented by function \(g\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; The object represented by function \(f\) because the vertex is higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Which object was launched with the greater upward velocity?
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The object represented by function \(f\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The object represented by function \(g\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; The object represented by function \(f\) because the &amp;ldquo;slope&amp;rdquo; near the \(y\)-intercept is greater. It increases in height much more quickly than the other object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Which object landed last?
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The object represented by function \(f\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The object represented by function \(g\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; The object represented by function \(g\) because the positive \(x\)-intercept of its graph is to the right of the positive \(x\)-intercept of the graph of \(f\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The function \(h\) given by \(h(t)=(1&amp;minus;t)(8+16t)\) models the height of a ball in feet, \(t\) seconds after it was thrown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Find one of the zeros of the functions using \((8+16t)\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; -0.5. From the factored form, we can tell that the graph intersects the horizontal axis at \(t=-0.5\). The zero of the function is the same value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Find one of the zeros of the functions using \((1-t)\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 1. From the factored form, we can tell that the graph intersects the horizontal axis at \((1-t)\). The zero of the function is the same value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What do the zeros tell us in this situation?
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The positive zero means the time, in seconds, when the basketball is on the ground or hits the ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The negative zero represents the height, in feet, when the time is zero. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The positive zero represents the time, in seconds, when the basketball reaches the maximum height. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The negative zero represents the time, in seconds, when the basketball is on the ground or hits the ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; The positive zero means the time, in seconds, when the basketball is on the ground or hits the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Are both zeros meaningful?
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Yes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; No &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; No. Only the positive zero is meaningful. It tells us the ball hits the ground after 1 second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="5" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; From what height, in feet, is the ball thrown? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 8 feet. When \((1&amp;minus;t)(8+16t)\)is rewritten in standard form it is \(8+8t&amp;minus;16t^2\). The constant term (which corresponds to the \(y\)-intercept) tells us the height of the basketball when \(t=0\) or when it is launched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="6" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; When, in seconds, does the ball reach its highest point? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.25 seconds. Graphing \(h\) shows the maximum point at \((0.25,9)\). Or, you could recognize that 0.25 is the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex because it is halfway between the two zeros, -0.5 and 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="7" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How high, in feet, does the ball go? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 9 feet. Graphing \(h\) shows the maximum point at \((0.25,9)\). Or, you could recognize that 0.25 is the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex because it is halfway between the two zeros, -0.5 and 1. Then evaluate the function at 0.25 to get a height of 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The height in feet of a thrown football is modeled by the equation \(f(t)=6+30t&amp;minus;16t^2\), where time \(t\) is measured in seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Which term in the equation describes how many feet above the ground the football was thrown?
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The constant term 6 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The linear term \(30t\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The squared term \(-16t^2\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The squared term \(16t^2\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; The constant term 6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Which term in the equation describes the initial upward velocity of the football in feet per second?
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The constant term 6 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The linear term \(30t\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The squared term \(-16t^2\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The squared term \(16t^2\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; The linear term \(30t\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How does the squared term \(-16t^2\) affect the value of the function \(f\)? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; The squared term decreases the value of the function because the values of \(16t^2\) are being subtracted from \(6+30t\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What does this term \(&amp;minus;16t^2\) reveal about the situation?
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The influence of gravity pulling the ball down to the ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The initial upward velocity of the football. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How far the football was thrown above the ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How long the ball is in the air before it hits the ground. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; The influence of gravity pulling the ball down to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The height in feet of an arrow is modeled by the equation \(h(t)=(1+2t)(18&amp;minus;8t)\), where \(t\) is seconds after the arrow is shot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; At what time, in seconds, does the arrow hit the ground? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;2.25. The positive zero is 2.25 because \((18&amp;minus;8t)\) is equal to zero when \(t=2.25\). The zeros mean the times, in seconds, when the arrow is on the ground. Only the positive zero makes sense. The negative zero would represent a time before the arrow was launched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; At what height, in feet, is the arrow shot? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 18 feet. When the arrow is shot, \(t\) is 0 and \(h(0)=(1+2&amp;sdot;0)(18&amp;minus;8&amp;sdot;0)=(1)(18)=18\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Two objects are launched into the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The height, in feet, of Object A is given by the equation \(f(t)=4+32t&amp;minus;16t^2\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The height, in feet, of Object B is given by the equation \(g(t)=2.5+40t&amp;minus;16^2\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both functions, \(t\) is seconds after launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Which object was launched from a greater height?
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Object A &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Object B &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; Object A. The objects are launched when \(t=0\). \(f(0)=4+32&amp;sdot;0&amp;minus;16(0)2=4\) and \(g(0)=2.5+40&amp;sdot;0&amp;minus;16(0)2=2.5\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Which object was launched with a greater upward velocity?
      &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Object A &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Object B &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; Object B. The coefficient of \(t\) gives the upward velocity and 40 is greater than 32.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4024">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665309686</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4025">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665309686</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1793">
        <prevpageid>1792</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665309891</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665309941</timemodified>
        <title>7.14.7: Lesson Synthesis</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;The examples students saw in this lesson were related to the motion of projectiles. Emphasize that the graphs that represent quadratic functions that model other kinds of situations can also be interpreted in context. For example, in an earlier lesson we saw a quadratic function defined by \(r(d)=d(600-75d)\). It described the revenue in thousands of dollars collected from ticket sales as a function of the price of one ticket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; "What can you tell about the ticket sales and revenue from the equation?" (If the ticket is sold for 0 dollars, or if \(d=0\), the revenue will be 0.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; "In what form is the quadratic expression defining \(r\) written?" (Factored form) "If we rewrite it in standard form, what new information would we gain?" (In standard form, the equation is \(r(d)=60d-75d^2\). It gives us the vertical intercept, but that is not new information. We saw that one of the horizontal intercepts is at \((0,0)\), so the vertical intercept is known.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; "Here is the graph representing the same function. What information does the horizontal intercepts, the vertical intercept, and the vertex of the graph give us?" (The horizontal intercepts tell us that no revenue will be collected if the tickets are sold at $0 and $8. The vertical intercept gives the same information: that if the ticket is free, there will be no revenue. The vertex tells us that the greatest revenue will be collected when the ticket is sold at $4 each, and that amount is $1,200.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Graph of parabola&amp;nbsp; height="179"' height="239" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/S5xjE6Boqvg4CV6WRL2h2bmr" width="328"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4026">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665309891</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4027">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665309891</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>
