<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="31" moduleid="266" modulename="page" contextid="277">
  <page id="31">
    <name>Unit 7 Wrap Up</name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, you learned about machines that students of Howard Bernard created for a Punkin Chunkin competition. While working within a budget as a constraint, students created a machine that would launch a pumpkin the farthest. While creating the machines, students relied on quadratic functions to represent the paths of the pumpkins and tweak their designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of this unit, you explored different patterns that weren’t linear and exponential and discovered how to recognize quadratic functions from geometric patterns. You then used quadratic functions to describe a variety of quadratic situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also learned to write equivalent quadratic expressions in standard, factored, and vertex forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you learned how to graph quadratics using the different forms and that each form helps to find key characteristics about quadratic graphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Building Character: Proactivity&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, you learned that&lt;strong&gt; proactivity&lt;/strong&gt; is important for taking initiative and brainstorming ideas. You discovered that proactivity is a trait that can be learned and comes from a willingness to initiate change. Proactive people are always looking to improve ways of doing things and are often leaders in different settings. They encourage brainstorming of ideas within teams to create solutions to problems.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:2:{s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";s:17:"printlastmodified";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>2</revision>
    <timemodified>1665717611</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>