<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="111" moduleid="147" modulename="lesson" contextid="158">
  <lesson id="111">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Lesson 4.16 Teacher Guide: Sequences are Functions</name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>1</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password></password>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>0</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>150</activitylink>
    <mediafile></mediafile>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>1</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1660691275</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="1013">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1014</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659797591</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662589081</timemodified>
        <title>4.16.0: Lesson Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Narrative&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building on the informal language students have used so far in the unit, the purpose of this lesson is for students to understand that sequences are functions and to use function notation when defining them with equations. In previous lessons, they described the arithmetic sequence 99, 96, 93, . . . as starting at 99 where each term is 3 less than the previous term. Now they think of it as a function \(f\) of the position, starting at position 1, and write \(f(1)=99\) and \(f(n)=f(n-1)-3\) for \(n\geq2\), where \(n\) is an integer. This is called a recursive definition for \(f\) because it describes a repeated, or recurring, process for getting the values of the sequence—namely, the process of subtracting 3 each time. Students will use recursive definitions to describe functions in both mathematical and real-world contexts throughout the remainder of this unit. It is not necessary that they use the term “recursive definition,” however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, definitions of sequences written in function notation are always followed by an inequality that describes the domain of the function, which is particularly helpful when students work with definitions for the term of a sequence and need to indicate what the first term of the sequence is. This is not meant to imply that all students should use such inequalities every time they define a sequence using function notation. In your classroom, it may be better to ask students to write out in words, instead of inequalities, the restrictions on the domain of a sequence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep the focus on writing equations and tell students to be prepared to respond orally when asked about the domain of a sequence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of the lesson is for students to practice interpreting and writing recursive definitions of functions while also representing functions in different ways. Students match sequences and recursive definitions in a matching activity, giving them opportunities to explain their reasoning and critique the reasoning of others. An important part of the activities is giving students time to share and explain their strategies for matching and creating different representations. This helps emphasize that there is often more than one way to approach problems. It also helps establish that sharing strategies and learning from other students are classroom norms.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Learning Goals (Teacher Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Comprehend that sequences are functions whose domain is a subset of the integers.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Create (in writing) a recursive definition for a sequence using function notation.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Create a table, graph, or recursive definition of a sequence from given information.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Determine what information is needed to represent a sequence in different ways. Ask questions to elicit information.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; Learning Targets (Student Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Define arithmetic and geometric sequences recursively using function notation.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Represent a sequence in different ways.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Ask questions to get the information needed to represent a sequence in different ways.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
    &lt;col&gt;
    &lt;col&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TEKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation of Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;A12(C) identify terms of arithmetic and geometric sequences when the sequences are given in function form using recursive processes;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Full coverage: Lesson provides content that covers all parts of this TEKS.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;



&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Lesson Activities&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the instructional activities for the lesson:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4.16.1: Define a Sequence&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4.16.2: What Is a Recursive Definition?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;4.16.2: Self Check&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        4.16.2: Additional Resources
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4.16.3: Ways to Represent a Sequence
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;4.16.3 Self Check&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        4.16.3: Additional Resources
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4.16.4: Geometric Recursive Definitions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will also complete a series of problems in the 4.16.5: Practice.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Graph paper
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Pre-printed slips, cut from copies of the blackline master, card sort
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/1947e7f277dd9f020767cf2c1e941793a92462a6" target="_blank"&gt;Cut card sort for activity&lt;/a&gt; (enough for each pair).
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; Lesson Vocabulary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this lesson, it is important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Familiarize students with the vocabulary words they will see throughout the lesson. Encourage students to look for these words and notice their use and meanings.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Encourage students to use key vocabulary words in “math talk” and their written and oral explanations.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Utilize a word wall. Sample cards are located here: &lt;a href="https://www.doe.virginia.gov/instruction/mathematics/resources/vocab_cards/" target="_blank"&gt;Mathematics Vocabulary Word Wall Cards&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary words that are emphasized in this lesson include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        geometric sequence
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        arithmetic sequence
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        recursive definition
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Support for Building Character&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, find ways to encourage and support students to work on cultivating their &lt;strong&gt;creativity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to try during this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/compound-interest/" target="_blank"&gt;Compound Interest&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/finding-flow/" target="_blank"&gt;Finding Flow&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find other tips located here in the &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/playbooks/creativity" target="_blank"&gt;Playbook on Creativity&lt;/a&gt; from Character Lab.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2272">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659797591</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1014">
        <prevpageid>1013</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1015</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659797763</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662589101</timemodified>
        <title>4.16.1: Define a Sequence</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Warm Up (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this activity is for students to practice defining sequences as arithmetic, geometric, or neither. Several of the sequences selected are ones students have seen previously. The sequence 1, 3, 7, 15, 31, . . . is from the Tower of Hanoi puzzle and is the only sequence in the activity that is neither arithmetic nor geometric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2. After quiet work time, ask students to compare their responses to their partner’s for sequences A and B and decide if they are both correct, even if they are different. Follow with a whole-class discussion.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the first 5 terms of each sequence to state if the sequence is arithmetic, geometric, or neither.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type="A"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
         30, 40, 50, 60, 70, . . .
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
         80, 40, 20, 10, 5, 2.5, . . .
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
         1, 2, 4, 8, 16, 32, . . .
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
         1, \(\frac12\), \(\frac14\), \(\frac18\), \(\frac{1}{16}\), . . .
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
         20, 13, 6, –1, –8, . . .
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
         1, 3, 7, 15, 31, . . .
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol type="A"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Arithmetic
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Geometric
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Geometric
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Geometric
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Arithmetic
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Neither
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this discussion is for students to notice some common features of arithmetic and geometric sequences. Display the six sequences for all to see throughout the discussion to record the sequence type next to each sequence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the sequences A and B, invite previously identified groups to share the sequence type. Repeat this process for the remaining sequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclude the discussion by inviting students to share things they notice about the different sequence types. (The arithmetic sequences have adding or subtracting a term, the geometric sequences have multiplying by a term, and the sequence that is neither is a mix of adding and multiplying.) If not brought up by students, remind them that arithmetic sequences are a type of linear function and geometric sequences are a type of exponential function, so it makes sense to see only addition and subtraction for arithmetic sequences and only multiplication for geometric sequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div style="border:1px solid black; padding:5px; background-color:#f2f2f2;"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use this routine to support whole-class discussion. After each student shares, provide the class with the following sentence frames to help them respond: “I agree because . . .” or “I disagree because . . .” If necessary, re-voice student ideas to demonstrate mathematical language use by restating a statement as a question to clarify, apply appropriate language, and involve more students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2273">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659797763</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2274">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659797763</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1015">
        <prevpageid>1014</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1016</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659799288</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662589173</timemodified>
        <title>4.16.2: What Is a Recursive Definition?</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this partner activity, students take turns matching a sequence to a definition. As students trade roles explaining their thinking and listening, they have opportunities to explain their reasoning and critique the reasoning of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One sequence and one definition do not have matches. Students are tasked with writing the corresponding match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monitor for students using clear reasoning as they create a recursive definition for the sequence 18, 20, 22, 24 to share during the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making a spreadsheet available gives students an opportunity to choose appropriate tools strategically.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2. Tell students that for each sequence, one partner finds its matching recursive definition and explains why they think it matches. The partner’s job is to listen and make sure they agree. If they don’t agree, the partners discuss until they come to an agreement. For the next sequence, the students swap roles. If necessary, demonstrate this protocol before students start working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ensure that students notice that one sequence and one definition do not have matches, and they are tasked with writing the corresponding match for each.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h5&gt; Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div style="border:1px solid black; padding:5px; background-color:#f2f2f2;"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use this routine to support small-group discussion as students should take turns finding a match. Display the following sentence frames for all to see: “Sequence _____ and definition _____ match because . . .” and “I noticed _____, so I matched . . .” Encourage students to challenge each other when they disagree, and to press for precise mathematical language. This will help students clarify their reasoning about each match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Support for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div style="border:1px solid black; padding:5px; background-color:#f2f2f2;"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt; Leverage choice around perceived challenge. Invite groups of students to find matches for at least 4 of the sequences. Chunking this task into more manageable parts may also support students who benefit from additional processing time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;




&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with the recursive definition: \(R(n)=3R(n-1) + 1\), \(n\geq2\) and given \(R(1)=-1\). See the table below for how to substitute to find more terms in the sequence using the recursive definition. Substitute the term number, \(n\), in for \(n\) in the recursive definition. Complete the table with a partner.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="128"&gt;
        &lt;col width="44"&gt;
        &lt;col width="59"&gt;
        &lt;col width="65"&gt;
        &lt;col width="89"&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Term number \((n)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Substitute in \(R(n)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(3R(2-1)+1\)&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(=3R(1)+1\)&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(=3(-1)+1\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(3R(3-1)+1\)&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(=3R(2)+1\)&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(=3(-2)+1\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(3R(4-1)+1\)&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(=3R(3)+1\)&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(=3(-5)+1\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Value&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;–1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;–2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;–5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Using the recursive definition:
        &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                Substitute \(n=5\) in \(R(n)\)
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                Substitute \(n=6\) in \(R(n)\)
                &lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Determine the value for each term:&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
        &lt;li aria-level="2"&gt;
            Value when \(n=4\)
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li aria-level="2"&gt;
            Value when \(n=5\)
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li aria-level="2"&gt;
            Value when \(n=6\)
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Write the full sequence out to 6 terms.&lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Determine if the following sequences are arithmetic or geometric.
        &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                3, 6, 12, 24
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                18, 36, 72, 144
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                3, 8, 13, 18
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                18, 13, 8, 3
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                18, 9, 4.5, 2.25
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                18, 20, 22, 24
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                3, 15, 75, 375
                &lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Next, take turns with your partner to match each sequence with a recursive definition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; For each match that you find, explain to your partner how you know it’s a match. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; For each match that your partner finds, listen carefully to their explanation. If you disagree, discuss your thinking and work to reach an agreement. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Definitions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; \(F(1)=18,F(n)=F(n-1)+2,n\geq2\) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; \(G(1)=18,G(n)=\frac12\cdot G(n-1),n\geq2\) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; \(H(1)=3,H(n)=5\cdot H(n-1),n\geq2\) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; \(J(1)=3,J(n)=J(n-1)+5,n\geq2\) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; \(K(1)=18,K(n)=K(n-1)-5,n\geq2\) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; \(L(1)=18,L(n)=2\cdot L(n-1),n\geq2\) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; \(M(1)=3,M(n)=2\cdot M(n-1),n\geq2\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Responses&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
        &lt;li aria-level="2"&gt; \(3R(5-1)+1\) &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li aria-level="2"&gt; \(3R(6-1)+1\) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
        &lt;li aria-level="2"&gt;–14 &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li aria-level="2"&gt;–41 &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li aria-level="2"&gt;–122 &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;–1, –2, –5, –14, –41, –122 &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                Geometric&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                Geometric
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                Arithmetic
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                Arithmetic
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                Geometric
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                Arithmetic
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
                Geometric
                &lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="255"&gt;
        &lt;col width="369"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Sequence&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Definition&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;ol&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;
                        3, 6, 12, 24
                    &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(M(1)=3,M(n)=2\cdot M(n-1),n\geq2\) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;ol start="2"&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;
                        18, 36, 72, 144
                    &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt; \(L(1)=18,L(n)=2\cdot L(n-1),n\geq2\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;ol start="3"&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;
                        3, 8, 13, 18
                    &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt; \(J(1)=3,J(n)=J(n-1)+5,n\geq2\) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;ol start="4"&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;
                        18, 13, 8, 3
                    &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt; \(K(1)=18,K(n)=K(n-1)-5,n\geq2\) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;ol start="5"&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;
                        18, 9, 4.5, 2.25
                    &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(G(1)=18,G(n)=\frac12\cdot G(n-1),n\geq2\) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;ol start="6"&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;
                        18, 20, 22, 24
                    &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt; \(F(1)=18,F(n)=F(n-1)+2,n\geq2\) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;ol start="7"&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;
                        3, 15, 75, 375
                    &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt; \(H(1)=3,H(n)=5\cdot H(n-1),n\geq2\) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br&gt;



&lt;h4&gt;Video: Learning About Recursive Definitions and Sequences&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch the following video to learn more about matching sequences to their recursive definitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video controls="true" crossorigin="anonymous" width="550"&gt;
    &lt;source src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/1ad29298163115b9ffa0ba588ead0d01ce6e667a"&gt;
    &lt;track src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/72685ed3769bf485d9d077fb87829e1f17f43a0d" kind="captions" srclang="en_us" label="On" default="true"&gt;https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/1ad29298163115b9ffa0ba588ead0d01ce6e667a
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some students may not be sure how to begin matching terms in a sequence to a definition. Encourage them to start by picking a definition and calculating the first few terms of the sequence it represents.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once all groups have completed the matching, ask: “How did you decide which definitions to match to sequence 3, 6, 12, 24 and sequence 18, 36, 72, 144 when they both involve doubling?” (They are both geometric with a growth factor of 2, but since they have different first terms you can use those to match the sequences to M and L.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, invite previously identified students to share the recursive definition they created for sequence 18, 20, 22, 24 and their strategy for writing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If time allows and students need extra practice graphing functions, assign students one function each from the task statement to sketch a graph for. After work time, select students to share their sketches, displaying them for all to see and compare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4.16.2: Self Check&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Following the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="302"&gt;
        &lt;col width="322"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Which of the following sequences matches the recursive definition for \(G(n)\) where \(G(n)=G(n-1)+4\) for \(n\geq2\) when \(G(1)=3\)?&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt; 4, 8, 12, 16, 20&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: The recursive definition adds 4 to the previous number, starting with 3, not 4. The answer is 3, 7, 11, 15.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1, 3, 7, 11, 15&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: \(G(1)=3\) means the first term is 3, so 1 should not be the start of the sequence. The answer is 3, 7, 11, 15.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3, 7, 11, 15&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;That’s correct! Check yourself: The first term is 3, and the recursive definition shows the sequence is arithmetic, so 4 is added to each previous term.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3, 12, 48, 144&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This sequence is geometric, and the given recursive definition creates an arithmetic sequence. The answer is 3, 7, 11, 15.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4.16.2: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Writing Recursive Definitions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we can define a sequence recursively. That is, we can describe how to calculate the next term in a sequence if we know the previous term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a sequence: 6, 10, 14, 18, 22, . . . This is an arithmetic sequence, where each term is 4 more than the previous term. Since sequences are functions, let’s call this sequence \(f\). Then we can use function notation to write \(f(n)=f(n-1)+4\). Here, \(f(n)\) is the term, \(f(n-1)\) is the previous term, and + 4 represents the common difference since f is an arithmetic sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we define a function recursively, we must also say what the first term is. Without that, there would be no way of knowing if the sequence defined by \(f(n)=f(n-1)+4\) started with 6 or 81 or any other number. Here, one possible initial condition is \(f(1)=6\). It could also make sense to number the terms starting with 0, using \(f(0)=6\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combining this information gives the recursive definition: \(f(1)=6\) and \(f(n)=f(n-1)+4\) for \(n\geq2\), where \(n\) is an integer. We include the \(n\geq2\) at the end since the value of \(f\) at 1 is already given, and the other terms in the sequence are generated by inputting integers larger than 1 into the definition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at some examples from the first activity and write the recursive definition for each type of sequence:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        A: 30, 40, 50, 60, 70, . . .
          &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;br&gt;
    Arithmetic&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    \(A(1)=30, A(n)=A(n-1)+10, n\geq2\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        B: 80, 40, 20, 10, 5, 2.5, . . .
          &lt;br&gt;
          &lt;br&gt;
  Geometric&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  \(B(1)=80, B(n)=B(n-1) \frac12, n\geq2\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        F: 1, 3, 7, 15, 31, . . .
          &lt;br&gt;
          &lt;br&gt;
  Neither&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  \(F(1)=1, F(n)=F(n-1)2 + 1, n\geq2\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Writing Recursive Definitions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write \(E(1)\) and a recursive definition for \(E(n)\):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E: 20, 13, 6, –1, –8, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your notebook, write down your answer. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt; Solution&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is how to write the recursive definition for this sequence:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\(E(1)=20\), then each term after is formed by subtracting 7, so \(E(n)=E(n-1)-7\), \(n\geq2\)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did you do? Know that you learn more from wrong answers than from right answers! Wrong answers help us find flaws in our thinking. Take a minute to think about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you got the question wrong. Then you won’t get this type of question wrong again!&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2275">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659799288</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2276">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659799288</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1016">
        <prevpageid>1015</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1017</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659806078</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662754499</timemodified>
        <title>4.16.3: Ways to Represent a Sequence</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (30 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first Info Gap activity in the course. See the launch for extended instructions for facilitating this activity successfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Info Gap activity gives students an opportunity to determine and request the information needed to represent sequences in different ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Info Gap structure requires students to make sense of problems by determining what information is necessary, and then to ask for information they need to solve it. This may take several rounds of discussion if their first requests do not yield the information they need (MP1). It also allows them to refine the language they use and ask increasingly more precise questions until they get the information they need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three pairs of cards are provided for this Info Gap, with the expectation that one pair will be used for a class demonstration of how the Info Gap routine works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the text of the cards for reference and planning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/RoKFbD9qvvhX4aGZicua51Tr" width="624" height="701"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h4&gt; Launch&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell students they will represent sequences in different ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first time students do the Information Gap cards instructional routine, so it is important to demonstrate the routine in a whole-class discussion before they do the routine with each other. For this Info Gap, three sets of cards are provided so that you can demonstrate with one set, leaving two remaining sets so that each student has a chance to work with both the problem card and the data card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explain the Info Gap routine: Students work with a partner. One partner gets a problem card with a math question that doesn’t have enough given information, and the other partner gets a data card with information relevant to the problem card. Students ask each other questions like “What information do you need?” and are expected to explain what they will do with the information. Once the partner with the problem card has enough information to solve the problem, both partners can look at the problem card and solve the problem independently. This graphic illustrates a framework for the routine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/pb2N9BktKT9Fwfg5D9VKyYni" width="624" height="567"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Display Problem Card 1 for all to see. Tell students that, as a class, they are playing the role of the person with the problem card while you play the role of the person with the data card. Explain to students that it is the job of the person with the problem card (in this case, the whole class) to think about what information they need to answer the question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explain that you will be playing the role of the person with the data card. Ask students, “What specific information do you need to represent the first five terms of the sequence?” Select students to ask their questions. Respond to each question with, “Why do you need that information?” Once students provide a mathematically valid reason, provide only data that appear on the data card. Once the class has created the representations asked for on the problem card, also display the data card so that students can see what it looks like. Reiterate that the person with the data card should only provide information that appears on their card, and only after the person with the problem card explains why they need the information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of 2. In each group, distribute a problem card to one student and a data card to the other student. After you review their work on the first problem, give them the cards for a second problem and instruct them to switch roles. Provide access to graph paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt; Support for English Language Learners&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div style="border:1px solid black; padding:5px; background-color:#f2f2f2;"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Display questions or question starters for students who need a starting point, such as: “Can you tell me . . . (specific piece of information),” and ”Why do you need to know . . . (that piece of information)?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Support for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div style="border:1px solid black; padding:5px; background-color:#f2f2f2;"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt; Display or provide students with a physical copy of the written directions. Check for understanding by inviting students to rephrase directions in their own words. Keep the display of directions visible throughout the activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your teacher will give you either a problem card or a data card. Do not show or read your card to your partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your teacher gives you the data card:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Silently read the information on your card.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Ask your partner, “What specific information do you need?” and wait for your partner to ask for information. Only give information that is on your card. (Do not figure out anything for your partner!)
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Before telling your partner the information, ask, “Why do you need to know (that piece of information)?”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Read the problem card and solve the problem independently.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Share the data card and discuss your reasoning.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your teacher gives you the problem card:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Silently read your card and think about what information you need to answer the question.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Ask your partner for the specific information that you need.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Explain to your partner how you are using the information to solve the problem.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        When you have enough information, share the problem card with your partner and solve the problem independently.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Read the data card and discuss your reasoning.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sample responses:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problem Card 1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="85"&gt;
        &lt;col width="93"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(n\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(f(n)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;16&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/sXgfZMYnSwwG4ptmU1VVf5xN" width="172" height="188"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Problem Card 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        2
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b. &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/mNTWkMPZABPGqzMqXJccYXp5" alt="GRAPH WITH PLOTTED POINTS (1, 16), (2, 11), (3, 6), (4, 1), AND (5, NEGATIVE 4). THE POINT (2, 11) IS LABELED Q." width="172" height="188"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problem Card 3:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;\(n\)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;\(Q(n)\)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;16 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;11 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;6 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td valign="top"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;–4 &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. \(Q(1)=16\), \(Q(n)=Q(n−1)−5\) for \(n\geq2\)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Extension&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Are you ready for more?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make a visual pattern (for example, using dots or boxes), starting with Step 0, so the pattern for Step \(n\) contains \(n^2+3n+3\) dots.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4&gt; Extension Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sample response: an \(n+1\) by \(n+2\) rectangle with one additional dot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/73kbrt9aw5TLQdtSM5SDRHxm" width="312" height="110"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After students have completed their work, share the correct answers and ask students to discuss the process of representing the sequences in different ways. Display the cards for all to see throughout the discussion. Some students may be surprised to see the different structures of the cards even though they were about the same topic. Allow time for students to share what questions they found helpful for solving their problem card and how they came up with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlight connections between the representations. For example, a recursive definition might include \(f(1)=16\), which corresponds to an entry in a table and the point \((1,16)\) on a graph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4.16.3: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="302"&gt;
        &lt;col width="322"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Which of the following recursive definitions is represented by the graph below?&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/5a18ffb1e1cf2d053ce1861f58f826d34d5d7dbf" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(a(1)=11\) and \(a(n)=4a(n-1)\) for \(n\geq2\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This recursive definition would give a geometric sequence. The answer is \(a(1)=11\) and \(a(n)=a(n-1)-4\) for \(n\geq2\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(a(1)=11\) and \(a(n)=a(n-1)-4\) for \(n\geq2\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;That’s correct! Check yourself: The recursive definition would give an arithmetic sequence, like the one that is graphed. The terms are 11, 7, 3, –1, –5.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(a(11)=1\) and \(a(n)=a(n-1)-4\) for (n\geq2\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: The first point is \((1,11)\), not \((11,1)\). The answer is \(a(1)=11\) and \(a(n)=a(n-1)-4\) for \(n\geq2\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(a(1)=11\) and \(a(n)=a(n)-4\) for \(n\geq2\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This recursive definition does not account for the previous term. The answer is \(a(1)=11\) and \(a(n)=a(n-1)-4\) for \(n\geq2\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;br&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;4.16.3: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Representing Sequences&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at some more examples for finding the recursive definition of arithmetic and geometric sequences ways to represent them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An arithmetic sequence, \(a\), begins 11, 7, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Write a recursive definition for this sequence using function notation.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Sketch a graph of the first 5 terms of this sequence.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Explain how to use the recursive definition to find \(a(100)\). (Don’t actually determine the value.)
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solutions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        \(a(1)=11, a(n)=a(n-1)-4, n\geq2\)
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/5a18ffb1e1cf2d053ce1861f58f826d34d5d7dbf" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Starting with 11, keep subtracting 4 until you do that 99 times.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example 2:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A geometric sequence, \(g\), starts 80, 40, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Write a recursive definition for this sequence using function notation.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Use your definition to make a table of values for \(g(n)\) for the first 6 terms.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Explain how to use the recursive definition to find \(g(100)\). (Don’t actually determine the value.)
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solutions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        \(g(1)=80, g(n)= \frac12 \cdot g(n-1), n\geq2\)
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(n\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(g(n)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;80&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;40&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;20&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;10&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2.5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Starting with 80, keep dividing by 2 until you do that 99 times.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Representing Sequences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a recursive definition for \(P(n)\), the sequence below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1, 2, 4, 8, 16&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your notebook, write down your answer. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to check your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Here is how to write the recursive definition for \(P(n)\):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First: \(P(1)=1\), then each term is 2 times the previous term, so \(P(n)=2P(n-1), n\geq2\)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;How did you do? Know that you learn more from wrong answers than from right answers! Wrong answers help us find flaws in our thinking. Take a minute to think about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you got the question wrong. Then you won’t get this type of question wrong again!&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2277">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659806078</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2278">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659806078</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1017">
        <prevpageid>1016</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1018</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659806430</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662589266</timemodified>
        <title>4.16.4: Geometric Recursive Definitions</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Cool Down (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Statement&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The geometric sequence \(G\) starts 12, 6, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Write a recursive definition for sequence \(G\).
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Sketch a graph representing the first 5 terms of sequence \(G\).
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h4&gt;Student Response&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    \(g(1)=12,g(n)=0.5⋅g(n−1)\) for \(n\geq2\) or equivalent.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/7drgUBrauk7KrSCWHkhfGdz9" width="172" height="164"&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Response to Student Thinking&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Points to Emphasize&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If students still struggle, plan to spend more time on the launch to 7.2.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2279">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659806430</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2280">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659806430</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1018">
        <prevpageid>1017</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1019</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659807430</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662754649</timemodified>
        <title>4.16.5: Practice </title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Students will complete the following questions to practice the skills they have learned in this lesson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For #1–3, match each sequence with one of the definitions. Note that only the part of the definition showing the relationship between the current term and the previous term is given so as not to give away the solutions.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 6, 12, 18, 24 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;\(c(n)=c(n−1)+6\)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &amp;nbsp;2, 14, 98, 686 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \(a(n)=7 \cdot a(n−1)\)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 160, 80, 40, 20 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \(b(n)=\frac12 b(n−1)\)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For #4–5, select the first five terms of each sequence. Determine whether each sequence is arithmetic, geometric, or neither.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; \(a(1)=7\), \(a(n)=a(n−1)−3\) for \(n\geq2\)
        &lt;ol&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;7, 4, 1, –2, –5, geometric&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;7, –21, 63, –189, geometric&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;7, –21, 63, –189, arithmetic&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;d. 7, 4, 1, –2, –5, arithmetic&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; d. 7, 4, 1, –2, –5, arithmetic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start="5"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;\( c(1)=3\), \(c(n)=10 \cdot c(n−1)\) for \(n\geq2\)
        &lt;ol&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;a. 3, 30, 300, 3000, 30000, arithmetic&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; b. 3, 30, 300, 3000, 30000, geometric&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; c. 3, 13, 23, 33, 43, geometric&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; d. 3, 13, 23, 33, 43, arithmetic&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; b. 3, 30, 300, 3000, 30000, geometric&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For #6–9, match each sequence with one of the recursive definitions. Note that only the part of the definition showing the relationship between the current term and the previous term is given so as not to give away the solutions.&lt;/p&gt;





&lt;ol start="6"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 3, 15, 75, 375, . . . &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \(c(n)=5 \cdot c(n−1)\)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start="7"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 18, 6, 2, \(\frac23\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \(a(n)=\frac13 a(n−1)\)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol start="8"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 1, 2, 4, 7 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \(d(n)=d(n−1)+n−1\)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;ol start="9"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 17, 13, 9, 5 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \(b(n)=b(n−1)−4\)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;ol start="10"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; An arithmetic sequence \(k\) starts 12, 6, . . . and is represented by the graph:&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/b9796b5a8c6fd4e1dbe3f5a42c3f01ad31965ef5" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem; font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;, Roboto, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, &amp;quot;Noto Sans&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Liberation Sans&amp;quot;, sans-serif, &amp;quot;Apple Color Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Symbol&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Noto Color Emoji&amp;quot;;"&gt;Which of the following is a recursive definition for sequence \(k\) when \(n\geq2\)?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;\(k(1)=12, k(n)=k(n)-6
        \)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;\(k(1)=12, k(n)=k(n-1)-6
            \)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;\(k(1)=12, k(n)=k(n-1)+6\)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;\(k(1)=12,6 \cdot k(n)=k(n-1)
        \)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \(k(1)=12, k(n)=k(n-1)-6\)&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2281">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659807430</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2282">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659807430</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1019">
        <prevpageid>1018</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1659807590</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1662589298</timemodified>
        <title>4.16.6: Lesson Synthesis</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;Display this sequence \(J\) for all to see: 2, 8, 32, 128, . . . and give students a few minutes to represent it in as many ways as they can think of. Then, ask them to check in with their partner and see if their partner came up with any different ways. Time permitting, ask one student to demonstrate or explain each type of representation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Using function notation: \(J(1)=2\), \(J(2)=8\), \(J(3)=32\), \(J(4)=128\) where the input is the term number and the output is the value of the term
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Using a table of inputs and outputs
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Writing a recursive definition like \(J(1)=2\), \(J(n)=4J(n-1)\), \(n\geq2\)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Sketching a graph that includes the points \((1,2)\), \((2,8)\), \((3,32)\), \((4,128)\)&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="os-raise-ib-pset" data-fire-success-event="eventnameX" data-fire-learning-opportunity-event="eventnameY" data-retry-limit="1" data-button-text="Submit" data-schema-version="1.0"&gt;&lt;div class="os-raise-ib-pset-problem" data-problem-type="dropdown" data-solution="" data-solution-options="[&amp;quot;1 - I’m totally lost!&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;2 - I could use some more help.&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;3 - I mostly understand.&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;4 - I can do it.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;5 - I’ve got this!&amp;quot;]"&gt;&lt;div class="os-raise-ib-pset-encourage-response"&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;!--Do not edit below line.--&gt;
    &lt;div class="os-raise-ib-pset-correct-response"&gt;
        &lt;!-- INSERT ANY VALID HTML HERE --&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="os-raise-ib-pset-encourage-response"&gt;
        &lt;!-- INSERT ANY VALID HTML HERE --&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="2283">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659807590</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="2284">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1659807590</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>