<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="205" moduleid="273" modulename="lesson" contextid="284">
  <lesson id="205">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Lesson 8.1 Teacher Guide: Finding Unknown Inputs</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>1</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password/>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>0</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>274</activitylink>
    <mediafile/>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>0</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1667072761</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="1878">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1879</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1666130963</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1666329473</timemodified>
        <title>8.1.0: Lesson Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Narrative&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a previous unit, students studied quadratic functions in some depth. They built quadratic expressions to represent situations and wrote equivalent expressions. They also graphed, analyzed, and evaluated quadratic functions to solve problems. In some cases, they investigated and interpreted the outputs of the functions. In others, they looked for the input values that produce certain outputs, and they found these values mainly by reasoning with graphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This unit picks up on where that unit left off. Sometimes we have a relationship that can be expressed with a quadratic function, and we want to know what input generates a particular output. How do we find out other than by graphing and estimating, or by guessing and checking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this lesson, students encounter a problem that cannot be easily solved by familiar strategies. They will write a quadratic equation and interpret what a solution means in the given situation. The work here motivates the need to solve quadratic equations. In the next lesson, students will see some variations on these equations and work with them in context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Goals (Teacher Facing) &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Explain (orally and in writing) the meaning of the solution to a quadratic equation in terms of a situation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Write a quadratic equation that represents geometric constraints. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Targets (Student Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Explain the meaning of a solution to an equation in terms of a situation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Write a quadratic equation that represents a situation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table class="os-raise-standardtable"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TEKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation of Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;A8(A) solve quadratic equations having real solutions by factoring, taking square roots, completing the square, and applying the quadratic formula.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foundational: Lesson provides foundational content necessary for students to be able to perform this TEKS in later lessons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the instructional activities for the lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 8.1.1: Understanding a Situation with Quadratic Equations &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 8.1.2: Modeling a Quadratic Problem 
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 8.1.2: Self Check &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 8.1.2: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 8.1.3: Formulating a Quadratic Equation to Represent the Model 
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 8.1.3: Self Check &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 8.1.3: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 8.1.4: Interpreting a Solution &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will also complete a series of problems in the 8.1.5: Practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Paper and pencil &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Classroom set of scissors (1 per student if possible) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Classroom set of rulers (1 per student if possible) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Cut-outs of a picture measuring 7 inches by 4 inches (1 per student) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Colored paper to represent framing material measuring 4 inches by 2.5 inches (3 per student) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Arrange the cut-out pictures and colored paper as described in the required materials. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Vocabulary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this lesson, it is important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Familiarize students with the vocabulary words they will see throughout the lesson. Encourage students to look for these words and notice their use and meanings. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Encourage students to use key vocabulary words in &amp;ldquo;math talk&amp;rdquo; and their written and oral explanations. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Utilize a word wall. Sample cards are located here: &lt;a href="https://www.doe.virginia.gov/instruction/mathematics/resources/vocab_cards/" target="_blank"&gt;Mathematics Vocabulary Word Wall Cards&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary words that are emphasized in this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table class="os-raise-standardtable"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; quadratic function &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; function &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; quadratic equation &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Support for Building Character&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, find ways to encourage and support students to work on cultivating their curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to try during this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/seeing-red/" target="_blank"&gt;Seeing Red&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/retrieval-practice/" target="_blank"&gt;Retrieval Practice&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other tips located here in the &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/playbooks/curiosity/" target="_blank"&gt;Playbook on Curiosity&lt;/a&gt; from Character Lab.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4219">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666130963</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1879">
        <prevpageid>1878</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1880</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1666133846</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1666264016</timemodified>
        <title>8.1.1: Understanding a Situation with Quadratic Equations </title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Warm Up (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This task reminds students that they can use a graph of a function to gain information about the situation that the function models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every question can be answered, or at least estimated, by analyzing the graph. As students work, look for those who use the given equation to solve or verify the answers. For example, the first question can be answered by evaluating \(h(1)\) and the second question by evaluating \(h(8)\). Invite them to share their strategy during synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given their earlier work on quadratic functions, students should be familiar with projectiles. If needed, give a brief orientation on the context. Tell students that there are devices that use compressed air or other means to generate a great amount of force and launch a potato or similar-sized object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the problem as a class. Allow students to answer the exercises individually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mechanical device is used to launch a potato vertically into the air. The potato is launched from a platform 20 feet above the ground, with an initial vertical velocity of 92 feet per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function \(h(t) = -16t^2 + 92t + 20\) models the height of the potato over the ground, in feet, \(t\) seconds after launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the graph representing the function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height="160" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/NB1dRNXXszkTdxerbFoKb627" width="273"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each question, explain your reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the height of the potato 1 second after launch? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The height of the potato 1 second after launch will be 96 feet.&lt;br&gt;
  Substituting 1 second into the function \(h(t)\) yields:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(\begin{array}{rcl}h(1)&amp;amp;=&amp;amp;-16{(1)}^2+20\\&amp;amp;=&amp;amp;-16+92+20\\&amp;amp;=&amp;amp;96\end{array}\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will the potato still be in the air 8 seconds after launch? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; No, from the graph, we can see the potato will land before 8 seconds after the launch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will the potato reach 120 feet? If so, when will it happen? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, from the graph, we can see the potato&amp;rsquo;s height will be 120 feet at two times: approximately 1.5 seconds and 4.3 seconds after launch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When will the potato hit the ground, or have a height of zero feet? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; We can see from the graph the potato will hit the ground, or have a height of zero feet, after approximately 6 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus the discussion on how students used the graph to help them answer the questions. Encourage students to use precise mathematical vocabulary in their explanation. Invite students, especially those who do not rely solely on the graph, to share their responses and reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point out that we can gather quite a bit of information about the function from the graph, but the information may not be precise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is there a way to get more exact answers rather than estimates?&amp;rdquo; (Some questions can be answered by evaluating the function. For questions that are not easy to calculate at this point, we can only estimate from the graph.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Which questions in the activity could be answered by calculating?&amp;rdquo; (The first two questions, about where the potato is after some specified number of seconds.)&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Which questions were not as easy to figure out by calculation?&amp;rdquo; (Those about when the potato reaches certain heights.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How can we verify the time when the potato is 120 feet above the ground or when, exactly, it hits the ground?&amp;rdquo; (We can find the \(t\) values that make \(h(t)\) equal 120 by looking at the graph and then evaluating the function at those values of \(t\). To find exactly when the potato hits the ground, we would need to find the zeros of \(h\) by solving the equation \(h(t)=0\).) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell students that, in this unit, they will investigate how answers to these questions could be calculated rather than estimated from a graph or approximated by guessing and checking.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4220">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666133846</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4221">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666133846</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1880">
        <prevpageid>1879</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1881</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1666133951</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1666278585</timemodified>
        <title>8.1.2: Modeling a Quadratic Problem </title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (20 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this task is to motivate the need to write and solve a quadratic equation to solve a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students are asked to frame a picture by cutting up a rectangular piece of &amp;ldquo;framing material&amp;rdquo; into strips and arranging it around a picture such that they create a frame with a uniform width. The framing material has a different length-to-width ratio and is smaller than the picture, so students cannot simply center the framing material on the back of the picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students are not expected to succeed in the task through trial and error. They are meant to struggle, just enough to want to know a way to solve the problem that is better than guessing and checking. Some students may try writing an equation to help them figure out the right measurement for the frame, but they don&amp;rsquo;t yet have the knowledge to solve the quadratic equation. The solutions to this equation are irrational, so it is also unlikely that students will find them by chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students if they ever had an artwork or a picture framed at a frame shop. If students are unfamiliar with custom framing, explain that it is very expensive. The framing materials, which are cut to exact specifications, can be costly. The time and labor needed to properly frame a picture further increase the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell students that they are now going to frame a picture, using a sheet of paper as their framing material. The sheet is to be cut such that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; All of it is used. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The framing material does not overlap. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The frame does not cover any part of the picture. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The resulting frame has uniform width all the way around. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distribute to each student:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Scissors &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; A ruler &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The &amp;ldquo;picture&amp;rdquo; measuring 7 inches by 4 inches &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The &amp;ldquo;framing material&amp;rdquo; (colored paper measuring 4 inches by 2.5 inches) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inform students that if they should need it, there will be additional pieces of framing material, in case they wish to start over. Remind them to remove all pieces of the old framing material before cutting the new framing material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your teacher will give you a picture that is 7 inches by 4 inches, a piece of colored paper that measures 4 inches by 2.5 inches representing framing material, a ruler, and a pair of scissors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cut the framing material to create a rectangular frame for the picture. The frame should have the same width all the way around and have no overlaps. All of the framing material should be used with no leftover pieces. The frame should not cover any part of the picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s review the information we know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The picture measures 7 inches by 4 inches. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; There are 10 square inches of framing material. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The frame must be uniform in width. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; All of the framing material must be used. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The frame should not cover any part of the picture. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the process you used to create the frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Here is an example of the process shown in images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height="351" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/5qktc87BDWtYhJ8Fy8bVWd5S" width="624"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have completed the activity, can you think of any mathematical method to solve the problem?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Extension&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Are you ready for more?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Juan says, &amp;ldquo;The perimeter of the picture is 22 inches. If I cut the framing material into 9 pieces, each one being 2.5 inches by \(\frac {4}{9}\) inch, I&amp;rsquo;ll have more than enough material to surround the picture because those pieces would yield \(9 \cdot 2.5\), or 22.5 inches for the frame.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you agree with Juan? Explain your reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; No, Juan is not correct because 9 pieces would not be enough to go around the frame. While the total length of those pieces is enough to surround the picture, he will need at least two pieces for each short side to cover 4 inches and at least 3 pieces for each long side to cover 7 inches. This adds up to 10 pieces, as shown below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height="416" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/5fae4a0aa1dabe1a82fbdbd38464f6c6a71d60b5" width="412"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask a few students to show their &amp;ldquo;frames.&amp;rdquo; Consider asking questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How did you decide how thick the frame should be?&amp;rdquo; (Sample answer: I tried a couple of different widths to see if they would work. I first tried \( \frac {1}{2}\) inch, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t give enough to frame the entire picture. Then, I tried \( \frac {1}{4}\) inch, but that was too thin.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How did you know what width would be too large or too small?&amp;rdquo; (Sample answer: It is hard to tell, but I know that the framing needs to have a linear measurement of at least 22 inches, enough for the entire perimeter of the picture, plus some more length for the corners. If the frame is too thin, there will be extra material. If it is too thick, there won&amp;rsquo;t be enough to get the 22-plus-some-inch length.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How did you determine the width such that no framing materials were left unused? Is it possible to determine this?&amp;rdquo; (Sample answer: I tried to find a way to evenly spread the area of the framing material around the picture, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite sure how to do that.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What frame width did you end up with?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Were all the strips or pieces the same size?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students are likely to share the challenges they encountered along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell students that they will learn strategies that are more effective than trial and error to solve problems such as this one. Using the information they have now, they will be able to write a quadratic equation to represent the given situation, which they can use to calculate the exact width of the picture frame before even cutting anything!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For students who are curious about the solution to the exact width of the picture frame, the solution to the problem is approximately 0.342 inches in width.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;8.1.2: Self Check&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;table class="os-raise-standardtable"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="309"&gt;
&lt;col width="315"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose you want to frame a picture that measures 8 inches by 3 inches. The frame is created from 12 square inches of framing material. The frame must be uniform in width, and all of the framing material must be used. Which statement is true?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;The frame will measure exactly 8 inches by 3 inches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The frame cannot have the same dimensions as the picture. Its dimensions will be longer to include the width of the frame.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;The true statement is that the total area of the framed picture will be 36 square inches: 24 square inches for the picture and 12 square inches for the frame. \(24 + 12 = 36\) square inches.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;The total area of the framed picture will be 24 square inches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The area of the picture by itself is \(8 \cdot 3\), or 24 square inches. The area of the framing material is 12 square inches. To find the total area, these values must be added together. The answer is the total area of the framed picture will be \(24 + 12\), or 36 square inches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;The perimeter of the framed picture will be 22 inches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The perimeter of the picture by itself is \(8 + 8 + 3 + 3\), or 22 inches. The framed picture will have a larger perimeter than 22 inches.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;The true statement is that the total area of the framed picture will be 36 square inches: 24 square inches for the picture and 12 square inches for the frame. \(24 + 12 = 36\) square inches.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;The total area of the framed picture will be 36 square inches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: The area of the picture is \(8 \cdot 3\), or 24 square inches. The area of the frame material is 12 square inches. So, the total area of the framed picture will be \(24 + 12\), or 36 square inches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;8.1.2: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Modeling a Quadratic Problem&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This activity challenges you to complete a very difficult task!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s review the information we know from the picture in the Self Check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The picture measures 8 inches by 3 inches. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; There are 12 square inches of framing material. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The frame must be uniform in width. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; All of the framing material must be used. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The frame should not cover any part of the picture. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What other information can you learn from the situation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The perimeter of the picture is \(8 + 8 + 3 + 3\), or 22 inches. The framed picture will have a perimeter greater than this. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; If the picture is 8 inches by 3 inches, then the area of the picture is \(8 \cdot 3\), or 24 square inches. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Since there are 12 square inches of framing material and all of it must be used, the framed picture will have an area of \(24 + 12\), or 36 square inches. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more you know about the situation, the closer you are to being able to solve this problem mathematically instead of guessing and checking to see if you are correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use this information in later activities to set up a quadratic equation that can be used to solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Modeling a Quadratic Problem&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose you want to frame a different picture that measures 10 inches by 6 inches. The frame is created from 36 square inches of framing material. The frame must be uniform in width, and all of the framing material must be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the perimeter of the picture?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the area of the picture?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What will be the total area of the framed picture?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answers, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to find the missing information about the framed picture:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The perimeter of the picture is \(10 + 10 + 6 + 6 = 32\) inches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The area of the picture is \(10 \cdot 6 = 60\) square inches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The total area of the framed picture will be \(60 + 36 = 96\) square inches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4222">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666133951</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4223">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666133951</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1881">
        <prevpageid>1880</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1882</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1666138148</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1666993218</timemodified>
        <title>8.1.3: Formulating a Quadratic Equation to Represent the Model  </title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (10 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This activity allows students to formulate a mathematical model around the framing task they saw earlier. Students are prompted to write an equation but are not expected to solve it at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prompt to write an equation is left relatively open to allow for different approaches. For instance, students may think in terms of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The length and width of the framed picture. The length is 7 inches plus the width of the frame, \(x\), on either side, which gives \(7 + 2x\). The height is 4 inches plus the same frame width, \(x\), for the top and bottom, which gives \(4 + 2x\). The total area is \(7 \cdot 4 + 4 \cdot (2.5)\), or 38 square inches, so the equation is \((7 + 2x)(4 + 2x) = 38\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The area of the picture plus the area of the frame. The area of the picture is 28 square inches. The area of the frame, in square inches, can be found by decomposing it into &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; four squares (in the corners) that are \(x\) by \(x\), or \(x^2\) each &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; two rectangles that are \(7x\) each (top and bottom) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; two rectangles that are \(4x\) each (left and right). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The equation is \(4x^2+2(7x)+2(4x)+28=38\) or \(4x^2+22x+28=38\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As students work, monitor for different strategies students use. Invite students with contrasting approaches to share later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell students that they will now write an equation to represent the quantities in the framing problem. Consider arranging students in groups of two and asking them to think quietly about the questions before conferring with their partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If students have trouble getting started, suggest that they start by labeling the diagram with relevant lengths. Then, if needed, use scaffolding questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; "How do you determine the area of a picture that is 7 inches by 4 inches?" (Multiply \(7 \cdot 4 = 28\).) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"What is the combined area of the picture and the framing material?" (38 square inches, because \(7 \cdot 4 + 4 \cdot (2.5) = 38\).) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; "What happens to the dimensions of a picture if a frame is added around the outside of the picture?" (It increases.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; "How is the width changed?" (It will be increased by two times the width of the frame.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; "How is the length changed?" (It will be increased by two times the width of the frame.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"How could we show that the frame is the same width all the way around?" (Use the same variable, for example, \(x\), to label the width of the strip of framing on all four sides.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a diagram that shows the picture with a frame that is the same width all the way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is 7 inches by 4 inches. The frame is created from 10 square inches of framing material (in the form of a rectangle measuring 4 inches by 2.5 inches).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height="248" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/QxPTEfQf4tJUo9Qku42JHuGw" width="417"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write an expression to represent the length of the framed picture on its shorter side. Use \(x\) to represent the width of the frame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \(2x + 4\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write an expression to represent the length of the framed picture on its longer side. Use \(x\) to represent the width of the frame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \(2x + 7\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the expressions from the previous exercises to write an equation to represent the relationship between the measurements of the framed picture and its total area. Be prepared to explain what each part of your equation represents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \((2x + 7)(2x + 4) = 38\) or \(4x^2 + 22x + 28 = 38\) (or equivalent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A picture is shown with a frame of uniform width around it. The dimensions of the picture are 7 inches by 4 inches. The width of the frame is x. The total length of the framed picture is 2x + 7. The total width of the framed picture is 2x + 4." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="246" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/abd013d7bc8d0e66787b880a5c8ea907406fea42" width="369"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What would a solution to this equation mean in this situation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; A solution would represent the width of the frame when all of the framing material is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some students may struggle to express the overall length and width of the framed picture because of trouble combining numbers and variables. Consider drawing a segment composed of 3 pieces of length 1.5 inches, 10 inches, and 1.5 inches, and prompting students to find the length of the entire segment. Then, change each 1.5 to an \(x\) and ask for an expression for the length of the entire segment \((10 + 2x)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If students mistake the result of adding \(x\) and \(x\) as \(x^2\), consider drawing a square with side length \(x\) and ask students to write expressions for the perimeter and area. Then, ask them to point out the difference between multiplying to find area and adding to find total length. If needed, draw a few more segments that are decomposed into parts, with each part labeled with a number or a variable expression, and ask students to write expressions for the total length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select students to present their equations and reasoning. If no students bring up one of the strategies shown in the Activity Narrative, bring it up. Consider asking students whether \((7 + 2x)(4 + 2x) = 38\) and \(4x^2 + 22x + 28 = 38\) (or other correct equations that come up) are equivalent and how to check if they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss what a solution to these equations represents. Make sure students understand that a solution reveals the width of the frame when all of the framing material (10 square inches) is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solicit some ideas on how they might go about finding the solution(s). Students may mention:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Graphing the equation \(y = (7 + 2x)(4 + 2x)\) and finding a point on the graph with a \(y\)-coordinate of 38 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Evaluating the expression on one side of the equation at different values of \(x\) until it has a value of 38 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Using a spreadsheet to evaluate the expression at different values of \(x\) and see what values produce an output of 38 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can see that the equations \((7 + 2x)(4 + 2x) = 38\) and \(4x^2 + 22x + 28 = 38\) are each composed of a quadratic expression. Tell students that these are examples of quadratic equations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quadratic equation is defined as one that can be written in the form of \(ax^2 + bx + c = 0\), where \(a\) is not 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They will learn several techniques for using algebra to solve equations like this. In the next lesson, students will work with equations of this form and make sense of them in context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Video: Formulating a Quadratic Equation to Represent the Model&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the following video to learn more about formulating a quadratic equation to represent the model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls="true" crossorigin="anonymous" width="550"&gt;
&lt;source src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/3da5ec1aa9c1847437a0eb534316e26a796642e9"&gt;
&lt;track default="true" kind="captions" label="On" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/c7c85fd780762a181ac98e0c385b3f823cccbe39" srclang="en_us"&gt;https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/3da5ec1aa9c1847437a0eb534316e26a796642e9
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;8.1.3: Self Check&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;table class="os-raise-standardtable"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="304"&gt;
&lt;col width="324"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose a different picture is 5 inches by 5 inches. The frame is created from 11 square inches of framing material. The frame will be uniform in width, and all of the framing material is used. Which equation would you need to solve in order to determine the value of \(x\), the width of the frame?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A square picture has side lengths measuring 5 inches. It is surrounded by a square frame that is uniformly x inches in width." height="231" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/5394a210768633a34f72bc87e1543ce8f6ca230a" width="296"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(4x^2 + 20x + 25 = 36\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's correct! Check yourself: The length of one side of the frame is \(2x + 5\). The area of the framed picture is \((2x + 5)(2x + 5)\). Set this equal to the total area, \(25 + 11\), or 36 square inches. So, the equation to represent the total area is \((2x + 5)(2x + 5) = 36\), or \(4x^2 + 20x + 25 = 36\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(x^2 + 10x + 25 = 36\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let's try again a different way: The length of one side of the frame is \(2x + 5\). So the area of the framed picture is \((2x + 5)(2x + 5)\). Remember to add the product of the inner terms and outer terms when multiplying the binomials. Set this equal to the total area, \(25 + 11\), or 36 square inches. The answer, or the equation to represent the total area, is \((2x + 5)(2x + 5) = 36\), or \(4x^2 + 20x + 25 = 36\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(x^2 + 25 = 11\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let's try again a different way: This represents only part of the frame. The length of one side of the frame is \(2x + 5\). So the area of the framed picture is \((2x + 5)(2x + 5)\). Set this equal to the total area, \(25 + 11\), or 36 square inches. The answer, or the equation to represent the total area, is \((2x + 5)(2x + 5) = 36\), or \(4x^2 + 20x + 25 = 36\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(4x^2 + 20x = 36\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let's try again a different way: The length of one side of the frame is \(2x + 5\). So the area of the framed picture is \((2x + 5)(2x + 5)\). Set this equal to the total area, \(25 + 11\), or 36 square inches. Remember to add the product of the last terms of each binomial when multiplying the two binomials. The answer, or the equation to represent the total area, is \((2x + 5)(2x + 5) = 36\), or \(4x^2 + 20x + 25 = 36\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;8.1.3: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Formulating a Quadratic Equation to Represent the Model&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's look at a similar situation as in the previous activities but using a picture with different measurements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a picture 8 inches by 6 inches. The frame is created from 32 square inches of framing material. The frame will be uniform in width, and all of the framing material is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we write an equation representing the total area of the framed picture?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A FRAMED PICTURE." height="232" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/bf047a5f6cfa1e2bcecc83d87d38dfcd8692117f" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's break down the measurements that we know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let \(x\) represent the thickness of the frame in inches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A rectangular picture has side lengths measuring 8 inches by 6 inches. It is surrounded by a frame that is uniformly x inches in width." height="317" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/dceee0cd555cd3e8fcb6de7750d4a66c50dbda52" width="350"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the picture is 8 inches by 6 inches, it has an area of 48 square inches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frame is created from 32 square inches of framing material, and we must use all of it. So, the total area of the framed picture is \(48 + 32\), or 80 square inches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The length of one side of the framed picture is \(x + 6 + x = 2x + 6\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A DIAGRAM REPRESENTING A RECTANGULAR PICTURE INSIDE A RECTANGULAR PICTURE FRAME IS SHOWN. THE RECTANGULAR PICTURE FRAME HAS A SIDE LENGTH OF 6 INCHES AND X AND X LABELED." height="232" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/03fd8be04c40854d0d85e8ca821618315df14678" width="350"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The length of the other side of the framed picture is \(x + 8 + x = 2x + 8\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A DIAGRAM REPRESENTING A RECTANGULAR PICTURE INSIDE A RECTANGULAR PICTURE FRAME IS SHOWN. THE RECTANGULAR PICTURE FRAME HAS A SIDE LENGTH OF 8 INCHES AND X AND X LABELED." height="291" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/c0de4d3970e836136536fbfcd0fbc25e4fcb56f9" width="300"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the area of the framed picture is \((2x + 8)(2x + 6)\). We can set this equal to 80 square inches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\((2x + 8)(2x + 6) = 80\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's multiply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(4x^2 + 12x + 16x + 48 = 80\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(4x^2 + 28x + 48 = 80\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the equation representing the total area of the framed picture is \(4x^2 + 28x + 48 = 80\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This equation is a quadratic equation. A quadratic equation is defined as one that can be written in the form of \(ax^2 + bx + c = 0\) where \(a\) is not 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Formulating a Quadratic Equation to Represent the Model&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A picture measures 9 inches by 7 inches. Its frame is created from 36 square inches of framing material. The frame will be uniform in width, and all of the framing material is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write an equation representing the total area of the framed picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to find the quadratic equation to represent the total area of the framed picture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The area of the picture is 63 square inches. The total area of the framed picture will be \(63 + 36\), or 99 square inches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sides of the framed picture are represented by \((2x + 9)\) and \((2x + 7)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the total area of the framed picture is represented by \(4x^2 + 32x + 63 = 99\).&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4224">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666138148</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4225">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666138148</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1882">
        <prevpageid>1881</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1883</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1666138576</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1666188926</timemodified>
        <title>8.1.4: Interpreting a Solution</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Cool Down (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A framed picture has a total area \(y\), in square inches. The thickness of the frame is represented by \(x\), in inches. The equation \(y = (2x + 8)(2x + 10)\) relates these two variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the width, or shorter side, of the picture without the frame?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 8 inches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the length, or longer side, of the picture without the frame?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 10 inches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What would a solution to the equation \(100 = (2x + 8)(2x + 10)\) mean in this situation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The solution would represent the thickness of a frame that results in a total area of 100 square inches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Response to Student Thinking&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;More Chances&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will have more opportunities to understand the mathematical ideas in this cool down, so there is no need to slow down or add additional work to the next lessons. Instead, use the results of this cool down to provide guidance for what to look for and emphasize over the next several lessons to support students in advancing their current understanding.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4226">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666138576</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4227">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666138576</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1883">
        <prevpageid>1882</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1884</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1666139273</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1666914795</timemodified>
        <title>8.1.5: Practice</title>
        <contents>&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will complete the following questions to practice the skills they have learned in this lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the following to answer questions 1&amp;ndash;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A water balloon is launched by a catapult into the air. The water balloon is launched from 4 feet above the ground, with an initial vertical velocity of 40 feet per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function \(h(t)=-16t^2 + 40t + 4\) models the height of the water balloon over the ground, in feet, \(t\) seconds after launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A DOWNWARD PARABOLA. X-AXIS LABEL IS TIME IN SECONDS AND Y-AXIS LABEL IS HEIGHT IN FEET. THE GRAPH PASSES THROUGH THE POINTS (0, 4), (0.5, 20), (1, 28), (1.5, 28), (2, 20), AND (2.5, 4)." class="img-fluid atto_image_button_text-bottom" height="272" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/796834755c9625082b6b6d76fe2c1c69b585dd60" width="260"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the height of the water balloon 1 second after launch?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 18 feet &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 22 feet &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 28 feet &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 34 feet &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 28 feet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will the water balloon still be in the air 2 seconds after the launch?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Yes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; No &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the graph, estimate when the water balloon hit the ground.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 1.2 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 1.8 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 2.1 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 2.6 seconds &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.6 seconds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the following to answer questions 4&amp;ndash;5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose you want to frame a different picture that measures 12 inches by 9 inches. The frame is created from 46 square inches of framing material. The frame must be uniform in width, and all of the framing material must be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which of the following is true about the situation described?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The perimeter of the picture is 40 inches. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The perimeter of the framed picture is 42 inches. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The area of the framed picture is 148 square inches. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The perimeter of the framed picture is greater than 42 inches. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The perimeter of the framed picture is greater than 42 inches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="5"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the total area of the framed picture?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 46 square inches &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 108 square inches &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 154 square inches &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 176 square inches &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 154 square inches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the following to answer questions 6&amp;ndash;8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose you want to frame a different picture that measures 9 inches by 8 inches. The frame is created from 38 square inches of framing material. The frame must be uniform in width, and all of the framing material must be used. Let \(x\) represent the thickness of the frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="6"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the total area of the framed picture?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 34 square inches &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 72 square inches &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 110 square inches &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 134 square inches &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 110 square inches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="7"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write an equation to represent the relationship between the measurements of the picture and of the frame and the area of the framed picture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(x^2 + 34x = 38\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(4x^2 + 34x = 72\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(x^2 + 34x + 72 = 110\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(4x^2 + 34x + 72 = 110\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(4x^2 + 34x + 72 = 110\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="8"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does the solution to the equation in the previous question represent in this situation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The solution represents the area of the framing material that should be used. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The solution represents the thickness of the frame when all of the framing material is used. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The solution represents the perimeter of the frame when all of the framing material is used. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The solution represents the total area of the framed picture. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;The solution represents the thickness of the frame when all of the framing material is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the following to answer questions 9&amp;ndash;10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A framed picture has a total area \(y\), in square inches. The thickness of the frame is represented by \(x\), in inches. The equation \(y = (2x + 5)(2x + 7)\) relates these two variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="9"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the width and length of the picture without the frame?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 2 inches and 2 inches &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 2 inches and 5 inches &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 2 inches and 7 inches &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 5 inches and 7 inches &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 5 inches and 7 inches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="os-raise-noindent" start="10"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which of the following represents the area of the frame?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(y - 35\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(x + y\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(x + 35\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 35 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(y - 35\)&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4228">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666139273</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4229">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666139273</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1884">
        <prevpageid>1883</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1666139467</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1666268534</timemodified>
        <title>8.1.6: Lesson Synthesis</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;To highlight reasons for writing and solving an equation, discuss questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="os-raise-indent"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In this lesson, we saw a few examples where we knew the output of a function and were interested in finding the input that produced it. In the launched potato situation, what outputs were known?&amp;rdquo; (The potato&amp;rsquo;s heights or distances from the ground.) &amp;ldquo;What inputs did we want to know?&amp;rdquo; (The times at which the potato was at certain heights.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the framing problem, what was the output that we cared about?&amp;rdquo; (The total area of the framed picture, which was 38 square inches.) &amp;ldquo;What information was the input?&amp;rdquo; (The width of the frame that would produce that total area.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why might it be helpful to write an equation to represent a problem such as the one about framing?&amp;rdquo; (An equation helps us see the relationship between the quantities in the problem, including those whose values are unknown. We can solve for those values.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the framing situation, if \(x\) represents the width of the frame, in inches, what would a solution to the equation \((2x + 7)(2x + 4) = 50\) mean?&amp;rdquo; (The width of the frame would produce a total area of 50 square inches.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Equations such as \((2x + 7)(2x + 4) = 50\) and \(4x^2 + 22x + 28 = 38\) are called quadratic equations. Why do you think equations like these are described as quadratic?&amp;rdquo; (Each equation has a quadratic expression in it. Each one relates quantities in a quadratic function.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quadratic equations will be defined more formally in the next lesson. It is fine and expected that students have an informal or partial understanding of what they are at this point.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="4230">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666139467</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="4231">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1666139467</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>
