<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="188" moduleid="251" modulename="lesson" contextid="262">
  <lesson id="188">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Lesson 7.11 Teacher Guide: Graphing from the Factored Form</name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>1</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password></password>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>0</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>252</activitylink>
    <mediafile></mediafile>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>0</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1665638503</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="1728">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1729</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665067399</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665675114</timemodified>
        <title>7.11.0: Lesson Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Lesson Narrative&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an earlier lesson, students noticed a connection between the numbers in a quadratic expression in factored form (for example, the "2" and "8" in \((X+2)(X-8)\)) and the \(x\)-intercepts of the graph. In this lesson, they explore that connection further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to this point, students have not looked closely at how the addition and subtraction symbols in the factors affect the \(x\)-intercepts. They also have not considered how or why the connection works, or whether it is a reliable way to determine the \(x\)-intercepts. In this lesson, they verify their observations by evaluating the expressions at certain \(x\)-values and seeing if they produce an output of 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students also explore what the factored form can tell us about the vertex and the \(y\)-intercept of a graph representing a quadratic function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Goals (Teacher Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Create graphs of quadratic functions that are in factored form. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Given a quadratic function in factored form, explain how to determine the vertex and \(y\)-intercept of its graph. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Targets (Student Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Graph a quadratic function given in factored form. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Find the vertex and \(y\)-intercept of the graph of a quadratic function in factored form without graphing it first. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
  &lt;colgroup&gt;
  &lt;col&gt;
  &lt;col&gt;
  &lt;/colgroup&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TEKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation of Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;A7(A) &lt;u&gt;graph quadratic functions on the coordinate plane and use the graph to identify key attributes, if possible, including \(x\)-intercept, \(y\)-intercept, zeros, &lt;/u&gt;maximum value, minimum values, &lt;u&gt;vertex&lt;/u&gt;, and the equation of the axis of symmetry;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Partial coverage: Lesson provides content that covers part of this TEKS. The parts that are covered have been underlined.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;A7(B) describe the relationship between the linear factors of quadratic expressions and the zeros of their associated quadratic functions;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Full coverage: Lesson provides content that covers all parts of this TEKS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the instructional activities for the lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; 7.11.1: Finding Coordinates &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; 7.11.2: The Factored Form of a Quadratic Expression and the \(X\)-Intercepts of Its Graph &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 7.11.2: Self Check&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 7.11.2: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; 7.11.3: Sketching a Graph of a Quadratic Function Using at Least Three Identifiable Points &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 7.11.3: Self Check&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; 7.11.3: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; 7.11.4: Graphs of Quadratic Functions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will also complete a series of problems in the 7.11.5: Practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Colored pencils &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Graphing paper or coordinate grids &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Graphing technology &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acquire devices that can run Desmos (recommended) or other graphing technology. It is ideal if each student has their own device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digital version of the activity "Sketching a Graph of a Quadratic Function Using at Least Three Identifiable Points" has an applet in the launch to display for all to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colored pencils are optional for the activity "The Factored Form of a Quadratic Expression and the \(X\)-Intercepts of Its Graph."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Vocabulary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this lesson, it is important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Familiarize students with the vocabulary words they will see throughout the lesson. Encourage students to look for these words and notice their use and meanings. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Encourage students to use key vocabulary words in “math talk” and their written and oral explanations. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Utilize a word wall. Sample cards are located here: &lt;a href="https://www.doe.virginia.gov/instruction/mathematics/resources/vocab_cards/" target="_blank"&gt;Mathematics Vocabulary Word Wall Cards&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary words that are emphasized in this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
  &lt;colgroup&gt;
  &lt;col&gt;
  &lt;col&gt;
  &lt;/colgroup&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td valign="top"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt; factor &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt; equation&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt; expression &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt; quadratic function &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt; vertex &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt; \(x\)-intercept &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt; \(y\)-intercept &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td valign="top"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt; none &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Support for Building Character&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, find ways to encourage and support students to work on cultivating their proactivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to try during this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/the-peak-end-rule/" target="_blank"&gt;The Peak-End Rule&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/great-expectations/" target="_blank"&gt;Great Expectations&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other tips located here in the &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/playbooks/proactivity/" target="_blank"&gt;Playbook on Proactivity&lt;/a&gt; from Character Lab.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3882">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665067399</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1729">
        <prevpageid>1728</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1730</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665067431</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665068759</timemodified>
        <title>7.11.1: Finding Coordinates</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Warm Up (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This warm up refreshes the work in lesson 7.10. It prepares students to deepen their understanding of the factored form and the intercepts of a graph that represents a quadratic function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As students work, notice how they find the \(y\)-coordinate of the \(y\)-intercept. Identify students who do so by evaluating w(0). Ask them to share during a whole-class discussion. If a student is struggling to start, remind them they know how to find the intercept of a factored quadratic from 7.10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of two. Give students quiet work time and then time to share their work with a partner. Follow with a whole-class discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a graph of a function \(w\) defined by \(w(x)=(x+1.6)(x-2)\). Three points on the graph are labeled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/StXkTHsn6Sfi53JPgdryPpEF" width="254" height="206"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the graph to answer the following questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find the value of \(a\). Be prepared to explain your reasoning.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; -1.6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find the value of \(b\). Be prepared to explain your reasoning.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find the value of \(c\). Be prepared to explain your reasoning.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find the value of \(d\). Be prepared to explain your reasoning.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="5"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find the value of \(e\). Be prepared to explain your reasoning.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="6"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find the value of \(f\). Be prepared to explain your reasoning.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;-3.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some students may think that the numerical values in the equation correspond directly to the \(x\)-intercepts in the graph and incorrectly state that \(a=-2\) and \(c=1.6\). Remind them that a graph shows all pairs of \(x\)- and \(y\)-values that make the equation true. Consider asking these students to try substituting -2 for \(x\) and evaluating the expression to verify that \(w(-2)=0\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will have opportunities to attend to the signs or the operations in quadratic expressions in factored form, so it is not essential that this misconception is corrected at this moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite students to share their responses and reasoning. If not mentioned in students' explanations, emphasize that:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; \(b\) and \(d\) must be 0 because the \(y\)-coordinate of the \(x\)-intercepts of the graph of any function is 0. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; \(e\) must be 0 because the \(x\)-coordinate of the \(y\)-intercept of the graph of any function is 0. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; \(a\) and \(c\) correspond to the "1.6" and "2" in the factored expression. Students may reason that the graph shows that the positive \(x\)-intercept is farther away from 0 than the negative \(x\)-intercept, suggesting that \(c\) is 2 and \(a\) is -1.6. They may also use their observations from an earlier lesson: that when a factor in the expression shows a negative sign or subtraction, a corresponding intercept takes a positive value, and when a factor shows a positive sign or addition, a corresponding intercept takes a negative value. Either explanation is reasonable at this point. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; \((0,f)\) is the \(y\)-intercept, so the value of \(f\) would be found by evaluating \(w(0)\), which is -3.2, because \((0+1.6)(0-2)=(1.6)(-2)=-3.2\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3883">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665067431</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3884">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665067431</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1730">
        <prevpageid>1729</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1731</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665068819</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665732114</timemodified>
        <title>7.11.2: The Factored Form of a Quadratic Expression and the X-Intercepts of Its Graph</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this activity, students continue to make sense of their earlier observations about the connection between the factored form of a quadratic expression and the \(x\)-intercepts of its graph. They study two very similar expressions: x(x+4) and x(x-4). They evaluate each at different \(x\)-values. The expressions are chosen so that students can shift their focus from the numbers to the operations, attending to precision along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students notice that for \(x(x+4)\), the \(x\)-values that produce a 0 output are 0 and -4, and for \(x(x-4)\), those values are 0 and 4. This helps to explain why the signs of the \(x\)-intercepts are the opposite of the signs in the factors. In an upcoming unit, they will further develop this understanding algebraically, in terms of the zero product property. For now, it suffices that they verify the \(x\)-intercepts by evaluating the quadratic expression at the predicted values and checking that the outputs are 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students also observe, by looking for regularity in repeated reasoning, that the horizontal location of the vertex of the graph can be identified once the \(x\)-intercepts are known: it is exactly halfway between the intercepts. This suggests that a quadratic expression in factored form can help us "see" both the \(x\)-coordinates of the \(x\)-intercepts and the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex of the graph. Some students may notice the horizontal location of the vertex could be determined using the halfway point between any two points with the same \(y\)-coordinate because the graphs have reflection symmetry across a vertical line through the vertex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As students work, look for those who use the table to determine the \(x\)-intercepts, rather than by plotting the points first. Invite those students to share their strategy during the synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this activity, students are generalizing the relationship between the zeros on the graph of a function and the factored form of the function so technology is not an appropriate tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Display for all to see the equations defining \(f\) and \(g\):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(f(x)=x(x+4)\) and \(g(x)=x(x-4)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poll the class to gather some predictions about the graphs that represent the two functions and display the results for all to see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; In what ways would the graphs be alike? &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; In what ways would they be different? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of two. Ask partners to split the work on the first question (with one person analyzing function \(f\) and the other person analyzing function \(g\)) and then working together to plot the points and make observations in the last question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If needed, remind students that the vertex of a graph is the point at which the graph changes direction from increasing to decreasing, or from decreasing to increasing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this activity was designed to be completed without technology, ask students to put away any devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If desired, distribute coordinate grids (or graph paper) and colored pencils so that each student has access to two different colors for creating their graphs in the last question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider two functions defined by \(f(x)=x(x+4)\) and \(g(x)=x(x-4)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Consider the function defined by \(f(x)=x(x+4)\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the table to answer questions a–g to complete the table of values for the function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="os-raise-standardtable"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="51"&gt;
        &lt;col width="108"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(x\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(f(x)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;a. _____&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;b. _____&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;c. _____&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;d. _____&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;e. _____&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;f. _____&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;32&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;g. _____&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; When the value of \(x=-4\), what is the value of \(f(x)\)? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 0
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="2"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;When the value of \(x=-3\), what is the value of \(f(x)\)? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; -3
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="3"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; When the value of \(x=0\), what is the value of \(f(x)\)? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 0
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="4"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;When the value of \(x=1\), what is the value of \(f(x)\)? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 5
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="5"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; When the value of \(x=2\), what is the value of \(f(x)\)? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;12
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="6"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; When the value of \(x=3\), what is the value of \(f(x)\)? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;21
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="7"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; When the value of \(x=5\), what is the value of \(f(x)\)? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;45
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Now, answer questions a–d to analyze the function defined by \(f(x)=x(x+4)\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; What are the \(x\)-intercepts of the graph? Explain your reasoning. &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; The \(x\)-intercepts for function \(f\) are \((-4,0)\) and \((0,0)\). These points have an \(x\)-coordinate that makes the output value 0.
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="2"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; What is the value of the \(x\)-coordinate in the vertex of the graph? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; -2
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; What is the value of the \(y\)-coordinate in the vertex of the graph? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; -4
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol start="4" type="a"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; What is the vertex of the graph of function \(f\)? Explain your reasoning. &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt;The vertex appears to be at \((-2,-4)\). From the tables, the function values seem to change from decreasing to increasing at those points.
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Consider the function defined by \(g(x)=x(x-4)\).&lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        Use the table to answer questions a–g to complete the table of values for the function.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;table class="os-raise-standardtable"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="51"&gt;
        &lt;col width="108"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(x\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(g(x)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;45&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;a. _____&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;b. _____&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;12&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;c. _____&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;d. _____&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;e. _____&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;f. _____&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;g. _____&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; When the value of \(x=-4\), what is the value of \(g(x)\)? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 32
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; When the value of \(x=-3\), what is the value of \(g(x)\)? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 21
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="3"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; When the value of \(x=0\), what is the value of \(g(x)\)? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 0
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="4"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; When the value of \(x=1\), what is the value of \(g(x)\)? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; -3
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="5"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; When the value of \(x=2\), what is the value of \(g(x)\)? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; -4
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol start="6" type="a"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; When the value of \(x=4\), what is the value of \(g(x)\)? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 0
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="7"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; When the value of \(x=5\), what is the value of \(g(x)\)? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 5
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Now, answer questions a–d to analyze the function defined by \(g(x)=x(x-4)\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; What are the \(x\)-intercepts of the graph? Explain your reasoning. &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; The \(x\)-intercepts for function \(g\) are \((0,0)\) and \((4,0)\). These points have an \(x\)-coordinate that makes the output value 0.
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="2"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; What is the value of the \(x\)-coordinate in the vertex of the graph? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 2
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="3"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; What is the value of the \(y\)-coordinate in the vertex of the graph? &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; -4
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="4"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; What is the vertex of the graph of function \(g\)? Explain your reasoning. &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;The vertex appears to be at \((2,-4)\). From the tables, the function values seem to change from decreasing to increasing at those points.
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="5"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Use the graphing tool or technology outside the course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; Plot the points from the tables on the same coordinate plane. (Consider using different colors or markings for each set of points so you can tell them apart.) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/vYj6gcx3w5HkepXjWH6nw41q" alt="Coordinate grid with two graphs shown by plotted points." width="262" height="267"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="2"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; Make a couple of observations about how the two graphs compare. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; The \(x\)-intercept of both graphs is at \((0,0)\). &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; The graphs seem to be a reflection of each other across the \(y\)-axis. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; The vertices both have a \(y\)-coordinate of -4 and also mirror one another across the \(y\)-axis. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Each function mirrors itself across a vertical line through its vertex. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Activity Synthesis &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss how students use the completed tables to help them find the \(x\)-intercepts and the vertex of each graph. If not already mentioned in students' explanations, highlight that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; The \(x\)-values that produce 0 for the output are the zeros of the function. They tell us where the graph intersects the \(x\)-axis. For \(f(x)=x(x+4)\), those values are 0 and -4, so the \(x\)-intercepts are \((0,0)\) and \((-4,0)\). For \(g(x)=x(x-4)\), those values are 0 and 4, so the \(x\)-intercepts are \((0,0)\) and \((-4,0)\). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; The vertex tells us the point where the function reaches its maximum or minimum value. We can see the minimum value in each table. In the first table, \(f(-2)\) is the lowest value. Because the values on one side of \(f(-2)\) mirror those on the other, we can reason that -4 is the lowest value of the function \(f\). In the second table, \(g(2)\) is the lowest value. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; The vertex is halfway between each pair of \(x\)-intercepts. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If time permits, consider asking students how they think the graphs of the functions given by \(p(x)=(x-1)(x-3)\) and \(q(x)=(x+1)(x+3)\) will compare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; "Where will their \(x\)-intercepts be?" (\((1,0)\) and \((3,0)\) for the graph of function \(p\), and \((-1,0)\) and \((-3,0)\) for the graph of function \(q\).) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; "Where will the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex of each graph be?" (2 for the graph of \(p\) and -2 for that of \(q\).) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; "How do we find the \(y\)-coordinate of the vertex?" (Evaluate \(p(2)\) and \(q(-2)\).) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; "The \(y\)-intercept of both graphs is \((0,3)\). What is another point on each graph with the same \(y\)-coordinate?" (The point 2 units to the right of the vertex of \(p\) will have the same \(y\)-coordinate, so \((4,3)\). The point (-4,3) is on the graph of \(q\).) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clarify that a table of values won't always show the maximum or minimum values of a function. It also won't always help us identify the \(x\)-intercepts of a graph or the zeros of a quadratic function, especially if the zeros are not integers or the given expressions are more complex. Students will learn other ways to find the zeros of any function in another unit later in the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.11.2: Self Check&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class="os-raise-standardtable"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col width="302"&gt;
        &lt;col width="322"&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;The table for function \(f\) is below. What is the vertex of the graph of \(f\)?&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
                    &lt;colgroup&gt;
                        &lt;col&gt;
                        &lt;col&gt;
                        &lt;col&gt;
                        &lt;col&gt;
                        &lt;col&gt;
                        &lt;col&gt;
                        &lt;col&gt;
                    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
                    &lt;tbody&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;\(x\)&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;-3&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;-2&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;-1&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;\(f(x)\)&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;-1&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;-3&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;-1&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;/tbody&gt;
                &lt;/table&gt;
                &lt;br&gt;
                &lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\((-3, 0)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This is an \(x\)-intercept. The answer is \((-1, -3)\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\((0,-1)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This is the \(y\)-intercept. The answer is \((-1, -3)\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\((-1, -3)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;That’s correct! Check yourself: The graph mirrors itself with the points \((-2, -1)\) and \((0,-1)\), so it appears that \((-1, -3)\) is the vertex of the parabola.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\((1, 0)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This is an \(x\)-intercept. The answer is \((-1, -3)\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.11.2: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Determining Parts of a Graph from a Table&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify the \(x\)-intercepts and vertex of the quadratic from the table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="os-raise-standardtable"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(x\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-3&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(f(x)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;16&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;16&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The \(x\)-intercepts are where the \(y\)-values are 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This occurs at \((-3,0)\) and \((0,0)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vertex occurs where the function will create a mirror image, or be symmetrical for all points. This often occurs halfway between the two zeros (when there are two zeros).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this function, the vertex is at \((-1,-2)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt; Try It: Determining Parts of a Graph from a Table &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Determine the vertex from the table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="os-raise-standardtable"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(x\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;9&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;10&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(f(x)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;-2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to determine the vertex from the table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The zeros are located at \((5, 0)\) and \((9, 0)\).
    The vertex will be halfway between the two zeros. This occurs at \(x = 7\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point in the table at \(x = 7\) is \((7, 8)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the vertex.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3885">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665068819</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3886">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665068819</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1731">
        <prevpageid>1730</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1732</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665075260</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665754962</timemodified>
        <title>7.11.3: Sketching a Graph of a Quadratic Function Using at Least Three Identifiable Points</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this activity, students apply what they learned in earlier lessons to identify the \(x\)-intercepts and the vertex of the graphs representing several quadratic functions. For example, they saw that the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex is always halfway between those of the \(x\)-intercepts, and the coordinate pairs on one side of the vertex mirror those on the other side. These observations help students locate the vertex of a graph once the \(x\)-intercepts are known, and ultimately to sketch a graph of a quadratic function using at least three identifiable points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The given expressions here are in factored form, but some are unlike what students have previously seen, so students will need to transfer and generalize the reasoning strategies from earlier work. They also use graphing technology to graph the functions and check their predictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a later lesson, students will use the symmetry of the graph of a quadratic function to sketch graphs when they know the vertex and one additional point rather than the vertex and \(x\)-intercepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of two to four. Provide access to devices that can run Desmos or other graphing technology. Give students a few minutes of quiet time to think about the first question. Then, ask them to discuss their response and to complete the second question with their group. (Emphasize that students are expected to make the predictions in the first question before using their graphing tool.) To save time, consider asking groups to split the graphing work (each group member graphs only one function and analyze the graphs together).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If students have not yet learned how to use the graphing tools at their disposal to trace a graph or otherwise identify its intercepts and vertex (or other points on the graph), consider demonstrating this during the graphing portion of the activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask students to attempt the last question (sketching the graph of a function) without using technology. They could use technology to check their sketch afterward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The functions \(f\), \(g\), and \(h\) are given. Refer to these functions to complete questions a–f.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(x\)-intercepts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(x\)-coordinate of the vertex&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(f(x)=(x+3)(x-5)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt; _____ &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt; _____ &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(g(x)=2x(x-3)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt; _____ &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;ol start="4" type="a"&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt; _____ &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\(h(x)=(x+4)(4-x)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;ol start="5" type="a"&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt; _____ &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;ol start="6" type="a"&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt; _____ &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; Predict the \(x\)-intercepts for function \(f(x)=(x+3)(x-5)\).&amp;nbsp; &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;\(x\)-intercepts for function \(f\): \((-3,0)\) and \((5,0)\)
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="2"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; Predict the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex for function \(f(x)=(x+3)(x-5)\).&amp;nbsp; &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 1
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="3"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; Predict the \(x\)-intercepts for function \(g(x)=2x(x-3)\).&amp;nbsp; &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;\(x\)-intercepts for function \(g\): \((0,0)\) and \((3,0)\)
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="4"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; Predict the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex for function \(g(x)=2x(x-3)\).&amp;nbsp; &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.5
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="5"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; Predict the \(x\)-intercepts for function \(h(x)=(x+4)(4-x)\).&amp;nbsp; &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;\(x\)-intercepts for function \(h\): \((-4,0)\) and \((4,0)\)
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;ol type="a" start="6"&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; Predict the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex for function \(h(x)=(x+4)(4-x)\).&amp;nbsp; &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;Answer: &lt;/strong&gt;0
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Use the graphing tool or technology outside the course. Graph the functions \(f\), \(g\), and \(h\):&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        \(f(x)=(x+3)(x-5)\)&lt;br&gt;
        \(g(x)=2x(x-3)\)&lt;br&gt;
        \(h(x)=(x+4)(4-x)\)
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the graphs to check your predictions. Then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/xCifYZykHku2E5hZfPAJN2iQ" alt="3 graphs f, g, h shown on the same coordinate plane." width="418" height="219"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Without using technology, sketch a graph that represents the equation \(y=(x-7)(x+11)\) and that shows the \(x\)-intercepts and the vertex. Think about how to find the \(y\)-coordinate of the vertex. Be prepared to explain your reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;solution &lt;/strong&gt;button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; The \(x\)-intercepts for \((x-7)(x+11)\) are at \(x=7\) and \(x=-11\). The vertex for \((x-7)(x+11)\) is halfway between the \(x\)-intercepts, at \(x=-2\). If the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex is -2, then the \(y\)-value is \((-2,-7)(-2+11)\) or -81. The vertex is at \((-2,81)\). The \(y\)-value when \(x=0\) is \((0-7)(0+11)\), which is -77. The \(y\)-intercept is \((0,-77)\).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/xhDeaHZzh2FhouPF6VeNd8nx" alt="Graph on coordinate plane." width="272" height="214"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Video: Sketching a Graph of a Quadratic Function&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the following video to learn more about sketching a graph of a quadratic function using at least three identifiable points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls="true" crossorigin="anonymous" width="550"&gt;
    &lt;source src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/e54db5db94f260e4358f839163d748806128a386"&gt;
    &lt;track src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/b648d292c43bdf07b745271de3314a418e2139be" kind="captions" srclang="en_us" label="On" default="true"&gt;https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/e54db5db94f260e4358f839163d748806128a386
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student-Facing Extension&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Are you ready for more?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quadratic function \(f\) is given by \(f(x)=x^2+2x+6\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Find \(f(-2)\).&lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 6
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Find \(f(0)\).&lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER&lt;/strong&gt;: 6
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What is the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex of the graph of this quadratic function?&lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER&lt;/strong&gt;: -1
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Does the graph have any \(x\)-intercepts? Explain or show how you know.&lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;No, the graph does not have any \(x\)-intercepts. The \(y\)-coordinate of the vertex is 5 because \(f(-1)=(-1)2+2(-1)+6=5\). The coefficient of the squared term is positive, so the vertex is a minimum, which means the output of the function is never less than 5.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus the discussion on how students determined the \(x\)-intercepts and the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex of a graph, and how the coordinates of these points could help them sketch the graph.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; "For \(g(x)=2x(x-3)\), how did you find the \(x\)-intercepts without graphing?" (The \((x-3)\) suggests that one \(x\)-intercept is \((3,0)\), and evaluating \(g(3)\) does give an output of 0. The factor \(2x\) suggests that the second \(x\)-intercept is \((0,0)\), because \(2(0)\) is 0, and multiplying 0 by any number gives 0.) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; "How did you find the \(x\)-value of the vertex?" (By finding the halfway point between 0 and 3, which is 1.5.) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; "How would you find the \(y\)-coordinate of the vertex?" (By evaluating \(g(1.5)\), which gives -4.5.) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; "The expression that defines function \(h\) has the factor \((4-x)\), where the constant term appears first and \(x\) is subtracted from it. Did this affect how you determined the \(x\)-intercepts? How so?" &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; "How did you sketch the graph representing \(y=(x-7)(x+11)\)?" (By finding the \(x\)-intercepts and the vertex. The intercepts are \((7,0)\) and \((-11,0)\), so the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex is -2, and the \(y\)-coordinate is \((-2-7)(-2+11)\) or -81. Those points are enough to sketch a graph.) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; (For the Student-Facing Extension) “When graphing &amp;nbsp;\(f(x)=x ^2+2x+6\), how does that fact that both \(f(-2)\) and \(f(0)=6\) help you find the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex?” (Because the graph of a quadratic function is symmetric, any two points that have the same \(y\) value are the same distance from the vertex. You can use this just like you used the halfway point between the zeroes of the function to determine the \(x\)-value of the vertex.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.11.3: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
    &lt;colgroup&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
        &lt;col&gt;
    &lt;/colgroup&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Find the coordinate of the vertex of \(f(x) = (x - 2)(x - 4)\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\((2, 0)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This is a zero. The answer is \((3, -1)\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\((3, -1)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;That’s correct! Check yourself: The vertex is located halfway between the zeros of \(x = 2\) and \(x = 4\). Substitute \(x = 3\) into the function and the result is \(y = -1\).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\((4, 0)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This is a zero. The answer is \((3, -1)\).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;\((0, 8)\)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let’s try again a different way: This is the \(y\)-intercept. The answer is \((3, -1)\).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.11.3: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Graphing Quadratics With Points&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function \(f\) given by \(f(x)=(x+1)(x-1)\) is written in factored form. Recall that this form is helpful for finding the zeros of the function (where the function has the value 0) and telling us the \(x\)-intercepts on the graph representing the function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a graph representing \(f\). It shows two \(x\)-intercepts at \(x=-1\) and \(x=3\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/xhDeaHZzh2FhouPF6VeNd8nx" alt=" Graph on coordinate plane." width="317" height="263"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we use –1 and 3 as outputs to \(f\), what are the outputs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;\(
        f(-1)=(-1+1)(-1-3)=(0)(-4)=0\) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; \(f(3)=(3+1)(3-3)=(4)(0)=0\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the inputs –1 and 3 produce an output of 0, they are the zeros of the function \(f\). And because both \(x\) values have 0 for their \(y\) value, they also give us the \(x\)-intercepts of the graph (the points where the graph crosses the \(x\)-axis, which always have a \(y\)-coordinate of 0). So, the zeros of a function have the same values as the \(x\)-coordinates of the \(x\)-intercepts of the graph of the function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The factored form can also help us identify the vertex of the graph, which is the point where the function reaches its minimum value. Notice that the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex is 1, and that 1 is halfway between –1 and 3. Once we know the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex, we can find the \(y\)-coordinate by evaluating the function \(f(1)=(1+1)(1-3)=(2)(-2)=-4\). So the vertex is at \((1, –4)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a quadratic function is in standard form, the \(y\)-intercept is clear: its \(y\)-coordinate is the constant term \(c\) in \(ax^2+bx+c\). To find the \(y\)-intercept from factored form, we can evaluate the function at \(x=0\), because the \(y\)-intercept is the point where the graph has an input value of 0:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(f(0)=(0+1)(0-3)=(1)(-3)=-3\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Graphing Quadratics with Points&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the zeros and vertex of the function \(f\) given by \(f(x)=(x-4)(x+2)\). Use the points to graph \(f\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to find the function’s zeros and vertex:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 1&lt;br&gt;
    Set each factor equal to 0 and solve. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;\(
        x - 4 = 0, x = 4\) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; \(x + 2 = 0,&amp;nbsp; x = -2\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 2&lt;br&gt;
    Write the zeros as points. &lt;br&gt;
    \((4, 0) (-2, 0)\) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 3&lt;br&gt;
    Find the \(x\)-value halfway between the zeros. &lt;br&gt;
    \(x=1\) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 4&lt;br&gt;
    Substitute \(x = -1\) into the function to find the vertex. &lt;br&gt;
    \(f(1) = (1 - 4)(1 + 2) = (-3)(3) = -9\) &lt;br&gt;
    Vertex: \((1,-9)\) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 5&lt;br&gt;
    Now, use these points to graph \(f\): &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/c191713d5b7dbc9d098119cda6d531aa53db5096" width="250" height="252"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3887">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665075260</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3888">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665075260</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1732">
        <prevpageid>1731</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1733</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665080713</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665732305</timemodified>
        <title>7.11.4: Graphs of Quadratic Functions</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Cool Down (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function \(f\) is given by \(f(x)=(x-2)(x+4)\).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without using graphing technology, answer questions 1–4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the \(x\)-intercepts of the graph representing \(f\)?&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;\(x\)-intercepts for function \(f\): \((2,0)\) and \((-4,0)\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex of the graph?&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer&lt;/strong&gt;: -1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the \(y\)-coordinate of the vertex of the graph?&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer&lt;/strong&gt;: -9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the \(y\)-intercept?&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;The \(y\)-intercept is \((0,-8)\), because \((0-2)(0+4)=(-2)(4)=-8\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="5"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use the graphing tool or technology outside the course. Sketch a graph that represents \(f\).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;The graph opens upward with vertex at \((-1,-9)\) and \(x\)-intercepts at \((2,0)\) and \((-4, 0)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/rAg85AthXtmofqTzV6srvwmT" alt="Graph on coordinate plane." width="262" height="267"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Response to Student Thinking&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Points to Emphasize&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If students struggle to identify the \(x\)- and \(y\)-intercepts, use the Card Sort in Lesson 7.12 to highlight key ideas based on student work in the cool down.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3889">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665080713</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3890">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665080713</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1733">
        <prevpageid>1732</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1734</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665082315</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665754030</timemodified>
        <title>7.11.5: Practice </title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Students will complete the following questions to practice the skills they have learned in this lesson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select two &lt;/strong&gt;true statements about the graph that represents \(y=2x(x-11)\).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Its \(x\)-intercepts are at \((-2,0)\) and \((11,0)\). &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Its \(x\)-intercepts are at \((0,0)\) and \((11,0)\). &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Its \(x\)-intercepts are at \((2,0)\) and \((-11,0)\). &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; It has only one \(x\)-intercept. &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; The \(x\)-coordinate of its vertex is -4.5. &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; The \(x\)-coordinate of its vertex is 11. &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; The \(x\)-coordinate of its vertex is 4.5. &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; The \(x\)-coordinate of its vertex is 5.5. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER&lt;/strong&gt;: Its \(x\)-intercepts are at \((0,0)\) and \((11,0)\). The \(x\)-coordinate of its vertex is 5.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select two &lt;/strong&gt;equations whose graphs have a vertex with \(x\)-coordinate 2.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; \(y=(x-2)(x-4)\) &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; \(y=(x-2)(x+2)\) &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; \(y=(x-1)(x-3)\) &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; \(y=x(x+4)\) &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;\( y=x(x-4)\) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \(y=(x-1)(x-3)\), \(y=x(x-4)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three different equations are given. Refer to these equations to complete questions a–f.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
  &lt;colgroup&gt;
  &lt;col width="183"&gt;
  &lt;col width="110"&gt;
  &lt;col width="194"&gt;
  &lt;/colgroup&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(x\)-intercepts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;\(x\)-coordinate of the vertex&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;\(y=x(x-2)\)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;a. _____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;b. _____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;\(y=(x-4)(x+5)\)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;c. _____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;d. _____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;\(y=-5x(3-x)\)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;e. _____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;f. _____&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; What are the \(x\)-intercepts of the graph that represents \(y=x(x-2)\)?
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;\((0,0)\) and \((0, 2)\) &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; \((0,0)\) and \((2, 0)\) &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;\((0,0)\) and \((0,-2)\) &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; \((0,0)\) and \((-2,0)\) &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \((0,0)\) and \((2,0)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;ol type="a" start="2"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; What is the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex of the graph that represents \(y=x(x-2)\)?&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; What are the \(x\)-intercepts of the graph that represents \(y=(x-4)(x+5)\)?
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;\((-5,0)\) and \((4,0)\) &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; \((0,-5)\) and \((0,4)\) &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; \((5,0)\) and \((-4,0)\) &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; \((0,5)\) and \((0,-4)\) &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \((-5,0)\) and \((4,0)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;ol start="4" type="a"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; What is the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex of the graph that represents \(y=(x-4)(x+5)\)? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; -0.5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;ol start="5" type="a"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; What are the \(x\)-intercepts of the graph that represents \(y=-5x(3-x)\)?
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;\((0,0)\) and \((0,-3)\) &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;\((0,0)\) and \((-3,0)\) &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;\((0,0)\) and \((3,0)\) &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; \((0,0)\) and \((0,3)\) &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \((0,0)\) and \((3,0)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;ol start="6" type="a"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; What is the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex of the graph that represents \(y=-5x(3-x)\)? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Answer questions a–c about the function \(y=(x-2)(x-4)\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;ol type="a"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; What are the \(x\)-intercepts of the graph of \(y=(x-2)(x-4)\)?
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; \((2,0)\) and \((4,0)\) &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; \((0,2)\) and \((0,4)\) &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; \((-2,0)\) and \((-4,0)\) &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; \((0,-2)\) and \((0,-4)\) &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \((2,0)\) and \((4,0)\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;ol type="a" start="2"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Is \((-1,3)\) a point on the graph?
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; Yes &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt; No &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;No. Substituting -1 for \(x\) gives \((-1-2)(-1-4)\) or \(-3 \cdot -5\), which is 15, so \((-1,15)\) would be a point on the graph, not \((-1,3)\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Does the graph represent the equation \(y=(x-2)(x-4)\)? &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/MTCLCZUmf8dnPMDbbFacxLcJ" alt="Graph of nonlinear function, origin O. Horizontal axis from negative 8 to 6, by 2’s. Vertical axis from negative 8 to 12, by 4’s. Line passes through negative 7 comma 8, negative 5 comma 0, negative 3 comma 0 and 1 comma 7." width="262" height="171"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Yes &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; No &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3891">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665082315</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3892">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665082315</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1734">
        <prevpageid>1733</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1665085068</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665085193</timemodified>
        <title>7.11.6: Lesson Synthesis</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;To help students consolidate the ideas in this lesson, consider asking them to reflect on some or all of the following questions in writing or by discussing with a partner:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quadratic function \(k\) is defined by \(k(x)=(x-100)(x+20)\). How would you explain to a friend who is absent today how to use the equation to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Find the zeros of the function? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Find the \(x\)-intercepts of the graph? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Find the \(x\)-coordinate of the vertex without graphing? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Find the \(y\)-coordinate of the vertex without graphing? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Find the \(y\)-intercept of the graph? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3893">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665085068</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3894">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1665085068</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>