<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<activity id="176" moduleid="235" modulename="lesson" contextid="246">
  <lesson id="176">
    <course>2</course>
    <name>Lesson 7.5 Teacher Guide: Building Quadratic Functions to Describe Situations, Part 1</name>
    <intro/>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <practice>1</practice>
    <modattempts>0</modattempts>
    <usepassword>0</usepassword>
    <password/>
    <dependency>0</dependency>
    <conditions>O:8:"stdClass":3:{s:9:"timespent";i:0;s:9:"completed";i:0;s:15:"gradebetterthan";i:0;}</conditions>
    <grade>0</grade>
    <custom>1</custom>
    <ongoing>0</ongoing>
    <usemaxgrade>0</usemaxgrade>
    <maxanswers>5</maxanswers>
    <maxattempts>0</maxattempts>
    <review>0</review>
    <nextpagedefault>0</nextpagedefault>
    <feedback>0</feedback>
    <minquestions>0</minquestions>
    <maxpages>1</maxpages>
    <timelimit>0</timelimit>
    <retake>1</retake>
    <activitylink>236</activitylink>
    <mediafile/>
    <mediaheight>480</mediaheight>
    <mediawidth>640</mediawidth>
    <mediaclose>0</mediaclose>
    <slideshow>0</slideshow>
    <width>640</width>
    <height>480</height>
    <bgcolor>#FFFFFF</bgcolor>
    <displayleft>1</displayleft>
    <displayleftif>0</displayleftif>
    <progressbar>0</progressbar>
    <available>0</available>
    <deadline>0</deadline>
    <timemodified>1665638204</timemodified>
    <completionendreached>0</completionendreached>
    <completiontimespent>0</completiontimespent>
    <allowofflineattempts>0</allowofflineattempts>
    <pages>
      <page id="1620">
        <prevpageid>0</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1621</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1664721993</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665324226</timemodified>
        <title>7.5.0: Lesson Overview</title>
        <contents>&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Narrative&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first of several lessons in which students construct quadratic functions to represent various situations. Here they investigate the movement of free-falling objects. Students analyze the vertical distances that falling objects travel over time and see that they can be described by quadratic functions. They use tables, graphs, and equations to represent and make sense of the functions. In subsequent lessons, students build on the functions developed here to represent projectile motions, providing a context to develop understanding of the zeros, vertex, and domain of quadratic functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To express the relationship between distance and time, students need to see regularity in numerical values and express that regularity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Goals (Teacher Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Explain (orally and in writing) the meaning of each term in a quadratic expression that represents the height of a free-falling object. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Use tables, graphs, and equations to represent the height of a free-falling object. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Write quadratic functions to represent the height of an object falling due to gravity. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning Targets (Student Facing)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Explain the meaning of the terms in a quadratic expression that represents the height of a falling object. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Use tables, graphs, and equations to represent the height of a falling object. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills (TEKS)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TEKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation of Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;A7(A) graph quadratic functions on the coordinate plane and use the graph to identify key attributes, if possible, including \(x\)-intercept, \(y\)-intercept, zeros, maximum value, minimum values, vertex, and the equation of the axis of symmetry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foundational: Lesson provides foundational content necessary for students to be able to perform this TEKS in later lessons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Activities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the instructional activities for the lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.5.1: Numerical Patterns &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.5.2: A Time-Distance Quadratic Model &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.5.2: Self Check &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.5.2: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.5.3: Distance as a Quadratic Function of Elapsed Time &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.5.3: Self Check &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.5.3: Additional Resources &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 7.5.4: A Quadratic Expression that Represents the Relationship Between Distance and Time &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will also complete a series of problems in the 7.5.5: Practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Materials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Required Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be prepared to display a GeoGebra applet for all to see during the synthesis of the activity &amp;ldquo;Distance as a Quadratic Function of Elapsed Time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lesson Vocabulary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this lesson, it is important to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Familiarize students with the vocabulary words they will see throughout the lesson. Encourage students to look for these words and notice their use and meanings. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Encourage students to use key vocabulary words in &amp;ldquo;math talk&amp;rdquo; and their written and oral explanations. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Utilize a word wall. Sample cards are located here: &lt;a href="https://www.doe.virginia.gov/instruction/mathematics/resources/vocab_cards/" target="_blank"&gt;Mathematics Vocabulary Word Wall Cards&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocabulary words that are emphasized in this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; constant &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; equation &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; expression &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; negative numbers &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; opposite &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; quadratic expression &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; quadratic function &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; term &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; variable &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; none &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Support for Building Character&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this unit, find ways to encourage and support students to work on cultivating their &lt;strong&gt;proactivity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to try during this lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/the-peak-end-rule/" target="_blank"&gt;The Peak-End Rule&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/tips-of-the-week/great-expectations/" target="_blank"&gt;Great Expectations&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find other tips located here in the &lt;a href="https://characterlab.org/playbooks/proactivity/" target="_blank"&gt;Playbook on Proactivity&lt;/a&gt; from Character Lab.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3642">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664721993</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1621">
        <prevpageid>1620</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1622</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1664722482</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665324706</timemodified>
        <title>7.5.1: Numerical Patterns</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Warm Up (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this warm up is to elicit the idea that the values in the table have a predictable pattern, which will be useful when students consider the context of a falling object in a later activity. While students may notice and wonder many things about this table, the patterns are the important discussion points, rather than an attempt to find a rule for the function. Because the rule is not easy to uncover, studying the numbers ahead of time should prove helpful as students analyze the function later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This prompt gives students opportunities to see and make use of structure. The specific structure they might notice is all the \(y\)-values are multiples of 16 and perfect squares. Some may notice the pattern is not linear and wonder whether it is quadratic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have students write down their thoughts about what they notice and wonder in the table. Then, have them turn and talk with a partner. Ask pairs to share their thoughts with the class and add to a growing list. If some of the sample answers are not present, then ask questions to facilitate their addition to the class list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Study the table. What do you notice? What do you wonder?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="43"&gt;
&lt;col width="46"&gt;
&lt;col width="46"&gt;
&lt;col width="46"&gt;
&lt;col width="46"&gt;
&lt;col width="46"&gt;
&lt;col width="46"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;\(x\)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;\(y\)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;16&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;64&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;144&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;256&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;400&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things you may notice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The \(x\)-values increment by 1 as you move across the table. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The \(y\)-values increase. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; All \(y\)-values are even and divisible by 4, 8, and 16. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The \(y\)-values are all perfect squares. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The successive differences between the \(y\)-values are growing. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things you may wonder:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Is there a rule for these numbers? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Do the numbers represent the growth of a geometric pattern? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Do the numbers represent a quadratic relationship? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What is the next number in the table? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite students to share their observations and questions. Record and display them for all to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all responses are recorded, tell students that they will investigate these values more closely in upcoming activities.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3643">
            <jumpto>1620</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664722482</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3644">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664722482</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1622">
        <prevpageid>1621</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1623</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1664722723</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665718149</timemodified>
        <title>7.5.2: A Time-Distance Quadratic Model </title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The motion of a falling object is commonly modeled with a quadratic function. This activity prompts students to build a very simple quadratic model using given time-distance data of a free-falling rock. By reasoning repeatedly about the values in the data, students notice regularity in the relationship between time and the vertical distance the object travels, which they then generalize as an expression with a squared variable. The work here prepares students to make sense of more complex quadratic functions later (that is, to model the motion of an object that is launched up and then returns to the ground).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Display the image of the falling object for all to see. Students will recognize the numbers from the warm up. Invite students to make some other observations about the information. Ask questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;What do you think the numbers tell us?&amp;rdquo; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;Does the object fall the same distance every successive second? How do you know?&amp;rdquo; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of two. Tell students to think quietly about the first question and share their thinking with a partner. Afterward, consider pausing for a brief discussion before proceeding to the second question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rock is dropped from the top floor of a 500-foot-tall building. A camera captures the distance the rock traveled, in feet, after each second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="An image of a rock dropped from the top floor of a 500-foot tall building." height="474" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/vnduDW7SMLYFnbGS2Wypq48k" width="377"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many feet will the rock have fallen after 6 seconds? Be prepared to explain your reasoning.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;The rock will have fallen 500 feet after 6 seconds. The distance fallen increased with each additional second. The rock fell 144 feet between 4 and 5 seconds, so between 5 and 6 seconds, it would fall more than 144 feet. After 5 seconds of falling, there is less than 144 feet to go before the rock hits the ground.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jada noticed that the distances fallen are all multiples of 16.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
    She wrote down:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
    \(16=16 \cdot 1\)&lt;br&gt;
    \(64=16 \cdot 4\)&lt;br&gt;
    \(144=16 \cdot 9\)&lt;br&gt;
    \(256=16 \cdot 16\)&lt;br&gt;
    \(400=16 \cdot 25\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, she noticed that 1, 4, 9, 16, and 25 are \(1^2\), \(2^2\), \(3^2\), \(4^2\), \(5^2\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Use Jada&amp;rsquo;s observations to predict the distance fallen in feet after 7 seconds. (Assume the building is tall enough that an object dropped from the top of it will continue falling for at least 7 seconds.) Be prepared to explain your reasoning. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; 784&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Write an equation for the function, with \(d\) representing the distance dropped after \(t\) seconds. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(d=16 \cdot t^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Anticipated Misconceptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some students may question why the distances are positive when the rock is falling. In earlier grades, negative numbers represented on a vertical number line may have been associated with an arrow pointing down. Emphasize that the values shown in the picture measure how far the rock fell and not the direction it is falling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss the equation students wrote for the last question. If not already mentioned by students, point out that the \(t^2\) suggests a quadratic relationship between elapsed time and the distance that a falling object travels. Ask students:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;How do you know that the equation \(d=16t^2\) represents a function?&amp;rdquo; (For every input of time, there is a particular output.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;Suppose we want to know if the rock will travel 600 feet before 6 seconds have elapsed. How can we find out?&amp;rdquo; (Find the value of \(d\) when \(t\) is 6, which is \(16 \cdot 6^2\) or 576 feet.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain to students that we only have a few data points to go by in this case, and the quadratic expression \(16t^2\) is a simplified model, but quadratic functions are generally used to model the movement of falling objects. We will see this expression appearing in some other contexts where gravity affects the quantities being studied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;7.5.2: Self Check&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="302"&gt;
&lt;col width="322"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An object is dropped from a building and falls so that the distance in feet it falls, \(d(t)\), is found by \(d(t)=16t^2\), after \(t\) seconds. How many feet has it fallen after 10 seconds?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;160&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: Make sure to square the time. The answer is 1,600.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;320&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: Be sure to square the 10, not multiply by 2. The answer is 1,600.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;1,600&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: When \(t=10\), square the 10 to get 100, then multiply by 16.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;2,560&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: Use order of operations and square 10 first. Then multiply by 16. The answer is 1,600.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.5.2: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Finding Distance Fallen&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Empire State Building is 1250 ft high (excluding the lightning rod). A visitor drops a penny from the top, and it falls straight down. How far has it fallen after 5 seconds?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall the previous activity&amp;rsquo;s formula \(h(t)=16t^2\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substitute \(t=5\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(5)=16(5)^2=16 \cdot 25=400\) feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Finding Distance Fallen&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will the penny dropped from the Empire State Building reach the ground after 9 seconds? Explain your reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Solution &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to determine if the penny will hit the ground by 9 seconds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substitute \(t=9\) into \(h(t)=16t^2\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(9)=16(9)^2=16 \cdot 81=1296\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 9 seconds, the penny could travel 1296 feet. The Empire State Building is 1250 feet tall, so the penny will have hit the ground by 9 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3645">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664722723</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3646">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664722723</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1623">
        <prevpageid>1622</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1624</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1664725125</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665718688</timemodified>
        <title>7.5.3: Distance as a Quadratic Function of Elapsed Time</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Activity (15 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this activity, students continue to explore how quadratic functions can model the movement of a falling object. They evaluate the function seen earlier \((d=16t^2)\) at a non-integer input, and then build a new function to represent the distance from the ground of a falling object \(t\) seconds after it is dropped. To find a new expression that describes the height of the object, students reason repeatedly about the height of the object at different times and look for regularity in their reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number 576 is chosen as the height (in feet) from which the object is dropped to make it more apparent for students that the values in the two tables (distance fallen and distance from ground) record distances measured from opposite ends. (Any value of at a whole-number \(t\)&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;could work. In this case, \(t=6\) is selected.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrange students in groups of two, and suggest that they check in with each other after trying each question. To facilitate peer discussion, consider displaying sentence stems or questions that students could use, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;Why do you think the object will have fallen that distance in 0.5 seconds?&amp;rdquo; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;How do you think the values in the first table are changing? What about in the second table?&amp;rdquo; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;How are the two tables alike? How are they different?&amp;rdquo; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galileo Galilei, an Italian scientist, and other medieval scholars studied the motion of free-falling objects. The law they discovered can be expressed by the equation \(d=16t^2\), which gives the distance fallen in feet as a function of time, \(t\), in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An object is dropped from a height of 576 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many feet does it fall in 0.5 seconds?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;4
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To find out where the object is the first few seconds after it was dropped, Elena and Diego created different tables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elena&amp;rsquo;s table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5" width="231"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="85"&gt;
&lt;col width="77"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center" width="99"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time (seconds)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center" width="100"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distance fallen (feet)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;64&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(t\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diego&amp;rsquo;s table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="85"&gt;
&lt;col width="121"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center" width="118"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time (seconds)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center" width="119"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distance from the ground (feet)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;576&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;560&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;512&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;t&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How are the two tables alike?&amp;nbsp; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; They both have time in seconds and distance in feet as the two quantities being measured. They both show 0&amp;ndash;4 seconds and \(t\) seconds for time. They describe the same object falling.&amp;nbsp;
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How are the two tables different? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Elena&amp;rsquo;s table measures distance fallen, and Diego&amp;rsquo;s table measures distance from the ground. They record measurements from opposite ends. Elena&amp;rsquo;s table starts with 0 feet for 0 seconds, and Diego&amp;rsquo;s starts with 576 feet for 0 seconds.
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete Elena&amp;rsquo;s table. Be prepared to explain your reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What is the distance the object has fallen 3 seconds after it was dropped? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;144
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What is the distance the object has fallen 4 seconds after it was dropped? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;256
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What is the distance the object has fallen \(t\) seconds after it was dropped? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; \(16t^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete Diego&amp;rsquo;s table. Be prepared to explain your reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What is the object&amp;rsquo;s distance from the ground 3 seconds after it was dropped? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;432
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What is the object&amp;rsquo;s distance from the ground 4 seconds after it was dropped? &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;320
        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; What is the object&amp;rsquo;s distance from the ground \(t\) seconds after it was dropped? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;\(576-16t^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Video: Distance as a Quadratic Function of Elapsed Time&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the following video to learn more about quadratic functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls="true" crossorigin="anonymous" width="550"&gt;
&lt;source src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/005a0fd918a3812ba158602b14d462d900fd0661"&gt;
&lt;track default="true" kind="captions" label="On" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/99b550bc7dd378abebde6439ebf81a0f0c4fedd3" srclang="en_us"&gt;https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/005a0fd918a3812ba158602b14d462d900fd0661
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity Synthesis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help students make sense of the two functions, compare and contrast their representations (tables, equations, and graphs) and discuss the connections between them. Ask questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;How did you complete the missing values in the first table?&amp;rdquo; (Substituting 3 and 4 for \(t\) in \(16t^2\) gives the distances fallen after 3 and 4 seconds.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;What about those in the second table?&amp;rdquo; (The distance from the ground is 576 minus the distance fallen, so we can use the values for \(t=3\) and \(t=4\) from the first table to calculate the values in the second table.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;Why do the values in the first table increase and those in the second table decrease?&amp;rdquo; (The distance from the top of the building increases as the object falls farther and farther from it. The distance from the ground decreases as the object falls closer and closer to it.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;The expression representing the distance fallen shows \(16t^2\), and the other shows \(576-16t^2\). Why is that?&amp;rdquo; (In the first function, the distance fallen, measured from where the object is dropped, will always be positive. In the second function, what&amp;rsquo;s measured is the height from the ground, so the distance fallen needs to be subtracted from the height of the building.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;If we graph the two equations that represent distance fallen and distance from the ground over time, what would the graphs look like? Try sketching the graphs.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Display graphs that represent the two functions and make sure students can interpret them. For example, they should see that the \(y\)-intercept of each graph corresponds to the starting value of each function before the object is dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They should also notice that the difference in distance between successive seconds gets larger in both cases, hence the curving graphs. (If the differences were constant, the graphs would have been straight lines.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graph with x-axis labeled time in seconds and y-axis labeled distance fallen in feet." height="305" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/kozDeStkaJNuRFGvYAayn4t5" width="315"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graph with x-axis labeled with time in seconds and y-axis with distance above the ground in feet." height="305" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/kG3DxyVr425nn4JQnKD5X1Dv" width="313"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Display the embedded applet for all to see. Ask students how the graph of the height of the object is related to the path that the object takes as it falls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.5.3: Self Check&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the activity, students will answer the following question to check their understanding of the concepts explored in the activity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;col&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td colspan="2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUESTION:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A small ball is dropped from a 350-foot-tall building. Which equation could represent the ball&amp;rsquo;s height, \(h(t)\), in feet, relative to the ground, as a function of time, \(t\), in seconds?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWERS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(t)=350-16t\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: The \(t\) is squared in the formula. The answer is \(h(t)=350-16t^2\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(t)=350-16t^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s correct! Check yourself: The ball will fall from 350 feet, so subtract 16 times the time squared to find the height at a given time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(t)=350+16t^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: Be sure to subtract, not add. The answer is \(h(t)=350-16t^2\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(t)=\frac{350}{16t^2}\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect. Let&amp;rsquo;s try again a different way: Subtract the \(16t^2\) to find the height. The answer is \(h(t)=350-16t^2\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7.5.3: Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following content is available to students who would like more support based on their experience with the self check. Students will not automatically have access to this content, so you may wish to share it with those who could benefit from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Height as a Quadratic Function&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general formula for a free falling object is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h(t)=-16t^2+v_0t+h_0\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the meaning of the coefficients in the formula:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the formula, \(-16\) is the constant that has been determined by a combination of Newton&amp;rsquo;s Laws and Earth&amp;rsquo;s weight and is used with the units feet/second\(^2\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(v_0\) is the vertical speed of the object. If the object is simply dropped, the vertical speed is 0. If the object were thrown upward, this value would be positive, and if the object were thrown down, this value would be negative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;\(h_0\) is the initial height of the object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A man drops his keys from a restaurant at the top of a 196-foot-tall building. If the keys are free falling, will they reach the ground within 3 seconds?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 1&lt;br&gt;
    Write an equation for the height at a given time, \(t\).&lt;br&gt;
    \(h(t)=196-16t^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 2&lt;br&gt;
    Substitute \(t=3\) into the function.&lt;br&gt;
    \(h(3)=196-16(3)^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 3&lt;br&gt;
    Solve.&lt;br&gt;
    \(h(3)=196-144=52\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At \(t=3\) seconds, the keys will still have 52 feet to travel to hit the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Try It: Height as a Quadratic Function&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will the keys in the situation above reach the ground after 5 seconds?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt; Solution&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to determine if the keys reach the ground in 5 seconds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 1&lt;br&gt;
    Write an equation for the height at a given time, \(t\).&lt;br&gt;
    \(h(t)=196-16t^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 2&lt;br&gt;
    Substitute \(t=5\) into the function.&lt;br&gt;
    \(h(5)=196-16(5)^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 3&lt;br&gt;
    Solve.&lt;br&gt;
    \(h(5)=196-400=-204\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keys reach the ground before \(t=5\) seconds since substituting in 5 creates a negative height, which implies they have fallen below ground level and does not make sense for this scenario.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3647">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664725125</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3648">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664725125</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1624">
        <prevpageid>1623</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1625</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1664729948</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665719199</timemodified>
        <title>7.5.4: A Quadratic Expression that Represents the Relationship Between Distance and Time</title>
        <contents>&lt;h3&gt;Cool Down (5 minutes)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Student Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expression \(16t^2\) represents the distance in feet an object falls after \(t\) seconds. Assume an object is dropped from a height of 906 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the height of the object in feet 2 seconds after it is dropped?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;The object is at 842 feet 2 seconds after it&amp;rsquo;s dropped. \(906-16(2)^2=906-16(4)=906-64=842\)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write an expression representing the height of the object in feet \(t\) seconds after it is dropped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down your answer, then select the &lt;strong&gt;solution&lt;/strong&gt; button to compare your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;\(906-16t^2\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Response to Student Thinking&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;More Chances&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will have more opportunities to understand the mathematical ideas in this cool down, so there is no need to slow down or add additional work to the next lessons. Instead, use the results of this cool down to provide guidance for what to look for and emphasize over the next several lessons to support students in advancing their current understanding.&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3649">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664729948</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3650">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664729948</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1625">
        <prevpageid>1624</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>1626</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1664730334</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665460971</timemodified>
        <title>7.5.5: Practice</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Students will complete the following questions to practice the skills they have learned in this lesson.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A rocket is launched in the air and its height, in feet, is modeled by the function \(h\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a graph representing \(h\).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A curve on a graph, origin O, with grid. Horizontal axis, time, seconds, scale 0 to 8, by 1&amp;rsquo;s. Vertical axis, height, feet, scale 0 to 200, by 20&amp;rsquo;s. A curve passes through the points 0 comma 5, 3 comma 161, and 5 comma 105." src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/im-ims-export/Tiasy6YvNNYHj9s1YbFFABNS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select three&lt;/strong&gt; true statements about the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; The rocket is launched from a height less than 20 feet above the ground. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; The rocket is launched from about 20 feet above the ground. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; The rocket reaches its maximum height after about 3 seconds. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; The rocket reaches its maximum height after about 160 seconds. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; The maximum height of the rocket is about 160 feet.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; The rocket is launched from a height less than 20 feet above the ground. The rocket reaches its maximum height after about 3 seconds. The maximum height of the rocket is about 160 feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A baseball travels \(d\) meters \(t\) seconds after being dropped from the top of a building. The distance traveled by the baseball can be modeled by the equation \(d=5t^2\).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use this table to answer questions a&amp;ndash;g.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellpadding="5"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="85"&gt;
&lt;col width="81"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;\(t\) &lt;strong&gt;(seconds)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;\(d\) &lt;strong&gt;(meters)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;0&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;0.5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How many meters (\(d\)) did the baseball travel in 0 seconds (\(t\))? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="2" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How many meters (\(d\)) did the baseball travel in 0.5 seconds (\(t\))? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="3" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How many meters (\(d\)) did the baseball travel in 1 second (\(t\))? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="4" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How many meters (\(d\)) did the baseball travel in 1.5 seconds (\(t\))? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 11.25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="5" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; How many meters (\(d\)) did the baseball travel in 2 seconds (\(t\))? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; 20 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="6" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Is this graph an accurate representation of the data in the table?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img height="147" src="https://k12.openstax.org/contents/raise/resources/76e9e08d68737f77cd4e09f02636aec9922513b8" width="305"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;Yes. The coordinates plotted on the graph match the data in the table: \((0,0)\), \((0.5,1.25)\), \((1,5)\), \((1.5,11.25)\), \((2,20)\). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;ol start="7" type="a"&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Is the baseball traveling at a constant speed?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER: &lt;/strong&gt;No. The distance traveled is not changing at a constant speed; it is increasing over time. For example, in the first half second, it travels 1.25 meters, and in the next half second, it travels 3.75 meters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small ball is dropped from a 100-foot-tall building. Which equation could represent the ball&amp;rsquo;s height, \(h(t)\), in feet, relative to the ground, as a function of time, \(t\), in seconds?
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;\(h(t)=100-16t\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(h(t)=100-16t^2\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(h(t)=100+16t^2\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; \(h(t)=100-16t\) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSWER:&lt;/strong&gt; \(h(t)=100-16t^2\)&lt;/p&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3651">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664730334</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3652">
            <jumpto>-1</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664730334</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Next</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
      <page id="1626">
        <prevpageid>1625</prevpageid>
        <nextpageid>0</nextpageid>
        <qtype>20</qtype>
        <qoption>0</qoption>
        <layout>1</layout>
        <display>1</display>
        <timecreated>1664731419</timecreated>
        <timemodified>1665424123</timemodified>
        <title>7.5.6: Lesson Synthesis</title>
        <contents>&lt;p&gt;To highlight the key ideas from this lesson and the connections to earlier lessons, discuss questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;We used two different functions to describe the movement of a falling object. One function measured the distance the object traveled from its starting point, and the other measured its distance from the ground. How are the representations of these functions alike and different?&amp;rdquo; (The equations both have \(16t^2\), but one is positive and the other negative. Their graphs are both curves, but one graph curves upward and the other downward. The values in one table show increasing values, and the others show decreasing values, but they change by the same amounts from row to row.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;How are these functions like or unlike those representing visual patterns in earlier lessons?&amp;rdquo; (They can all be represented by quadratic expressions. The relationships between the step number and the number of squares or dots were easier to see. The relationships between time and distance are not as obvious.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &amp;ldquo;How are the graphs representing falling objects like or unlike those representing visual patterns?&amp;rdquo; (The graphs representing the patterns curved upward. They showed plotted points at whole-number inputs because non-whole-number steps would not make sense. In this lesson, we saw graphs that curved upward and downward. The graphs can be continuous because we can measure the distances even when the number of seconds is fractional.) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</contents>
        <contentsformat>1</contentsformat>
        <answers>
          <answer id="3653">
            <jumpto>-40</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664731419</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>Previous</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
          <answer id="3654">
            <jumpto>-9</jumpto>
            <grade>0</grade>
            <score>0</score>
            <flags>0</flags>
            <timecreated>1664731419</timecreated>
            <timemodified>0</timemodified>
            <answer_text>End of Lesson</answer_text>
            <response>$@NULL@$</response>
            <answerformat>0</answerformat>
            <responseformat>0</responseformat>
            <attempts>
            </attempts>
          </answer>
        </answers>
        <branches>
        </branches>
      </page>
    </pages>
    <grades>
    </grades>
    <timers>
    </timers>
    <overrides>
    </overrides>
  </lesson>
</activity>
